{"sentence_LOW": ["Building", "upon", "the", "Association", "of", "South-East", "Asian", "Nations", "(", "ASEAN", ")", "Plus", "Three", ",", "I", "have", "advocated", "the", "idea", "of", "an", "East", "Asia", "community", "."], "sentence_words": [{"token": "Building", "sentence_position": 0, "sentence_start": true, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "upon", "sentence_position": 1, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "the", "sentence_position": 2, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Association", "sentence_position": 3, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "of", "sentence_position": 4, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "South-East", "sentence_position": 5, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Asian", "sentence_position": 6, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Nations", "sentence_position": 7, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "(", "sentence_position": 8, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "ASEAN", "sentence_position": 9, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": ")", "sentence_position": 10, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Plus", "sentence_position": 11, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-MISC"}, {"token": "Three", "sentence_position": 12, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-MISC"}, {"token": ",", "sentence_position": 13, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "I", "sentence_position": 14, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "have", "sentence_position": 15, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "advocated", "sentence_position": 16, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "the", "sentence_position": 17, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "idea", "sentence_position": 18, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "of", "sentence_position": 19, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "an", "sentence_position": 20, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "East", "sentence_position": 21, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-LOC"}, {"token": "Asia", "sentence_position": 22, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-LOC"}, {"token": "community", "sentence_position": 23, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": ".", "sentence_position": 24, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": true, "NEtag": "O"}], "sentence_chunktags": [["NN-TL", "I-NP"], ["IN", "O"], ["AT", "B-NP"], ["NN-TL", "I-NP"], ["IN-TL", "O"], ["JJ-TL", "I-NP"], ["JJ-TL", "I-NP"], ["NNS-TL", "I-NP"], ["(", "O"], ["``", "I-NP"], [")", "O"], ["RB-TL", null], ["CD", "O"], [",", "O"], ["PPSS", "B-NP"], ["HV", "O"], ["VBD", "O"], ["AT", "B-NP"], ["NN", "I-NP"], ["IN", "O"], ["AT", "B-NP"], ["JJ-TL", "I-NP"], ["NP-TL", "I-NP"], ["NN", "I-NP"], [".", "O"]], "sentence_POS": [["Building", "NN-TL"], ["upon", "IN"], ["the", "AT"], ["Association", "NN-TL"], ["of", "IN-TL"], ["South-East", "JJ-TL"], ["Asian", "JJ-TL"], ["Nations", "NNS-TL"], ["(", "("], ["ASEAN", "``"], [")", ")"], ["Plus", "RB-TL"], ["Three", "CD"], [",", ","], ["I", "PPSS"], ["have", "HV"], ["advocated", "VBD"], ["the", "AT"], ["idea", "NN"], ["of", "IN"], ["an", "AT"], ["East", "JJ-TL"], ["Asia", "NP-TL"], ["community", "NN"], [".", "."]]}