{"sentence_LOW": ["Bulgaria", "greatly", "values", "the", "role", "of", "the", "United", "Nations", "in", "Iraq", "and", "appreciates", "the", "contribution", "of", "Mr.", "Nickolay", "Mladenov", ",", "former", "Bulgarian", "Foreign", "Minister", ",", "Special", "Representative", "of", "the", "Secretary-General", "and", "Head", "of", "the", "United", "Nations", "Assistance", "Mission", "for", "Iraq", "."], "sentence_words": [{"token": "Bulgaria", "sentence_position": 0, "sentence_start": true, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-LOC"}, {"token": "greatly", "sentence_position": 1, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "values", "sentence_position": 2, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "the", "sentence_position": 3, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "role", "sentence_position": 4, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "of", "sentence_position": 5, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "the", "sentence_position": 6, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "United", "sentence_position": 7, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Nations", "sentence_position": 8, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "in", "sentence_position": 9, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Iraq", "sentence_position": 10, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-LOC"}, {"token": "and", "sentence_position": 11, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "appreciates", "sentence_position": 12, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "the", "sentence_position": 13, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "contribution", "sentence_position": 14, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "of", "sentence_position": 15, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Mr.", "sentence_position": 16, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Nickolay", "sentence_position": 17, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-PER"}, {"token": "Mladenov", "sentence_position": 18, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-PER"}, {"token": ",", "sentence_position": 19, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "former", "sentence_position": 20, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Bulgarian", "sentence_position": 21, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Foreign", "sentence_position": 22, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Minister", "sentence_position": 23, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": ",", "sentence_position": 24, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Special", "sentence_position": 25, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Representative", "sentence_position": 26, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "of", "sentence_position": 27, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "the", "sentence_position": 28, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Secretary-General", "sentence_position": 29, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "and", "sentence_position": 30, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Head", "sentence_position": 31, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "of", "sentence_position": 32, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "the", "sentence_position": 33, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "United", "sentence_position": 34, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Nations", "sentence_position": 35, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Assistance", "sentence_position": 36, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Mission", "sentence_position": 37, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "for", "sentence_position": 38, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Iraq", "sentence_position": 39, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-LOC"}, {"token": ".", "sentence_position": 40, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": true, "NEtag": "O"}], "sentence_chunktags": [["NP", "B-NP"], ["RB", "O"], ["VBZ", "O"], ["AT", "B-NP"], ["NN", "I-NP"], ["IN", "O"], ["AT", "B-NP"], ["VBN-TL", "I-NP"], ["NNS-TL", "I-NP"], ["IN", "O"], ["NP", "B-NP"], ["CC", "O"], ["VBZ", "O"], ["AT", "B-NP"], ["NN", "I-NP"], ["IN", "O"], ["NP", "B-NP"], ["``", "I-NP"], ["``", "I-NP"], [",", "O"], ["AP", "B-NP"], ["``", "I-NP"], ["JJ-TL", "I-NP"], ["NN-TL", "I-NP"], [",", "O"], ["JJ-TL", "I-NP"], ["NN-TL", "I-NP"], ["IN-TL", "O"], ["AT-TL", "B-NP"], ["NN-TL", "I-NP"], ["CC", "O"], ["NN-TL", "I-NP"], ["IN-TL", "O"], ["AT-TL", "B-NP"], ["VBN-TL", "I-NP"], ["NNS-TL", "I-NP"], ["NN", "I-NP"], ["NN-TL", "I-NP"], ["IN", "O"], ["NP", "B-NP"], [".", "O"]], "sentence_POS": [["Bulgaria", "NP"], ["greatly", "RB"], ["values", "VBZ"], ["the", "AT"], ["role", "NN"], ["of", "IN"], ["the", "AT"], ["United", "VBN-TL"], ["Nations", "NNS-TL"], ["in", "IN"], ["Iraq", "NP"], ["and", "CC"], ["appreciates", "VBZ"], ["the", "AT"], ["contribution", "NN"], ["of", "IN"], ["Mr.", "NP"], ["Nickolay", "``"], ["Mladenov", "``"], [",", ","], ["former", "AP"], ["Bulgarian", "``"], ["Foreign", "JJ-TL"], ["Minister", "NN-TL"], [",", ","], ["Special", "JJ-TL"], ["Representative", "NN-TL"], ["of", "IN-TL"], ["the", "AT-TL"], ["Secretary-General", "NN-TL"], ["and", "CC"], ["Head", "NN-TL"], ["of", "IN-TL"], ["the", "AT-TL"], ["United", "VBN-TL"], ["Nations", "NNS-TL"], ["Assistance", "NN"], ["Mission", "NN-TL"], ["for", "IN"], ["Iraq", "NP"], [".", "."]]}