{"sentence_LOW": ["From", "that", "perspective", ",", "the", "global", "review", "that", "Mr.", "Ban", "Ki-moon", "is", "called", "upon", "to", "present", "in", "April", "2015", "on", "the", "question", "of", "Western", "Sahara", ",", "which", "pits", "the", "Kingdom", "of", "Morocco", "against", "the", "Frente", "Popular", "para", "la", "Liberación", "de", "Saguía", "el-Hamra", "y", "de", "Río", "de", "Oro", ",", "must", "honour", "the", "United", "Nations", "doctrine", "in", "the", "matter", "of", "decolonization", ",", "as", "well", "as", "stress", "the", "importance", "of", "the", "relevant", "Security", "Council", "and", "General", "Assembly", "resolutions", "."], "sentence_words": [{"token": "From", "sentence_position": 0, "sentence_start": true, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "that", "sentence_position": 1, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "perspective", "sentence_position": 2, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": ",", "sentence_position": 3, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "the", "sentence_position": 4, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "global", "sentence_position": 5, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "review", "sentence_position": 6, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "that", "sentence_position": 7, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Mr.", "sentence_position": 8, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Ban", "sentence_position": 9, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-PER"}, {"token": "Ki-moon", "sentence_position": 10, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-PER"}, {"token": "is", "sentence_position": 11, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "called", "sentence_position": 12, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "upon", "sentence_position": 13, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "to", "sentence_position": 14, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "present", "sentence_position": 15, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "in", "sentence_position": 16, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "April", "sentence_position": 17, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "2015", "sentence_position": 18, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "on", "sentence_position": 19, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "the", "sentence_position": 20, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "question", "sentence_position": 21, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "of", "sentence_position": 22, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Western", "sentence_position": 23, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-LOC"}, {"token": "Sahara", "sentence_position": 24, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-LOC"}, {"token": ",", "sentence_position": 25, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "which", "sentence_position": 26, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "pits", "sentence_position": 27, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "the", "sentence_position": 28, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Kingdom", "sentence_position": 29, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-LOC"}, {"token": "of", "sentence_position": 30, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Morocco", "sentence_position": 31, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-LOC"}, {"token": "against", "sentence_position": 32, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "the", "sentence_position": 33, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Frente", "sentence_position": 34, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Popular", "sentence_position": 35, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "para", "sentence_position": 36, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "la", "sentence_position": 37, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Liberación", "sentence_position": 38, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "de", "sentence_position": 39, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Saguía", "sentence_position": 40, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "el-Hamra", "sentence_position": 41, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "y", "sentence_position": 42, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "de", "sentence_position": 43, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Río", "sentence_position": 44, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "de", "sentence_position": 45, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Oro", "sentence_position": 46, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": ",", "sentence_position": 47, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "must", "sentence_position": 48, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "honour", "sentence_position": 49, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "the", "sentence_position": 50, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "United", "sentence_position": 51, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Nations", "sentence_position": 52, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "doctrine", "sentence_position": 53, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "in", "sentence_position": 54, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "the", "sentence_position": 55, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "matter", "sentence_position": 56, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "of", "sentence_position": 57, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "decolonization", "sentence_position": 58, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": ",", "sentence_position": 59, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "as", "sentence_position": 60, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "well", "sentence_position": 61, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "as", "sentence_position": 62, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "stress", "sentence_position": 63, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "the", "sentence_position": 64, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "importance", "sentence_position": 65, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "of", "sentence_position": 66, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "the", "sentence_position": 67, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "relevant", "sentence_position": 68, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "Security", "sentence_position": 69, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Council", "sentence_position": 70, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "and", "sentence_position": 71, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "General", "sentence_position": 72, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Assembly", "sentence_position": 73, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "resolutions", "sentence_position": 74, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": ".", "sentence_position": 75, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": true, "NEtag": "O"}], "sentence_chunktags": [["IN", "O"], ["DT", "B-NP"], ["NN", "I-NP"], [",", "O"], ["AT", "B-NP"], ["JJ", "I-NP"], ["NN", "I-NP"], ["CS", "O"], ["NP", "B-NP"], ["``", "I-NP"], ["``", "I-NP"], ["BEZ", "O"], ["VBN", "O"], ["IN", "O"], ["IN", "O"], ["JJ", "I-NP"], ["IN", "O"], ["NP", "B-NP"], ["CD", "O"], ["IN", "O"], ["AT", "B-NP"], ["NN", "I-NP"], ["IN", "O"], ["JJ-TL", "I-NP"], ["NP-TL", "I-NP"], [",", "O"], ["WDT", "O"], ["NNS", "I-NP"], ["AT", "B-NP"], ["NN-TL", "I-NP"], ["IN-TL", "O"], ["NP-TL", "I-NP"], ["IN", "O"], ["AT", "B-NP"], ["``", "I-NP"], ["JJ-TL", "I-NP"], ["``", "I-NP"], ["FW-AT", null], ["``", "I-NP"], ["FW-IN", null], ["``", "I-NP"], ["``", "I-NP"], ["NN", "I-NP"], ["FW-IN", null], ["``", "I-NP"], ["FW-IN", null], ["``", "I-NP"], [",", "O"], ["MD", "O"], ["NN", "I-NP"], ["AT", "B-NP"], ["VBN-TL", "I-NP"], ["NNS-TL", "I-NP"], ["NN", "I-NP"], ["IN", "O"], ["AT", "B-NP"], ["NN", "I-NP"], ["IN", "O"], ["``", "I-NP"], [",", "O"], ["CS", "O"], ["RB", "O"], ["CS", "O"], ["NN", "I-NP"], ["AT", "B-NP"], ["NN", "I-NP"], ["IN", "O"], ["AT", "B-NP"], ["JJ", "I-NP"], ["NN-TL", "I-NP"], ["NN-TL", "I-NP"], ["CC", "O"], ["NN-TL", "I-NP"], ["NN-TL", "I-NP"], ["NNS", "I-NP"], [".", "O"]], "sentence_POS": [["From", "IN"], ["that", "DT"], ["perspective", "NN"], [",", ","], ["the", "AT"], ["global", "JJ"], ["review", "NN"], ["that", "CS"], ["Mr.", "NP"], ["Ban", "``"], ["Ki-moon", "``"], ["is", "BEZ"], ["called", "VBN"], ["upon", "IN"], ["to", "IN"], ["present", "JJ"], ["in", "IN"], ["April", "NP"], ["2015", "CD"], ["on", "IN"], ["the", "AT"], ["question", "NN"], ["of", "IN"], ["Western", "JJ-TL"], ["Sahara", "NP-TL"], [",", ","], ["which", "WDT"], ["pits", "NNS"], ["the", "AT"], ["Kingdom", "NN-TL"], ["of", "IN-TL"], ["Morocco", "NP-TL"], ["against", "IN"], ["the", "AT"], ["Frente", "``"], ["Popular", "JJ-TL"], ["para", "``"], ["la", "FW-AT"], ["Liberación", "``"], ["de", "FW-IN"], ["Saguía", "``"], ["el-Hamra", "``"], ["y", "NN"], ["de", "FW-IN"], ["Río", "``"], ["de", "FW-IN"], ["Oro", "``"], [",", ","], ["must", "MD"], ["honour", "NN"], ["the", "AT"], ["United", "VBN-TL"], ["Nations", "NNS-TL"], ["doctrine", "NN"], ["in", "IN"], ["the", "AT"], ["matter", "NN"], ["of", "IN"], ["decolonization", "``"], [",", ","], ["as", "CS"], ["well", "RB"], ["as", "CS"], ["stress", "NN"], ["the", "AT"], ["importance", "NN"], ["of", "IN"], ["the", "AT"], ["relevant", "JJ"], ["Security", "NN-TL"], ["Council", "NN-TL"], ["and", "CC"], ["General", "NN-TL"], ["Assembly", "NN-TL"], ["resolutions", "NNS"], [".", "."]]}