{"sentence_LOW": ["Myanmar", "has", "been", "cooperating", "closely", "with", "the", "United", "Nations", "Human", "Rights", "Council", "."], "sentence_words": [{"token": "Myanmar", "sentence_position": 0, "sentence_start": true, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-LOC"}, {"token": "has", "sentence_position": 1, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "been", "sentence_position": 2, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "cooperating", "sentence_position": 3, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "closely", "sentence_position": 4, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "with", "sentence_position": 5, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "the", "sentence_position": 6, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "O"}, {"token": "United", "sentence_position": 7, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Nations", "sentence_position": 8, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Human", "sentence_position": 9, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Rights", "sentence_position": 10, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": "Council", "sentence_position": 11, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": false, "NEtag": "I-ORG"}, {"token": ".", "sentence_position": 12, "sentence_start": false, "sentence_end": true, "NEtag": "O"}], "sentence_chunktags": [["``", "I-NP"], ["HVZ", "O"], ["BEN", "O"], ["VBG", "O"], ["RB", "O"], ["IN", "O"], ["AT", "B-NP"], ["VBN-TL", "I-NP"], ["NNS-TL", "I-NP"], ["JJ-TL", "I-NP"], ["NNS-TL", "I-NP"], ["NN-TL", "I-NP"], [".", "O"]], "sentence_POS": [["Myanmar", "``"], ["has", "HVZ"], ["been", "BEN"], ["cooperating", "VBG"], ["closely", "RB"], ["with", "IN"], ["the", "AT"], ["United", "VBN-TL"], ["Nations", "NNS-TL"], ["Human", "JJ-TL"], ["Rights", "NNS-TL"], ["Council", "NN-TL"], [".", "."]]}