It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
privilege	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
an	DET	O
honour	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
me	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
address	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
audience	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
represent	NOUN	O
Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
in	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
new	ADJ	O
status	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
State	NOUN	O
member	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
European	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

Having	NOUN	O
subscribed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
statement	NOUN	O
made	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Prime	NOUN	O
Minister	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Portugal	NOUN	I-LOC
(see	NOUN	O
A/62/PV	NOUN	O
.	.	O
4)	NOUN	O
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
assure	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
that	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
part	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
European	NOUN	I-ORG
family	NOUN	O
,	.	O
my	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
now	ADV	O
even	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
committed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
universal	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
normative	NOUN	O
role	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
in	ADP	O
today	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
globalized	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
delighted	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
see	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
leadership	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
body	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
outstanding	NOUN	O
representative	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
neighbouring	NOUN	O
State	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
region	NOUN	O
,	.	O
South-Eastern	NOUN	O
Europe	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
reiterate	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
my	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
fully	NOUN	O
supports	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
priorities	NOUN	O
you	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
outlined	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
work	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
session	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
wish	VERB	O
you	NOUN	O
every	DET	O
success	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
months	NOUN	O
ahead	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Our	NOUN	O
gratitude	NOUN	O
goes	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
Her	PRON	O
Excellency	NOUN	O
Sheikha	NOUN	I-PER
Haya	NOUN	I-PER
Rashed	NOUN	I-PER
Al-Khalifa	NOUN	I-PER
,	.	O
for	NOUN	O
her	PRON	O
leadership	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
President	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
sixty-first	NOUN	O
session	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
take	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
opportunity	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
commend	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
dedicated	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
energetic	NOUN	O
performance	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Ban	NOUN	I-PER
Ki-moon	NOUN	I-PER
,	.	O
during	NOUN	O
his	PRON	O
first	NOUN	O
nine	NOUN	O
months	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
office	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
thank	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
President	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
having	NOUN	O
chosen	NOUN	O
climate	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
central	NOUN	O
theme	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
debate	NOUN	O
.	.	O

That	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
challenge	NOUN	O
calls	NOUN	O
upon	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
us	PRON	O
to	NOUN	O
provide	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
immediate	NOUN	O
response	NOUN	O
based	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
shared	NOUN	O
but	CONJ	O
differentiated	NOUN	O
responsibilities	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Member	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Global	ADJ	O
warming	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
exacerbating	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
serious	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
social	NOUN	O
problems	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
developing	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
facing	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
also	ADV	O
threatens	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
implementation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
development	NOUN	O
goals	NOUN	O
set	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
,	.	O
including	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Millennium	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
Goals	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
prepared	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
play	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
part	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
solidarity	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
developing	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Unfortunately	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
list	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
serious	NOUN	O
threats	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
common	NOUN	O
security	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
short	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Non-proliferation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
weapons	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
mass	NOUN	O
destruction	NOUN	O
,	.	O
arms	NOUN	O
control	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
disarmament	NOUN	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
forefront	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
scene	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Strengthening	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
regime	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Treaty	NOUN	I-MISC
on	ADP	I-MISC
the	DET	I-MISC
Non-Proliferation	NOUN	I-MISC
of	ADP	I-MISC
Nuclear	NOUN	I-MISC
Weapons	NOUN	I-MISC
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
truly	NOUN	O
universal	NOUN	O
remains	NOUN	O
one	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
major	NOUN	O
priorities	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
time	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
regrettable	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
no	DET	O
progress	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
achieved	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
pending	NOUN	O
question	NOUN	O
regarding	NOUN	O
Iran	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
nuclear	NOUN	O
programme	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
reaffirms	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Programme	NOUN	I-MISC
of	ADP	I-MISC
Action	NOUN	I-MISC
on	ADP	I-MISC
Small	NOUN	I-MISC
Arms	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
firmly	NOUN	O
committed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
process	NOUN	O
towards	NOUN	O
adoption	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
an	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
treaty	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
arms	NOUN	O
trade	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
near	NOUN	O
future	NOUN	O
.	.	O

My	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
unambiguously	NOUN	O
condemns	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
rejects	NOUN	O
terrorist	NOUN	O
ideology	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
forms	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
manifestations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Terrorism	NOUN	O
cannot	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
linked	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
any	NOUN	O
specific	NOUN	O
culture	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
religion	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
must	NOUN	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
play	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
central	NOUN	O
role	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
mobilizing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
meet	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
challenge	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
meet	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
related	NOUN	O
challenge	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
radicalism	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
political	NOUN	O
extremism	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
order	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
combat	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
first	NOUN	O
address	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
fundamental	NOUN	O
problems	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
poverty	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
underdevelopment	NOUN	O
,	.	O
overcome	NOUN	O
prejudices	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
stereotypes	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
promote	NOUN	O
tolerance	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
great	NOUN	O
diversity	NOUN	O
.	.	O

That	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
why	NOUN	O
Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
has	NOUN	O
joined	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Group	NOUN	I-ORG
of	ADP	I-ORG
Friends	NOUN	I-ORG
of	ADP	I-ORG
the	DET	I-ORG
Alliance	NOUN	I-ORG
of	ADP	I-ORG
Civilizations	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
fully	NOUN	O
supporting	NOUN	O
other	NOUN	O
complementary	NOUN	O
initiatives	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
well	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
situation	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
continues	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
source	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
concern	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
.	.	O

This	NOUN	O
calls	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
commitment	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
participating	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
joint	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
ensure	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
able	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
vision	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
safe	NOUN	O
,	.	O
unified	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
democratic	NOUN	O
State	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Afghanistan	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
another	NOUN	O
example	NOUN	O
where	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
powerful	NOUN	O
need	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
felt	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
see	NOUN	O
increased	NOUN	O
involvement	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
along	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
NATO	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
European	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
difficult	NOUN	O
national	NOUN	O
reconstruction	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Progress	NOUN	O
towards	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Middle	NOUN	I-LOC
East	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
of	ADP	O
primary	NOUN	O
importance	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
welcomes	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
resumption	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
bilateral	NOUN	O
talks	NOUN	O
between	NOUN	O
President	NOUN	O
Abbas	NOUN	I-PER
and	CONJ	O
Prime	NOUN	O
Minister	NOUN	O
Olmert	NOUN	I-PER
and	CONJ	O
hopes	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
they	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
lead	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
just	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
lasting	NOUN	O
solution	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
accordance	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
relevant	NOUN	O
resolutions	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
Quartet	NOUN	I-MISC
principles	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

Lebanon	NOUN	I-LOC
too	NOUN	O
continues	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
require	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
strong	NOUN	O
commitment	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
part	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
secure	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
national	NOUN	O
unity	NOUN	O
,	.	O
territorial	NOUN	O
integrity	NOUN	O
,	.	O
recovery	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
reconstruction	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Today	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
role	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
is	VERB	O
no	DET	O
longer	NOUN	O
solely	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
maintain	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
ensure	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
firmly	NOUN	O
rooted	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
sustainable	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Peacebuilding	NOUN	I-ORG
Commission	NOUN	I-ORG
is	VERB	O
now	ADV	O
up	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
running	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
believe	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
has	NOUN	O
great	NOUN	O
potential	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
its	NOUN	O
position	NOUN	O
vis-à-vis	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
principal	NOUN	O
organs	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
strengthened	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
better	NOUN	O
defined	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
see	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
future	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Commission	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
modern	NOUN	O
multilateral	NOUN	O
instrument	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
long-term	NOUN	O
resolution	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
conflicts	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
institution-building	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Human	NOUN	I-ORG
Rights	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
has	NOUN	O
led	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
compromise	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
believe	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
led	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
opportunities	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
an	DET	O
effective	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
tool	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
promote	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
fundamental	NOUN	O
freedoms	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
fully	NOUN	O
shares	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
view	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
life	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
supreme	NOUN	O
value	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
invites	NOUN	O
Member	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
draft	NOUN	O
resolution	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
a	DET	O
moratorium	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
and	CONJ	O
abolition	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
death	NOUN	O
penalty	NOUN	O
.	.	O

For	NOUN	O
multilateralism	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
effective	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
involve	NOUN	O
strong	NOUN	O
partnership	NOUN	O
between	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
regional	NOUN	O
organizations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
heartily	NOUN	O
endorse	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
growing	NOUN	O
interaction	NOUN	O
between	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
European	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

The	DET	O
recently	NOUN	O
updated	NOUN	O
Joint	NOUN	I-MISC
Declaration	NOUN	I-MISC
on	ADP	VMISC
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations-	NOUN	I-ORG
European	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
Cooperation	NOUN	I-MISC
in	ADP	I-MISC
Crisis	NOUN	I-MISC
Management	NOUN	I-MISC
has	NOUN	O
provided	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
avenue	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
joint	NOUN	O
action	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
addition	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
African	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
are	VERB	O
involved	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
an	DET	O
unprecedented	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
operation	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
African	NOUN	I-ORG
Union-United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Hybrid	NOUN	I-MISC
Operation	NOUN	I-MISC
in	ADP	O
Darfur	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
for	NOUN	O
remedying	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
critical	NOUN	O
situation	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Darfur	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
also	ADV	O
welcome	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
pragmatic	NOUN	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
established	NOUN	O
between	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
NATO	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

Various	NOUN	O
forms	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
regional	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
subregional	NOUN	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
always	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
cornerstone	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
global	ADJ	O
system	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
collective	NOUN	O
security	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
now	ADV	O
chairing	NOUN	O
two	NOUN	O
regional	NOUN	O
organizations:	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Central	NOUN	I-ORG
European	NOUN	I-ORG
Initiative	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
South-East	NOUN	O
European	NOUN	I-ORG
Cooperation	NOUN	I-ORG
Process	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Stability	NOUN	I-MISC
Pact	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
which	DET	O
was	VERB	O
launched	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
initiative	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
European	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
in	ADP	O
1999	NUM	O
,	.	O
has	NOUN	O
provided	NOUN	O
important	NOUN	O
impetus	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
accordance	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
concept	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
regional	NOUN	O
ownership	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
key	NOUN	O
role	NOUN	O
today	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
assumed	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
South-East	NOUN	I-MISC
European	NOUN	I-MISC
Cooperation	NOUN	I-MISC
Process	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

Agreement	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
creation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
regional	NOUN	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
council	NOUN	O
secretariat	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
just	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
signed	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Ministers	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
Foreign	NOUN	O
Affairs	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
member	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Bulgarian	NOUN	I-MISC
city	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Plovdiv	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
now	ADV	O
leading	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
will	VERB	O
spare	NOUN	O
no	DET	O
effort	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
strengthen	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
prospects	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
European	NOUN	I-MISC
integration	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
entire	NOUN	O
South-East	NOUN	O
European	NOUN	I-ORG
region	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Our	NOUN	O
priorities	NOUN	O
focus	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
sectors	NOUN	O
such	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
infrastructure	NOUN	O
,	.	O
security	NOUN	O
,	.	O
energy	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
environment	NOUN	O
,	.	O
tourism	NOUN	O
,	.	O
justice	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
domestic	NOUN	O
affairs	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
unresolved	NOUN	O
status	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Kosovo	NOUN	I-LOC
has	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
negative	NOUN	O
effect	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
security	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
entire	NOUN	O
region	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
regret	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
has	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
able	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
adopt	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
resolution	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
replace	NOUN	O
resolution	NOUN	O
1244	NUM	O
(1999)	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
thus	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
confirm	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
backing	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
negotiated	NOUN	O
solution	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
basis	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
proposal	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Special	ADJ	O
Envoy	NOUN	O
Ahtisaari	NOUN	I-PER
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
steadily	NOUN	O
supports	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
aimed	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
reaching	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
quickly	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
possible	NOUN	O
,	.	O
a	DET	O
viable	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
legitimate	NOUN	O
solution	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
respect	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
status	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Kosovo	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

Such	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
settlement	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
guarantee	NOUN	O
regional	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
stability	NOUN	O
;	.	O
it	PRON	O
should	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
account	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
interests	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
concerns	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
neighbouring	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Thanks	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
efforts	NOUN	O
deployed	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Contact	NOUN	I-ORG
Group	NOUN	I-ORG
Troika	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
now	ADV	O
have	NOUN	O
perhaps	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
final	NOUN	O
chance	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
find	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
negotiated	NOUN	O
solution	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
hope	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
Belgrade	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
Pristina	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
able	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
opportunity	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
find	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
compromise	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
open	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
path	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
European	NOUN	I-ORG
future	NOUN	O
.	.	O

While	CONJ	O
these	NOUN	O
talks	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
under	ADP	O
way	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
essential	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
prevent	NOUN	O
any	NOUN	O
worsening	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
situation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
—	.	O
first	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
foremost	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
NATO	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
the	DET	O
European	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
Organization	NOUN	I-ORG
for	NOUN	I-ORG
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	I-ORG
Cooperation	NOUN	I-ORG
in	ADP	I-ORG
Europe	NOUN	I-ORG
—	.	O
are	VERB	O
working	NOUN	O
together	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
local	NOUN	O
institutions	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
they	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
provide	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
necessary	NOUN	O
instruments	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
guarantees	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
preserve	NOUN	O
regional	NOUN	O
stability	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Promoting	NOUN	O
democratization	NOUN	O
,	.	O
stability	NOUN	O
,	.	O
security	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
major	NOUN	O
challenge	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Black	NOUN	I-LOC
Sea	NOUN	I-LOC
region	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Consistent	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
required	NOUN	O
so	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
can	NOUN	O
arrive	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
a	DET	O
settlement	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
frozen	NOUN	O
conflicts	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Transdniestria	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
southern	NOUN	O
Caucasus	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
which	DET	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
undermine	NOUN	O
stability	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
hamper	NOUN	O
regional	NOUN	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
actively	NOUN	O
supports	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
formulation	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
implementation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Black	NOUN	I-LOC
Sea	NOUN	I-LOC
dimension	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
policy	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
good-neighbourliness	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
European	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

Major	NOUN	O
projects	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
started	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
important	NOUN	O
sectors	NOUN	O
such	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
transportation	NOUN	O
,	.	O
energy	NOUN	O
,	.	O
trade	NOUN	O
,	.	O
environment	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
border	NOUN	O
security	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Stability	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
predictability	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
region	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
more	NOUN	O
important	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
ever	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
ensure	NOUN	O
energy	NOUN	O
security	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Europe	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
ensure	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
diversification	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
reliability	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
energy	NOUN	O
supplies	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
continent	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
firmly	NOUN	O
convinced	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
order	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
to	NOUN	O
play	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
role	NOUN	O
effectively	NOUN	O
worldwide	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
steadfastly	NOUN	O
pursue	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
radical	NOUN	O
reforms	NOUN	O
identified	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
2005	NUM	O
World	NOUN	I-MISC
Summit	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

Progress	NOUN	O
was	VERB	O
achieved	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
sixty-first	NOUN	O
session	NOUN	O
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
much	NOUN	O
remains	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
done	NOUN	O
so	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
reforms	NOUN	O
meet	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
hopes	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Despite	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
good-faith	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
mediators	NOUN	O
,	.	O
no	DET	O
tangible	NOUN	O
progress	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
seen	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
a	DET	O
question	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
discussed	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
length:	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

My	PRON	O
delegation	NOUN	O
supports	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
recommendation	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
move	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
forward	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
negotiation	NOUN	O
phase	NOUN	O
,	.	O
with	ADP	O
a	DET	O
view	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
reaching	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
broadly	NOUN	O
acceptable	NOUN	O
compromise	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
take	NOUN	O
account	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
equitable	NOUN	O
geographic	NOUN	O
representation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
obvious	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
will	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
easy	NOUN	O
task	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
require	NOUN	O
interim	NOUN	O
solutions	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
various	NOUN	O
stages	NOUN	O
over	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
certain	NOUN	O
period	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
time	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
first	NOUN	O
step	NOUN	O
,	.	O
however	NOUN	O
,	.	O
cannot	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
put	NOUN	O
off	NOUN	O
indefinitely	NOUN	O
,	.	O
because	CONJ	O
if	CONJ	O
we	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
unable	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
then	NOUN	O
broad	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
incomplete	NOUN	O
.	.	O

A	DET	O
critical	NOUN	O
consideration	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
implementation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
number	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
pilot	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
One	NOUN	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Initiative	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
revealed	NOUN	O
positive	NOUN	O
results	NOUN	O
.	.	O

But	CONJ	O
consensus	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
yet	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
emerge	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
how	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
further	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
process	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
attaining	NOUN	O
system-wide	NOUN	O
coherence	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
work	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
hope	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
final	NOUN	O
outcome	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
take	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
form	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
improved	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
increased	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
assistance	NOUN	O
,	.	O
which	DET	O
would	VERB	O
go	NOUN	O
together	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
a	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
synergy	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
concerned	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
competent	NOUN	O
structures	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
conclusion	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
should	NOUN	O
recognize	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
progress	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
made	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
number	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
reform	NOUN	O
areas	NOUN	O
.	.	O

But	CONJ	O
we	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
yet	NOUN	O
achieved	NOUN	O
enough	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
expects	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
remaining	NOUN	O
tasks	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
reform	NOUN	O
agenda	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
pursued	NOUN	O
energetically	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
without	NOUN	O
delay	NOUN	O
.	.	O

To	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
end	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
appeal	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
Member	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
show	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
flexibility	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
decisions	NOUN	O
needed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
ensure	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
consistency	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
reform	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
in	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
common	NOUN	O
interest	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
ensure	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
sixty-second	NOUN	O
session	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
success	NOUN	O
.	.	O

So	NOUN	O
let	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
work	NOUN	O
together	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
with	ADP	O
goodwill	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
happen	NOUN	O
.	.	O
