I	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
extend	NOUN	O
my	PRON	O
warmest	NOUN	O
gratitude	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
Mr.	NOUN	O
John	NOUN	I-PER
Ashe	NOUN	I-PER
for	NOUN	O
his	PRON	O
work	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
President	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
sixty-eighth	NOUN	O
session	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Over	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
past	NOUN	O
few	NOUN	O
months	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
Balkans	NOUN	I-LOC
have	NOUN	O
suffered	NOUN	O
unprecedented	NOUN	O
floods	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Thousands	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
people	NOUN	O
lost	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
homes	NOUN	O
,	.	O
crops	NOUN	O
were	NOUN	O
ruined	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
many	NOUN	O
innocent	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
died	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
heavy	NOUN	O
storms	NOUN	O
were	NOUN	O
no	DET	O
longer	NOUN	O
news	NOUN	O
but	CONJ	O
a	DET	O
part	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
daily	NOUN	O
life	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Nature	NOUN	O
once	NOUN	O
again	NOUN	O
reminded	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
that	NOUN	O
today	NOUN	O
,	.	O
political	NOUN	O
statements	NOUN	O
alone	NOUN	O
were	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
sufficient	NOUN	O
.	.	O

For	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
sake	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
children	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
our	NOUN	O
planet	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
time	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
act	NOUN	O
.	.	O

As	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
wise	NOUN	O
man	NOUN	O
once	NOUN	O
said	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
did	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
inherit	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Earth	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
fathers	NOUN	O
;	.	O
we	PRON	O
borrowed	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
from	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
children	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Climate	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
needs	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
urgently	NOUN	O
addressed	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
thank	NOUN	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
Ban	NOUN	I-PER
Ki-moon	NOUN	I-PER
for	NOUN	O
having	NOUN	O
organized	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Climate	NOUN	I-MISC
Summit	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
actively	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
completion	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
negotiations	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
,	.	O
universal	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
legally	NOUN	O
binding	NOUN	O
climate	NOUN	O
agreement	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
2015	NUM	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
contributed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
implementation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Millennium	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
Goals	NOUN	I-MISC
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
development	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
post-2015	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
agenda	NOUN	O
through	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
successful	NOUN	O
participation	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Open	NOUN	O
Working	NOUN	O
Group	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
Sustainable	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
Goals	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Group	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
fulfilled	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
mandate	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Group	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
report	NOUN	O
,	.	O
together	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
report	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
High-level	NOUN	I-MISC
Panel	NOUN	I-MISC
of	ADP	I-MISC
Eminent	NOUN	I-MISC
Persons	NOUN	I-MISC
on	ADP	I-MISC
the	DET	I-MISC
Post-2015	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
Agenda	NOUN	I-MISC
(A/67/890	NOUN	O
,	.	O
annex)	NOUN	O
,	.	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
leading	NOUN	O
documents	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
future	NOUN	O
discussions	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
enter	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
critical	NOUN	O
phase	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
debate	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
post-2015	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
agenda	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
crucial	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
sides	NOUN	O
stay	NOUN	O
engaged	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
committed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
final	NOUN	O
goal	NOUN	O
—	.	O
an	DET	O
ambitious	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
forward-looking	NOUN	O
framework	NOUN	O
.	.	O

No	DET	O
real	NOUN	O
transformative	NOUN	O
post-2015	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
agenda	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
possible	NOUN	O
unless	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
address	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
loopholes	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
current	NOUN	O
Millennium	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
Goals	NOUN	I-MISC
and	CONJ	O
build	NOUN	O
upon	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
lessons	NOUN	O
learned	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
framework	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
founded	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
principles	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
respect	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
,	.	O
inclusiveness	NOUN	O
,	.	O
good	NOUN	O
governance	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
rule	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
law	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Youth-specific	NOUN	O
targets	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
areas	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
education	NOUN	O
,	.	O
health	NOUN	O
care	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
employment	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
of	ADP	O
paramount	NOUN	O
importance	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
well	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Development	NOUN	I-MISC
is	VERB	O
unthinkable	NOUN	O
without	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
security	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
security	NOUN	O
environment	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Black	NOUN	I-LOC
Sea	NOUN	I-LOC
region	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
seriously	NOUN	O
affected	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
illegal	NOUN	O
annexation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Crimea	NOUN	I-LOC
undermines	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
order	NOUN	O
.	.	O

After	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Second	NOUN	I-MISC
World	NOUN	I-MISC
War	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
built	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
clear	NOUN	O
principles	NOUN	O
embodied	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Charter	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

They	NOUN	O
were	NOUN	O
shattered	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
pieces	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
matter	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
weeks	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
strongly	NOUN	O
supports	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
sovereignty	NOUN	O
,	.	O
unity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
territorial	NOUN	O
integrity	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Ukraine	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

My	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
does	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
recognize	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
illegal	NOUN	O
referendum	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Crimea	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
condemns	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
￼annexation	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
Russia	NOUN	I-LOC
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
violation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
international	NOUN	O
law	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
joined	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
numerous	NOUN	O
sponsors	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
resolution	NOUN	O
68/262	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
territorial	NOUN	O
integrity	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Ukraine	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

My	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
welcomes	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
ceasefire	NOUN	O
agreement	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
is	VERB	O
looking	NOUN	O
forward	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
implementation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
peace	NOUN	O
plan	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
commends	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
peaceful	NOUN	O
resolution	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
conflict	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Russia	NOUN	I-LOC
should	NOUN	O
stop	NOUN	O
arming	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
supporting	NOUN	O
separatists	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Ukraine	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
a	DET	O
few	NOUN	O
days	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Ukrainians	NOUN	I-MISC
will	VERB	O
vote	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
parliament	NOUN	O
.	.	O

They	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
every	DET	O
right	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
choose	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
own	NOUN	O
future	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
sincerely	NOUN	O
hope	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
elections	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
major	NOUN	O
step	NOUN	O
forward	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
building	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
democratic	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
prosperous	NOUN	O
Ukraine	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

The	DET	O
signing	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
ratification	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
European	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
Association	NOUN	O
Agreements	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Ukraine	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Moldova	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
Georgia	NOUN	I-LOC
represent	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
important	NOUN	O
milestone	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
process	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
European	NOUN	I-ORG
integration	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
those	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
positive	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
witnessed	NOUN	O
today	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Balkans	NOUN	I-LOC
would	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
possible	NOUN	O
without	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
engine	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
European	NOUN	I-MISC
integration	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
escalation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
violence	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
humanitarian	NOUN	O
situation	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Syria	NOUN	I-LOC
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
source	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
grave	NOUN	O
concern	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Millions	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
refugees	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
fled	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
homeland	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
pursuit	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
peace	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
neighbouring	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Hundreds	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
thousands	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
lost	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
lives	NOUN	O
.	.	O

More	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
10	NUM	O
,000	NOUN	O
refugees	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
sought	NOUN	O
asylum	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

A	DET	O
lasting	NOUN	O
solution	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
conflict	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Syria	NOUN	I-LOC
can	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
achieved	NOUN	O
only	NOUN	O
through	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
inclusive	NOUN	O
political	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
call	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
to	NOUN	O
unite	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
unity	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
is	VERB	O
crucial	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
order	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
conflict	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
resolved	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Syrian	NOUN	I-MISC
crisis	NOUN	O
,	.	O
along	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
outbreak	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
violence	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
sectarian	NOUN	O
tensions	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
has	NOUN	O
exacerbated	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
security	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
humanitarian	NOUN	O
situation	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
entire	NOUN	O
Middle	NOUN	I-LOC
East	NOUN	I-LOC
region	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
strongly	NOUN	O
condemns	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
armed	NOUN	O
attacks	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
killings	NOUN	O
perpetrated	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Islamic	NOUN	I-ORG
State	NOUN	I-ORG
terrorist	NOUN	O
organization	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
religious	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
ethnic	NOUN	O
minorities	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
denounces	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
brutal	NOUN	O
execution	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
innocent	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
an	DET	O
integral	NOUN	O
part	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
broad	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
coalition	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
.	.	O

A	DET	O
member	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
European	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
of	ADP	O
NATO	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
my	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
lends	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
political	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
well	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
humanitarian	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
material	NOUN	O
aid	NOUN	O
,	.	O
within	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
scope	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
possibilities	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Combating	NOUN	O
radicalization	NOUN	O
,	.	O
supporting	NOUN	O
State-building	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
cooperating	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
regional	NOUN	O
partners	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
essential	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
welcome	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
election	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Mr.	NOUN	O
Haider	NOUN	I-PER
Al	NOUN	I-PER
Abadi	NOUN	I-PER
as	NOUN	O
Prime	NOUN	O
Minister	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
hope	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
,	.	O
under	ADP	O
his	PRON	O
leadership	NOUN	O
,	.	O
a	DET	O
Government	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
broad	NOUN	O
representation	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
established	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
order	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
preserve	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
territorial	NOUN	O
integrity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
sovereignty	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
country	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
greatly	NOUN	O
values	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
role	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
in	ADP	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
appreciates	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
contribution	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Mr.	NOUN	O
Nickolay	NOUN	I-PER
Mladenov	NOUN	I-PER
,	.	O
former	NOUN	O
Bulgarian	NOUN	O
Foreign	NOUN	O
Minister	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Special	ADJ	O
Representative	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
Head	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Assistance	NOUN	I-ORG
Mission	NOUN	I-ORG
for	NOUN	I-ORG
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
stand	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
just	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
lasting	NOUN	O
settlement	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Israeli-Palestinian	NOUN	I-MISC
conflict	NOUN	O
based	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
two-State	NOUN	O
solution	NOUN	O
formula	NOUN	O
.	.	O

That	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
possible	NOUN	O
only	NOUN	O
through	NOUN	O
direct	NOUN	O
negotiations	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
no	DET	O
preconditions	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
in	ADP	O
conformity	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
relevant	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
obligations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
adoption	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Arms	NOUN	I-MISC
Trade	NOUN	I-MISC
Treaty	NOUN	I-MISC
was	VERB	O
a	DET	O
major	NOUN	O
achievement	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Just	NOUN	O
over	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
year	NOUN	O
later	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
threshold	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
50	NUM	O
ratifications	NOUN	O
was	VERB	O
reached	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
morning	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
am	VERB	O
glad	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
my	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
among	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
50	NUM	O
States	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
made	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
entry	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
force	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
that	NOUN	O
important	NOUN	O
legal	NOUN	O
instrument	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
reality	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Arms	NOUN	I-MISC
Trade	NOUN	I-MISC
Treaty	NOUN	I-MISC
fills	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
serious	NOUN	O
gap	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
international	NOUN	O
law	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
establishes	NOUN	O
regulations	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
trade	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
conventional	NOUN	O
arms	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
global	ADJ	O
level	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Now	ADV	O
its	NOUN	O
implementation	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
universalization	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
utmost	NOUN	O
importance	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Twenty-five	NOUN	O
years	NOUN	O
ago	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
Berlin	NOUN	I-LOC
Wall	NOUN	I-I-MISC
fell	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
democratic	NOUN	O
transitions	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Central	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
Eastern	NOUN	I-LOC
Europe	NOUN	I-LOC
began	NOUN	O
.	.	O

My	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
chose	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
become	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
modern	NOUN	O
European	NOUN	I-MISC
democracy	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
put	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
country	NOUN	O
back	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
path	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
freedom	NOUN	O
,	.	O
independence	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
rule	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
law	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
respect	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Our	NOUN	O
society	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
proved	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
firm	NOUN	O
commitment	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
democratic	NOUN	O
values	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
principles	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
witnessed	NOUN	O
similar	NOUN	O
political	NOUN	O
changes	NOUN	O
across	NOUN	O
South-East	NOUN	O
Europe	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Balkan	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
become	NOUN	O
partners	NOUN	O
,	.	O
sharing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
same	NOUN	O
values	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
projects	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
future	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
built	NOUN	O
bridges	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
trust	NOUN	O
,	.	O
friendship	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
mutual	NOUN	O
respect	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
working	NOUN	O
together	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
improve	NOUN	O
links	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
competition	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
order	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
increase	NOUN	O
prosperity	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Balkans	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

Human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
,	.	O
democracy	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
rule	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
law	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
heart	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
my	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
foreign	NOUN	O
policy	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
commitment	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
advancing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
agenda	NOUN	O
throughout	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
system	NOUN	O
was	VERB	O
further	NOUN	O
strengthened	NOUN	O
under	ADP	O
the	DET	O
successful	NOUN	O
Bulgarian	NOUN	I-MISC
￼chairmanship	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Social	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	I-ORG
Humanitarian	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	I-ORG
Cultural	NOUN	I-ORG
Committee	NOUN	I-ORG
during	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
sixty-eighth	NOUN	O
session	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
General	NOUN	I-ORG
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
determined	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
further	NOUN	O
contribute	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
promoting	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
upholding	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
internationally	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
member	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Human	NOUN	I-ORG
Rights	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
period	NOUN	O
2019-2021	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
will	VERB	O
rely	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
partners'	NOUN	O
valuable	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
candidature	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
wish	VERB	O
Prince	NOUN	O
Zeid	NOUN	I-PER
all	NOUN	O
success	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
fulfilling	NOUN	O
his	PRON	O
mandate	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
support	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
Rights	NOUN	O
Up	NOUN	O
Front	NOUN	O
Action	NOUN	O
Plan	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
safeguard	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
around	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
commends	NOUN	O
Deputy	NOUN	O
Secretary-	NOUN	O
General	NOUN	0
Jan	NOUN	I-PER
Eliasson	NOUN	I-PER
for	NOUN	O
his	PRON	O
insightful	NOUN	O
vision	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
global	ADJ	O
leadership	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
regard	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
initiative	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
his	PRON	O
valuable	NOUN	O
contribution	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
advancing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
agenda	NOUN	O
throughout	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
concerned	NOUN	O
about	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
anti-Semitic	NOUN	O
attacks	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
taken	NOUN	O
place	NOUN	O
recently	NOUN	O
,	.	O
especially	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Europe	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

As	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
country	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
saved	NOUN	O
48	NUM	O
,000	NOUN	O
Bulgarian	NOUN	I-MISC
Jews	NOUN	I-MISC
from	NOUN	O
deportation	NOUN	O
during	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Second	NOUN	I-MISC
World	NOUN	I-MISC
War	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
strongly	NOUN	O
condemns	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
recurring	NOUN	O
trend	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
brutal	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
disgusting	NOUN	O
manifestations	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
anti-Semitism	NOUN	O
.	.	O

This	NOUN	O
year	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
celebrating	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
twenty-fifth	NOUN	O
anniversary	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
adoption	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Convention	NOUN	I-MISC
on	ADP	I-MISC
the	DET	I-MISC
Rights	NOUN	I-MISC
of	ADP	I-MISC
the	DET	I-MISC
Child	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
which	DET	O
set	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
universal	NOUN	O
standard	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
effective	NOUN	O
promotion	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
children	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
commends	NOUN	O
UNICEF	NOUN	I-ORG
for	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
enormous	NOUN	O
contribution	NOUN	O
during	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
time	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
improving	NOUN	O
children	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
lives	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
advancing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
child	NOUN	O
agenda	NOUN	O
around	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
.	.	O

As	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
member	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Bureau	NOUN	I-ORG
of	ADP	I-ORG
the	DET	I-ORG
UNICEF	NOUN	I-ORG
Executive	NOUN	I-ORG
Board	NOUN	I-ORG
this	NOUN	O
year	NOUN	O
,	.	O
my	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
supports	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
actively	NOUN	O
participates	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
aimed	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
child	NOUN	O
protection	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
achieving	NOUN	O
results	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
children	NOUN	O
.	.	O

My	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
convinced	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
reform	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
continue	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
order	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
enhance	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
efficiency	NOUN	O
,	.	O
representativeness	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
transparency	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
entire	NOUN	O
system	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
more	NOUN	O
adequate	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
responsive	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
realities	NOUN	O
.	.	O

As	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
member	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Eastern	NOUN	O
European	NOUN	I-MISC
regional	NOUN	O
group	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
reiterates	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
position	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
favour	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
allocating	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
least	NOUN	O
one	NOUN	O
additional	NOUN	O
non-permanent	NOUN	O
seat	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Group	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
an	DET	O
enlarged	NOUN	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

At	ADP	O
the	DET	O
end	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
2016	NUM	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
second	NOUN	O
term	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
office	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
current	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
highly	NOUN	O
respected	NOUN	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Mr.	NOUN	O
Ban	NOUN	I-PER
Ki-moon	NOUN	I-PER
,	.	O
will	VERB	O
come	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
end	NOUN	O
.	.	O

My	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
greatly	NOUN	O
values	NOUN	O
his	PRON	O
outstanding	NOUN	O
leadership	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
commitment	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
expects	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
,	.	O
when	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
time	NOUN	O
comes	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
States	NOUN	O
Members	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
able	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
elect	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
worthy	NOUN	O
successor	NOUN	O
.	.	O

To	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
end	NOUN	O
I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
recall	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
relevant	NOUN	O
General	NOUN	I-ORG
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
resolution	NOUN	O
,	.	O
which	DET	O
states	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
,	.	O

"	.	O
[i]n	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
course	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
identification	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
appointment	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
best	NOUN	O
candidate	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
post	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
,	.	O
due	NOUN	O
regard	NOUN	O
shall	NOUN	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
given	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
regional	NOUN	O
rotation	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
shall	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
be	NOUN	O
given	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
gender	NOUN	O
equality	NOUN	O
"	.	O

(resolution	NOUN	O
51/241	NOUN	O
,	.	O
annex	NOUN	O
,	.	O
para	NOUN	O
.	.	O

59)	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bulgaria	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
convinced	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
time	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
finally	NOUN	O
come	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
East	NOUN	O
European	NOUN	I-MISC
regional	NOUN	O
group	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
represented	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
helm	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O
