I	NOUN	O
reiterate	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
he	PRON	O
strives	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
realize	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
purposes	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
principles	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Charter	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
welcome	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
choice	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
"	.	O
The	DET	O
post-2015	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
agenda:	NOUN	O
setting	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
stage	NOUN	O
"	.	O
as	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
main	NOUN	O
theme	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
session	NOUN	O
,	.	O
considering	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
high	NOUN	O
priority	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
peoples	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
accord	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
achievement	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
development	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
dimensions	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Allow	NOUN	O
me	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
deviate	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
customary	NOUN	O
practice	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
debate	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
General	NOUN	I-ORG
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
by	ADP	O
conveying	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
a	DET	O
message	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
comes	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
only	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
President	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Mr.	NOUN	O
Adly	NOUN	I-PER
Mansour	NOUN	I-PER
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
from	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
people	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
my	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
—	.	O
the	DET	O
Egyptians	NOUN	I-MISC
who	NOUN	O
laid	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
foundations	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
human	NOUN	O
civilization	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
have	NOUN	O
recently	NOUN	O
inspired	NOUN	O
peoples	NOUN	O
around	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
holds	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
unique	NOUN	O
position	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
history	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
humankind	NOUN	O
,	.	O
past	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
present	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Its	NOUN	O
status	NOUN	O
,	.	O
role	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
in	ADP	O
uence	NOUN	O
derive	NOUN	O
essentially	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
culture	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
civilization	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
would	VERB	O
have	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
historical	NOUN	O
inconsistency	NOUN	O
had	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
will	VERB	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Egyptians	NOUN	I-MISC
remained	NOUN	O
shackled	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
dawn	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
century	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
had	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
youth	NOUN	O
remained	NOUN	O
deprived	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
right	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
design	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
own	NOUN	O
destiny	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
future	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
was	VERB	O
therefore	NOUN	O
natural	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
streets	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
25	NUM	O
January	NOUN	O
2011	NUM	O
to	NOUN	O
declare	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
determination	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
build	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
democratic	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
modern	NOUN	O
State	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
which	DET	O
their	PRON	O
children	NOUN	O
could	VERB	O
enjoy	NOUN	O
freedom	NOUN	O
,	.	O
dignity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
social	NOUN	O
justice	NOUN	O
.	.	O

This	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
that	NOUN	O
millions	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
my	PRON	O
countrymen	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
women	NOUN	O
chose	NOUN	O
then	NOUN	O
—	.	O
the	DET	O
same	NOUN	O
Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
they	NOUN	O
yearned	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
30	NUM	O
June	NOUN	O
2013	NUM	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
doing	NOUN	O
so	NOUN	O
,	.	O
they	NOUN	O
showed	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
will	VERB	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
people	NOUN	O
cannot	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
broken	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
that	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
can	NOUN	O
grant	NOUN	O
authority	NOUN	O
,	.	O
just	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
can	NOUN	O
remove	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
from	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
hands	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
those	NOUN	O
who	NOUN	O
abuse	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Egyptians	NOUN	I-MISC
have	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
ambitious	NOUN	O
vision	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
future	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
achieved	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
working	NOUN	O
systematically	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
reasonable	NOUN	O
time	NOUN	O
frame	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Its	NOUN	O
success	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
based	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
a	DET	O
society	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
open	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
peaceful	NOUN	O
political	NOUN	O
currents	NOUN	O
,	.	O
that	NOUN	O
pluralistically	NOUN	O
embraces	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
diversity	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
￼members	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
that	NOUN	O
inclusively	NOUN	O
ensures	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
equal	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
duties	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
citizens	NOUN	O
through	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
rule	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
law	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
equality	NOUN	O
before	NOUN	O
justice	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
principles	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
practices	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
vision	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
consistent	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
fundamental	NOUN	O
rules	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
govern	NOUN	O
democratic	NOUN	O
practices	NOUN	O
throughout	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
,	.	O
in	ADP	O
particular	NOUN	O
respect	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
peaceful	NOUN	O
dialogue	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
rejection	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
violence	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
rule	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
law	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
respect	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Our	NOUN	O
conviction	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
Egyptians	NOUN	I-MISC
have	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
right	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
fulfil	NOUN	O
such	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
vision	NOUN	O
underpins	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
road	NOUN	O
map	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
has	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
implementing	NOUN	O
since	NOUN	O
3	NUM	O
July	NOUN	O
.	.	O

That	NOUN	O
road	NOUN	O
map	NOUN	O
includes	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
national	NOUN	O
agenda	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
build	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
institutions	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
democratic	NOUN	O
State	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
specific	NOUN	O
time	NOUN	O
frame	NOUN	O
.	.	O

All	NOUN	O
Egyptians	NOUN	I-MISC
are	VERB	O
invited	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
participate	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
phases	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
political	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
long	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
they	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
committed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
renouncing	NOUN	O
violence	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
incitement	NOUN	O
thereto	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Work	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
under	ADP	O
way	NOUN	O
,	.	O
in	ADP	O
line	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
road	NOUN	O
map	NOUN	O
,	.	O
on	ADP	O
several	NOUN	O
tracks	NOUN	O
.	.	O

To	NOUN	O
date	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
has	NOUN	O
succeeded	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
establishing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
principles	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
justice	NOUN	O
,	.	O
freedom	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
democracy	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
bases	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
governance	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Work	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
under	ADP	O
way	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
constitution	NOUN	O
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
followed	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
parliamentary	NOUN	O
elections	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
presidential	NOUN	O
elections	NOUN	O
,	.	O
bringing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
transitional	NOUN	O
phase	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
end	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
next	NOUN	O
spring	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
determined	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
fully	NOUN	O
implement	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
road	NOUN	O
map	NOUN	O
.	.	O

This	NOUN	O
requires	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
to	NOUN	O
give	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
utmost	NOUN	O
priority	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
preserving	NOUN	O
security	NOUN	O
,	.	O
enforcing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
law	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
countering	NOUN	O
any	NOUN	O
attempts	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
intimidate	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
humiliate	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
or	CONJ	O
hinder	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Some	DET	O
parts	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
were	NOUN	O
recently	NOUN	O
hit	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
desperate	NOUN	O
terrorist	NOUN	O
attacks	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Among	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
victims	NOUN	O
were	NOUN	O
Egyptians	NOUN	I-MISC
from	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
walks	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
life	NOUN	O
—	.	O
men	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
women	NOUN	O
,	.	O
young	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
old	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Muslims	NOUN	I-MISC
and	CONJ	O
non-Muslims	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

Those	NOUN	O
hideous	NOUN	O
acts	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
sought	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
undermine	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
democratic	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
destroy	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
economy	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
emphasize	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
reiterate	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
strongest	NOUN	O
terms	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
full	NOUN	O
confidence	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
brave	NOUN	O
Egyptian	NOUN	I-MISC
people	NOUN	O
,	.	O
who	NOUN	O
succeeded	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
imposing	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
,	.	O
can	NOUN	O
eradicate	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
within	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
framework	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
rule	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
law	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
trust	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
stand	NOUN	O
firmly	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Egyptian	NOUN	I-MISC
people	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
fight	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
who	NOUN	O
commit	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
advocate	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
violence	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
will	VERB	O
accept	NOUN	O
no	DET	O
attempt	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
justify	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
tolerate	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
opportunity	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
convey	NOUN	O
my	PRON	O
deep	NOUN	O
condolences	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Government	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
people	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Kenya	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
loss	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
innocent	NOUN	O
lives	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
result	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
latest	NOUN	O
terrorist	NOUN	O
attack	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
message	NOUN	O
I	NOUN	O
am	VERB	O
carrying	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
Egyptians	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
particularly	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
youth	NOUN	O
,	.	O
who	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
joining	NOUN	O
me	NOUN	O
here	NOUN	O
today	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
representing	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
ancient	NOUN	O
country	NOUN	O
,	.	O
would	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
complete	NOUN	O
without	NOUN	O
mentioning	NOUN	O
Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
aspirations	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
enjoy	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
democratic	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
relations	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
stronger	NOUN	O
ties	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
between	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
rest	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Those	NOUN	O
relations	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
based	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
principles	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
independence	NOUN	O
,	.	O
mutual	NOUN	O
respect	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
non-interference	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
internal	NOUN	O
affairs	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
other	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
on	ADP	O
a	DET	O
foreign	NOUN	O
policy	NOUN	O
founded	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
equality	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
a	DET	O
constructive	NOUN	O
,	.	O
civilized	NOUN	O
vision	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
future	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
foreign	NOUN	O
policy	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
now	ADV	O
a	DET	O
reflection	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
will	VERB	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
formulated	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
line	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
national	NOUN	O
interests	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
security	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
no	DET	O
regard	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
any	NOUN	O
other	NOUN	O
consideration	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
fully	NOUN	O
recognize	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
national	NOUN	O
security	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
linked	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
security	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
concerns	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
Arab	NOUN	I-MISC
nation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Given	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
geographical	NOUN	O
location	NOUN	O
,	.	O
history	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
identity	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
committed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
continuing	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
defend	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
interests	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
African	NOUN	I-MISC
continent	NOUN	O
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
address	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
issues	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
importance	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Islamic	NOUN	I-MISC
world	NOUN	O
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
spread	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Islamic	NOUN	I-MISC
values	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
moderation	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
tolerance	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
promote	NOUN	O
dialogue	NOUN	O
among	NOUN	O
divine	NOUN	O
religions	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
also	ADV	O
remains	NOUN	O
committed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
tackling	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
challenges	NOUN	O
facing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
South	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
a	DET	O
time	NOUN	O
when	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
witnessing	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
imbalance	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
power	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
now	ADV	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
briefly	NOUN	O
highlight	NOUN	O
Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
position	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
several	NOUN	O
issues	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
high	NOUN	O
priority	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
foreign	NOUN	O
policy	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
Syria	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
the	DET	O
tragedy	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
now	ADV	O
extended	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
resort	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
chemical	NOUN	O
weapons	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
strongly	NOUN	O
condemn	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
use	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
support	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
agreement	NOUN	O
reached	NOUN	O
between	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Russian	NOUN	I-LOC
Federation	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-LOC
States	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
well	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
resolution	NOUN	O
2118	NUM	O
(2013)	NOUN	O
.	.	O

While	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
humanitarian	NOUN	O
crisis	NOUN	O
resulting	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
fighting	NOUN	O
continues	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
intensify	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
Syrian	NOUN	I-MISC
State	NOUN	O
itself	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
verge	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
disintegration	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
imperative	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
reach	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
political	NOUN	O
solution	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
soon	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
possible	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
establish	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
freedom	NOUN	O
,	.	O
dignity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
democracy	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
which	DET	O
the	DET	O
people	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Syria	NOUN	I-LOC
aspire	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
preserve	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
unity	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
State	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
hope	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
achieved	NOUN	O
through	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
holding	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
"	.	O
Geneva	NOUN	I-LOC
II	NOUN	O
"	.	O
conference	NOUN	O
,	.	O
so	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
transitional	NOUN	O
authority	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
put	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
place	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
end	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
civil	NOUN	O
war	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
foreign	NOUN	O
interventions	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
long	NOUN	O
warned	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Palestinian	NOUN	I-MISC
question	NOUN	O
remains	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
main	NOUN	O
source	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
tension	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
region	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Palestine	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
still	ADV	O
suffering	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
effects	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
ongoing	NOUN	O
Israeli	NOUN	I-MISC
occupation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Arab	NOUN	I-MISC
territories	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
intensification	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
settlement	NOUN	O
activities	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
hope	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
achieving	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
two-State	NOUN	O
solution	NOUN	O
was	VERB	O
until	NOUN	O
recently	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
verge	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
fading	NOUN	O
away	NOUN	O
irrevocably	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Given	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
bleak	NOUN	O
scenario	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
welcome	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
appreciate	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
recent	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-LOC
States	NOUN	I-LOC
to	NOUN	O
advance	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
resumption	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Israeli-Palestinian	NOUN	I-MISC
negotiations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
￼commitment	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
both	NOUN	O
sides	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
engaging	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
process	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
time-bound	NOUN	O
negotiations	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
significant	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
should	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
ongoing	NOUN	O
negotiations	NOUN	O
so	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
they	NOUN	O
may	NOUN	O
lead	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
final	NOUN	O
settlement	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Palestinian	NOUN	I-MISC
question	NOUN	O
,	.	O
which	DET	O
has	NOUN	O
continued	NOUN	O
since	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
past	NOUN	O
century	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
right	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Palestinian	NOUN	I-MISC
people	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
self-determination	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
establishment	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
an	DET	O
independent	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
sovereign	NOUN	O
State	NOUN	O
,	.	O
with	ADP	O
East	NOUN	I-LOC
Jerusalem	NOUN	I-LOC
as	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
capital	NOUN	O
,	.	O
on	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
territories	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
West	NOUN	I-LOC
Bank	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
Gaza	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
in	ADP	O
accordance	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Arab	NOUN	I-MISC
Peace	NOUN	I-MISC
Initiative	NOUN	I-MISC
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
relevant	NOUN	O
terms	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
reference	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
reiterate	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
needs	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Gaza	NOUN	I-LOC
population	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
met	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
failure	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
do	NOUN	O
so	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
become	NOUN	O
politically	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
morally	NOUN	O
unacceptable	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
therefore	NOUN	O
call	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
Israel	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
shoulder	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
responsibilities	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
ensure	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Palestinians	NOUN	I-MISC
in	ADP	O
Gaza	NOUN	I-LOC
have	NOUN	O
access	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
basic	NOUN	O
supplies	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
ready	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
cooperate	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Palestinian	NOUN	I-MISC
authority	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
all	NOUN	O
concerned	NOUN	O
parties	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
agree	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
appropriate	NOUN	O
arrangements	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
guarantee	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
delivery	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
provisions	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
legal	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
transparent	NOUN	O
ways	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
will	VERB	O
agree	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
Middle	NOUN	I-LOC
East	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
emerge	NOUN	O
until	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
right	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
equal	NOUN	O
security	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
ensured	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
threats	NOUN	O
posed	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
existence	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
region	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
nuclear	NOUN	O
weapons	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
other	NOUN	O
weapons	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
mass	NOUN	O
destruction	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
eliminated	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
situation	NOUN	O
threatens	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
credibility	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
non-proliferation	NOUN	O
regime	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

For	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
reason	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
preserve	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
credibility	NOUN	O
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
introduce	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
today	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
initiative	NOUN	O
consisting	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
following	NOUN	O
steps	NOUN	O
.	.	O

First	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
invite	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Middle	NOUN	I-LOC
East	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
five	NOUN	O
permanent	NOUN	O
members	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
to	NOUN	O
deposit	NOUN	O
official	NOUN	O
letters	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-	NOUN	O
General	NOUN	O
stating	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
support	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
declaring	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Middle	NOUN	I-LOC
East	NOUN	I-LOC
a	DET	O
region	NOUN	O
free	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
nuclear	NOUN	O
,	.	O
chemical	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
biological	NOUN	O
weapons	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
mass	NOUN	O
destruction	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Secondly	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
countries	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
region	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
signed	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
ratified	NOUN	O
any	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
conventions	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
weapons	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
mass	NOUN	O
destruction	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
commit	NOUN	O
,	.	O
before	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
end	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
2013	NUM	O
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
simultaneously	NOUN	O
signing	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
ratifying	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
relevant	NOUN	O
conventions	NOUN	O
.	.	O

They	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
deposit	NOUN	O
documentation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
their	PRON	O
accession	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
conventions	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
invite	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-	NOUN	O
General	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
coordinate	NOUN	O
such	NOUN	O
steps	NOUN	O
so	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
they	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
carried	NOUN	O
out	NOUN	O
simultaneously	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
ensure	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
success	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Those	NOUN	O
actions	NOUN	O
translate	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
the	DET	O
following	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Israel	NOUN	I-LOC
must	NOUN	O
accede	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Treaty	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Non-Proliferation	NOUN	I-MISC
of	ADP	I-MISC
Nuclear	NOUN	I-MISC
Weapons	NOUN	I-MISC
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
non-nuclear	NOUN	O
State	NOUN	O
,	.	O
ratify	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Chemical	NOUN	I-MISC
Weapons	NOUN	I-MISC
Convention	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
sign	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
ratify	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Biological	NOUN	I-MISC
Weapons	NOUN	I-MISC
Convention	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

Syria	NOUN	I-LOC
must	NOUN	O
ratify	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Biological	NOUN	I-MISC
Weapons	NOUN	I-MISC
Convention	NOUN	I-MISC
and	CONJ	O
take	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
remaining	NOUN	O
steps	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
has	NOUN	O
pledged	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
relation	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Chemical	NOUN	I-MISC
Weapons	NOUN	I-MISC
Convention	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
must	NOUN	O
ratify	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Biological	NOUN	I-MISC
Weapons	NOUN	I-MISC
Convention	NOUN	I-MISC
and	CONJ	O
sign	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
ratify	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Chemical	NOUN	I-MISC
Weapons	NOUN	I-MISC
Convention	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
provided	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Middle	NOUN	I-LOC
East	NOUN	I-LOC
complete	NOUN	O
measures	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
accession	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
conventions	NOUN	O
prohibiting	NOUN	O
weapons	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
mass	NOUN	O
destruction	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
related	NOUN	O
arrangements	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
treaties	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Thirdly	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
pursue	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
ensure	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
delayed	NOUN	O
2012	NUM	O
conference	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
establish	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
Middle	NOUN	I-LOC
East	NOUN	I-LOC
zone	NOUN	O
free	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
weapons	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
mass	NOUN	O
destruction	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
convened	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
soon	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
possible	NOUN	O
,	.	O
preferably	NOUN	O
before	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
end	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
2013	NUM	O
and	CONJ	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
spring	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
2014	NUM	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
latest	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
roots	NOUN	O
go	NOUN	O
deep	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
proud	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
many	NOUN	O
positive	NOUN	O
changes	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
has	NOUN	O
witnessed	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
strides	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
continent	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
taken	NOUN	O
towards	NOUN	O
democracy	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
development	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Yet	NOUN	O
Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
remains	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
need	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
concerted	NOUN	O
national	NOUN	O
,	.	O
regional	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
international	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
enable	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
continent	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
resolve	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
conflicts	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
challenges	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Accordingly	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
soon	NOUN	O
establish	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
Egyptian	NOUN	I-MISC
agency	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
partnership	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Most	DET	O
of	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
future	NOUN	O
resources	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
directed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
African	NOUN	I-MISC
countries	NOUN	O
so	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
they	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
benefit	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
Egyptian	NOUN	I-MISC
technical	NOUN	O
expertise	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
assets	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
cannot	NOUN	O
talk	NOUN	O
about	NOUN	O
democracy	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
current	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
relations	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
rule	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
law	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
level	NOUN	O
unless	NOUN	O
comprehensive	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
substantial	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
takes	NOUN	O
place	NOUN	O
,	.	O
so	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Organization	NOUN	I-ORG
is	VERB	O
better	NOUN	O
able	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
respond	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
challenges	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
meet	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
aspirations	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
peoples	NOUN	O
worldwide	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
only	NOUN	O
logical	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
sound	NOUN	O
way	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
desired	NOUN	O
outcome	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
reform	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
expansion	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
therefore	NOUN	O
renews	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
call	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
end	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
monopoly	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
permanent	NOUN	O
members	NOUN	O
over	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
decision-making	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
rectification	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
historical	NOUN	O
injustice	NOUN	O
inflicted	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

The	DET	O
continent	NOUN	O
does	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
permanent	NOUN	O
seat	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
is	VERB	O
poorly	NOUN	O
represented	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
category	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
non-permanent	NOUN	O
members	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
renounce	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
demands	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
obtain	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
permanent	NOUN	O
membership	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
deserves	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
specified	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Ezulwini	NOUN	I-MISC
Consensus	NOUN	I-MISC
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
Sirte	NOUN	I-MISC
Declaration	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
conclusion	NOUN	O
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
highlight	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
priority	NOUN	O
issues	NOUN	O
within	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
system	NOUN	O
.	.	O

They	NOUN	O
include	NOUN	O
strengthening	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
framework	NOUN	O
,	.	O
addressing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
absence	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
democracy	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
international	NOUN	O
relations	NOUN	O
,	.	O
accelerating	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
achievement	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
￼the	NOUN	O
Millennium	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
Goals	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
realizing	NOUN	O
nuclear	NOUN	O
disarmament	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
fighting	NOUN	O
corruption	NOUN	O
,	.	O
including	NOUN	O
recovering	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
assets	NOUN	O
stolen	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
key	NOUN	O
members	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
regimes	NOUN	O
recently	NOUN	O
brought	NOUN	O
down	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
peoples	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
reiterate	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
determined	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
continue	NOUN	O
empowering	NOUN	O
women	NOUN	O
nationally	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
internationally	NOUN	O
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
protecting	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
allowing	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
youth	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
contribute	NOUN	O
effectively	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
elaboration	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
vision	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
for	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
future	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
opportunity	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
welcome	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
appointment	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
few	NOUN	O
months	NOUN	O
ago	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
Special	ADJ	O
Envoy	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
Youth	NOUN	O
who	NOUN	O
comes	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Arab	NOUN	I-MISC
world	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
exert	NOUN	O
concerted	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
level	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
combat	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
strengthen	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
capacity	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
to	NOUN	O
coordinate	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
address	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
root	NOUN	O
causes	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
conclusion	NOUN	O
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
truly	NOUN	O
hope	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
message	NOUN	O
I	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
delivered	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
behalf	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
people	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
President	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Egypt	NOUN	I-LOC
has	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
received	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
today	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
hope	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
aspirations	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
identified	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
realized	NOUN	O
so	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
may	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
progress	NOUN	O
,	.	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
development	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
that	NOUN	O
next	NOUN	O
year	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
may	NOUN	O
reap	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
fruits	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
labour	NOUN	O
.	.	O
