My	PRON	O
delegation	NOUN	O
assures	NOUN	O
you	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
full	NOUN	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
address	NOUN	O
issues	NOUN	O
identified	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
annual	NOUN	O
report	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
(A/62/1)	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
as	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
responsibly	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
creatively	NOUN	O
move	NOUN	O
forward	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
pending	NOUN	O
reforms	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Organization	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

At	ADP	O
the	DET	O
outset	NOUN	O
I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
express	NOUN	O
India	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
deep	NOUN	O
gratitude	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
Member	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
recent	NOUN	O
unanimous	NOUN	O
adoption	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
General	NOUN	I-ORG
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
of	ADP	O
resolution	NOUN	O
61/271	NOUN	O
,	.	O
deciding	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
annually	NOUN	O
observe	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
International	NOUN	I-MISC
Day	NOUN	I-MISC
of	ADP	I-MISC
Non-Violence	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
on	ADP	O
2	NUM	O
October	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
anniversary	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
birth	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Mahatma	NOUN	I-PER
Gandhi	NOUN	I-PER
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
look	NOUN	O
forward	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
participation	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
Member	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
informal	NOUN	O
plenary	NOUN	O
meeting	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
General	NOUN	I-ORG
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
other	NOUN	O
functions	NOUN	O
being	NOUN	O
organized	NOUN	O
tomorrow	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
to	NOUN	O
mark	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
first	NOUN	O
International	NOUN	I-MISC
Day	NOUN	I-MISC
of	ADP	I-MISC
Non-	NOUN	I-MISC
Violence	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

A	DET	O
central	NOUN	O
topic	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
year	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
debate	NOUN	O
—	.	O
responding	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
climate	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
—	.	O
is	VERB	O
both	NOUN	O
timely	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
relevant	NOUN	O
.	.	O

India	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
views	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
it	PRON	O
were	NOUN	O
recently	NOUN	O
set	NOUN	O
forth	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
high-level	NOUN	O
event	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
climate	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
,	.	O
which	DET	O
took	NOUN	O
place	NOUN	O
here	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
24	NUM	O
September	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
impact	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
climate	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
environmental	NOUN	O
degradation	NOUN	O
falls	NOUN	O
disproportionately	NOUN	O
upon	NOUN	O
developing	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Developing	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
the	DET	O
most	DET	O
vulnerable	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
also	ADV	O
lack	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
means	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
tackle	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
.	.	O

Measures	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
address	NOUN	O
climate	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
based	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
mitigation	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
adaptation	NOUN	O
strategies	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
fair	NOUN	O
burden-sharing	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
measures	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
realize	NOUN	O
sustainable	NOUN	O
patterns	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
consumption	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
production	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
process	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
burden-sharing	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
take	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
account	NOUN	O
where	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
primary	NOUN	O
responsibility	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
present	NOUN	O
state	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
greenhouse	NOUN	O
gas	NOUN	O
concentration	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
atmosphere	NOUN	O
rests	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
not	NOUN	O
foreclose	NOUN	O
rapid	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
sustained	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
developing	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
,	.	O
which	DET	O
,	.	O
in	ADP	O
any	NOUN	O
case	NOUN	O
,	.	O
is	VERB	O
an	DET	O
imperative	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
adaptation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Technology	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
other	NOUN	O
key	NOUN	O
area	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
needs	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
addressed	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
important	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
critical	NOUN	O
clean	NOUN	O
technologies	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
made	NOUN	O
available	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
affordable	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
developing	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
intellectual	NOUN	O
property	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
regime	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
balance	NOUN	O
rewards	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
innovators	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
common	NOUN	O
good	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
humankind	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Concerted	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
action	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
address	NOUN	O
climate	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
,	.	O
in	ADP	O
accordance	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
principle	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
common	NOUN	O
but	CONJ	O
differentiated	NOUN	O
responsibilities	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
respective	NOUN	O
capabilities	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
well	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
national	NOUN	O
circumstances	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
social	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
economic	NOUN	O
conditions	NOUN	O
,	.	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
need	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
hour	NOUN	O
.	.	O

India	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
for	NOUN	O
which	DET	O
energy	NOUN	O
security	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
national	NOUN	O
imperative	NOUN	O
,	.	O
has	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
very	ADV	O
small	NOUN	O
individual	NOUN	O
carbon	NOUN	O
footprint	NOUN	O
,	.	O
with	ADP	O
per	NOUN	O
capita	NOUN	O
carbon	NOUN	O
dioxide	NOUN	O
emissions	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
just	NOUN	O
about	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
quarter	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
average	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Even	NOUN	O
so	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
determined	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
pursue	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
growth	NOUN	O
,	.	O
our	NOUN	O
per	NOUN	O
capita	NOUN	O
greenhouse	NOUN	O
gas	NOUN	O
emissions	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
increase	NOUN	O
beyond	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
industrial	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Poverty	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
underdevelopment	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
amongst	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
central	NOUN	O
challenges	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
times	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
overarching	NOUN	O
requirement	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
for	NOUN	O
sustained	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
growth	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
eradicate	NOUN	O
poverty	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
developing	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Growth	NOUN	O
alone	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
enough	NOUN	O
if	CONJ	O
it	PRON	O
does	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
produce	NOUN	O
benefits	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
sufficiently	NOUN	O
dispersed	NOUN	O
,	.	O
not	NOUN	O
only	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
terms	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
increased	NOUN	O
income	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
employment	NOUN	O
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
also	ADV	O
for	NOUN	O
improved	NOUN	O
health	NOUN	O
,	.	O
nutrition	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
education	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
affirm	NOUN	O
India	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
resolve	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
internationally	NOUN	O
agreed	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
goals	NOUN	O
,	.	O
including	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Millennium	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
Goals	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
apparent	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
progress	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
achievement	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
internationally	NOUN	O
agreed	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
goals	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
tardy	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
,	.	O
through	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
system	NOUN	O
,	.	O
must	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
effectively	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
efforts	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
developing	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
development	NOUN	O
goals	NOUN	O
.	.	O

A	DET	O
comprehensive	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
financial	NOUN	O
architecture	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
key	NOUN	O
ingredient	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
that	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
.	.	O

That	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
include	NOUN	O
measures	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
ensure	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
greater	NOUN	O
voice	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
participation	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
developing	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Bretton	NOUN	I-LOC
Woods	NOUN	I-LOC
institutions	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
process	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
reform	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
carried	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
logical	NOUN	O
conclusion	NOUN	O
if	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
credibility	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
those	NOUN	O
institutions	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
enhanced	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
address	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
priority	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
regrettable	NOUN	O
inversion	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
global	ADJ	O
resource	NOUN	O
flows	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Today	NOUN	O
,	.	O
instead	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
urgently	NOUN	O
needed	NOUN	O
inflow	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
resources	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
developing	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
buttress	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
national	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
plans	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
confronted	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
a	DET	O
net	NOUN	O
outflow	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
them	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Official	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
assistance	NOUN	O
(ODA)	NOUN	O
showed	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
marked	NOUN	O
fall	NOUN	O
during	NOUN	O
2006	NUM	O
and	CONJ	O
remains	NOUN	O
well	NOUN	O
below	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
target	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
0	NUM	O
.	.	O
7	NUM	O
per	NOUN	O
cent	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
gross	NOUN	O
national	NOUN	O
product	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
primarily	NOUN	O
being	NOUN	O
used	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
finance	NOUN	O
debt	NOUN	O
relief	NOUN	O
.	.	O

That	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
happening	NOUN	O
after	NOUN	O
so	NOUN	O
many	NOUN	O
years	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
liberalization	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
globalization	NOUN	O
highlights	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
collective	NOUN	O
failure	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Perhaps	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
should	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
considering	NOUN	O
mechanisms	NOUN	O
,	.	O
such	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
debt	NOUN	O
commission	NOUN	O
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
redress	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
problem	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
developing	NOUN	O
country	NOUN	O
debt	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
least	NOUN	O
developed	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
,	.	O
which	DET	O
are	VERB	O
particularly	NOUN	O
hard	NOUN	O
hit	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
rising	NOUN	O
energy	NOUN	O
costs	NOUN	O
,	.	O
find	NOUN	O
themselves	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
an	DET	O
even	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
difficult	NOUN	O
situation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Enhanced	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
predictable	NOUN	O
resource	NOUN	O
flow	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
developing	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
remains	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
key	NOUN	O
objective	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
global	ADJ	O
partnership	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
.	.	O

India	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
do	NOUN	O
what	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
can	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
help	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
capacity-building	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
other	NOUN	O
developing	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
assist	NOUN	O
them	NOUN	O
through	NOUN	O
ODA	NOUN	O
within	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
limits	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
capacity	NOUN	O
.	.	O

By	ADP	O
the	DET	O
end	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
year	NOUN	O
,	.	O
imports	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
least	NOUN	O
developed	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
India	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
face	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
zero-tariff	NOUN	O
regime	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Early	ADV	O
and	CONJ	O
substantive	NOUN	O
progress	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Doha	NOUN	I-LOC
Round	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
trade	NOUN	O
negotiations	NOUN	O
,	.	O
based	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
primacy	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
development	NOUN	O
dimension	NOUN	O
,	.	O
is	VERB	O
another	NOUN	O
imperative	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
return	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
negotiating	NOUN	O
table	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
a	DET	O
redoubled	NOUN	O
sense	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
urgency	NOUN	O
,	.	O
while	CONJ	O
recognizing	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
adherence	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
existing	NOUN	O
mandate	NOUN	O
remains	NOUN	O
critical	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Nor	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
interests	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
subsistence	NOUN	O
farmers	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
ignored	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
equated	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
those	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
other	NOUN	O
sectors	NOUN	O
.	.	O

An	DET	O
illogical	NOUN	O
linkage	NOUN	O
between	NOUN	O
agriculture	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
non-agricultural	NOUN	O
market	NOUN	O
access	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
only	NOUN	O
complicate	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
development	NOUN	O
impact	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Round	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
overarching	NOUN	O
principle	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
special	ADJ	O
and	CONJ	O
differential	NOUN	O
treatment	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
developing	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
remains	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
categorical	NOUN	O
imperative	NOUN	O
.	.	O

As	NOUN	O
part	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
India	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
commitment	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
achievement	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
member	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Human	NOUN	I-ORG
Rights	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
remain	NOUN	O
actively	NOUN	O
involved	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
developing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
institutional	NOUN	O
framework	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
that	NOUN	O
body	NOUN	O
,	.	O
including	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
universal	NOUN	O
periodic	NOUN	O
review	NOUN	O
mechanism	NOUN	O
,	.	O
based	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
effective	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
central	NOUN	O
principle	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
's	NOUN	O
methods	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
work	NOUN	O
.	.	O

India	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
work	NOUN	O
towards	NOUN	O
developing	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
normative	NOUN	O
framework	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
promotion	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
protection	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
.	.	O

India	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
honoured	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
one	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
first	NOUN	O
signatories	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
International	NOUN	I-MISC
Convention	NOUN	I-MISC
for	NOUN	I-MISC
the	DET	I-MISC
Protection	NOUN	I-MISC
of	ADP	I-MISC
All	NOUN	I-MISC
Persons	NOUN	I-MISC
from	NOUN	I-MISC
Enforced	NOUN	I-MISC
Disappearance	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

The	DET	O
effort	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
participatory	NOUN	O
democracy	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
meaningful	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
every	DET	O
Indian	NOUN	O
citizen	NOUN	O
underpins	NOUN	O
what	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
perhaps	NOUN	O
one	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
greatest	NOUN	O
social	NOUN	O
experiments	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
today	NOUN	O
,	.	O
namely	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
transfer	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
decision-making	NOUN	O
power	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
nearly	NOUN	O
one	NOUN	O
million	NOUN	O
elected	NOUN	O
women	NOUN	O
local	NOUN	O
Government	NOUN	O
representatives	NOUN	O
.	.	O

As	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
result	NOUN	O
,	.	O
women	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
merely	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
beneficiaries	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
change	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
India	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
are	VERB	O
its	NOUN	O
instruments	NOUN	O
.	.	O

As	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
largest	NOUN	O
democracy	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
was	VERB	O
also	ADV	O
natural	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
India	NOUN	I-LOC
to	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
establishment	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Democracy	NOUN	I-MISC
Fund	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
made	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
initial	NOUN	O
contribution	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
$10	NOUN	O
million	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Fund	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
remain	NOUN	O
actively	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
constructively	NOUN	O
involved	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
realizing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
objectives	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
which	DET	O
it	PRON	O
was	VERB	O
set	NOUN	O
up	NOUN	O
.	.	O

As	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
small	NOUN	O
token	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
commitment	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
laudable	NOUN	O
initiative	NOUN	O
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
privilege	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
announcing	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
further	NOUN	O
pledge	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
$10	NOUN	O
million	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Democracy	NOUN	I-MISC
Fund	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

The	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
system	NOUN	O
cannot	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
reordered	NOUN	O
meaningfully	NOUN	O
without	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
comprehensive	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

If	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
Organization	NOUN	I-ORG
is	VERB	O
to	NOUN	O
remain	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
cornerstone	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
architecture	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
century	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
cannot	NOUN	O
remain	NOUN	O
mired	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
realities	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
1940s	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Despite	NOUN	O
substantive	NOUN	O
implementation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
reform	NOUN	O
agenda	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
emerged	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
2005	NUM	O
World	NOUN	I-MISC
Summit	NOUN	I-MISC
Outcome	NOUN	O
,	.	O
such	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
inevitably	NOUN	O
remain	NOUN	O
incomplete	NOUN	O
without	NOUN	O
comprehensive	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
expansion	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
revitalization	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
General	NOUN	I-ORG
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

Elements	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
ideas	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
reform	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
have	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
discussed	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
well	NOUN	O
over	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
decade	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
numerous	NOUN	O
reports	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
interminable	NOUN	O
consultations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
now	ADV	O
time	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
intergovernmental	NOUN	O
negotiations	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
commence	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
order	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
more	NOUN	O
democratic	NOUN	O
,	.	O
representative	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
responsive	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
,	.	O
together	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
partners	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Latin	NOUN	I-LOC
America	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
Asia	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
tabled	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
resolution	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
11	NUM	O
September	NOUN	O
2007	NUM	O
,	.	O
spelling	NOUN	O
out	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
principles	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
which	DET	O
reform	NOUN	O
ought	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
based	NOUN	O
if	CONJ	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
meaningful	NOUN	O
.	.	O

These	NOUN	O
principles	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
expansion	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
both	NOUN	O
permanent	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
non-permanent	NOUN	O
categories	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
membership	NOUN	O
;	.	O
greater	NOUN	O
representation	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
developing	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
representation	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
developed	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
reflective	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
contemporary	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
realities	NOUN	O
;	.	O
and	CONJ	O
comprehensive	NOUN	O
improvement	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
working	NOUN	O
methods	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
including	NOUN	O
ensuring	NOUN	O
greater	NOUN	O
access	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
island	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
small	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
welcome	NOUN	O
recent	NOUN	O
statements	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
podium	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
President	NOUN	O
Bush	NOUN	I-PER
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-LOC
States	NOUN	I-LOC
of	ADP	O
America	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
other	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
leaders	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
need	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
reform	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
both	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
permanent	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
non-permanent	NOUN	O
categories	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
high	NOUN	O
time	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
collectively	NOUN	O
bring	NOUN	O
these	NOUN	O
ideas	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
implementation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Reform	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
would	VERB	O
also	ADV	O
be	NOUN	O
incomplete	NOUN	O
without	NOUN	O
revitalization	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
General	NOUN	I-ORG
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

The	DET	O
central	NOUN	O
goal	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
such	NOUN	O
revitalization	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
restoration	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
enhancement	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
role	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
authority	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
General	NOUN	I-ORG
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
as	NOUN	O
originally	NOUN	O
envisaged	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Charter	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

Given	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
significance	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
developmental	NOUN	O
activities	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
developing	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
,	.	O
India	NOUN	I-LOC
sees	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
corresponding	NOUN	O
need	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
reform	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
operational	NOUN	O
activities	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
favour	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
development	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Since	NOUN	O
these	NOUN	O
activities	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
aimed	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
supporting	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
work	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Member	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
follows	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
Members	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
determine	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
direction	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
shape	NOUN	O
through	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
intergovernmental	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
litmus	NOUN	O
test	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
any	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
proposal	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
whether	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
improves	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
support	NOUN	O
extended	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
efforts	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
programme	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
.	.	O

India	NOUN	I-LOC
would	VERB	O
therefore	NOUN	O
judge	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
proposals	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
their	PRON	O
impact	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
ground	NOUN	O
,	.	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
resultant	NOUN	O
improvement	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
effectiveness	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
system	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
impact	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
transaction	NOUN	O
costs	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
development	NOUN	O
system	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Steps	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
complete	NOUN	O
elimination	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
nuclear	NOUN	O
weapons	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
only	NOUN	O
made	NOUN	O
limited	NOUN	O
headway	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Despite	NOUN	O
some	DET	O
progress	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
remains	NOUN	O
far	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
achieving	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
objective	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
total	NOUN	O
elimination	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
nuclear	NOUN	O
weapons	NOUN	O
.	.	O

India	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
long-standing	NOUN	O
commitment	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
universal	NOUN	O
,	.	O
non-discriminatory	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
comprehensive	NOUN	O
nuclear	NOUN	O
disarmament	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
embodied	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
vision	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
late	NOUN	O
Prime	NOUN	O
Minister	NOUN	O
Rajiv	NOUN	O
Gandhi	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
nuclear-free	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
non-violent	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
.	.	O

This	NOUN	O
vision	NOUN	O
was	VERB	O
put	NOUN	O
forward	NOUN	O
nearly	NOUN	O
two	NOUN	O
decades	NOUN	O
ago	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
remains	NOUN	O
undiminished	NOUN	O
today	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Indeed	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
all	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
more	NOUN	O
relevant	NOUN	O
today	NOUN	O
,	.	O
given	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
fact	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
peaceful	NOUN	O
uses	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
nuclear	NOUN	O
energy	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
address	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
inexorably	NOUN	O
growing	NOUN	O
demand	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
new	ADJ	O
and	CONJ	O
non-polluting	NOUN	O
sources	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
energy	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
fuel	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
bringing	NOUN	O
proposals	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
Member	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
this	NOUN	O
Organization	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
see	NOUN	O
how	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
can	NOUN	O
refocus	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
general	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
complete	NOUN	O
disarmament	NOUN	O
,	.	O
particularly	NOUN	O
nuclear	NOUN	O
disarmament	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Disarmament	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
our	NOUN	O
agreed	NOUN	O
goal	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
it	PRON	O
subsumes	NOUN	O
arms	NOUN	O
control	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
non-proliferation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
well	NOUN	O
known	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
India	NOUN	I-LOC
has	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
impeccable	NOUN	O
record	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
preventing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
proliferation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
sensitive	NOUN	O
technologies	NOUN	O
.	.	O

That	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
in	ADP	O
keeping	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
commitment	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
being	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
responsible	NOUN	O
nuclear	NOUN	O
Power	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
needs	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
intensify	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
effort	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
address	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
very	ADV	O
real	NOUN	O
threat	NOUN	O
posed	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
link	NOUN	O
between	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
proliferation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
weapons	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
mass	NOUN	O
destruction	NOUN	O
(WMDs)	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
related	NOUN	O
materials	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
technologies	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
ability	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
non-State	NOUN	O
actors	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
acquire	NOUN	O
them	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
risk	NOUN	O
posed	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
intersection	NOUN	O
between	NOUN	O
proliferation	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
real	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
serious	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
central	NOUN	O
objective	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
ensure	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
solidarity	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
words	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
translated	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
action	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
adoption	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Global	ADJ	I-MISC
Counter-Terrorism	NOUN	I-MISC
Strategy	NOUN	I-MISC
last	NOUN	O
September	NOUN	O
was	VERB	O
a	DET	O
noteworthy	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
,	.	O
signalling	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
will	VERB	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
combat	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
menace	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
holistic	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
coordinated	NOUN	O
manner	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Welcome	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Strategy	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
,	.	O
there	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
much	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
needs	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
done	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
combat	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
menace	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
become	NOUN	O
.	.	O

India	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
convinced	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
without	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
early	ADV	O
adoption	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
comprehensive	NOUN	O
convention	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
global	ADJ	O
struggle	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
remains	NOUN	O
incomplete	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
likely	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
succeed	NOUN	O
only	NOUN	O
partially	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
ensure	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
there	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
zero	NOUN	O
tolerance	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
forms	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
conclusion	NOUN	O
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
express	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
hope	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
deliberations	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
year	NOUN	O
ahead	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
lead	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
to	NOUN	O
enlightened	NOUN	O
action	NOUN	O
.	.	O

With	ADP	O
maturity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
resolve	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
successfully	NOUN	O
overcome	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
many	NOUN	O
challenges	NOUN	O
before	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
.	.	O
