Twenty-one	NOUN	O
years	NOUN	O
ago	NOUN	O
,	.	O
on	ADP	O
a	DET	O
day	NOUN	O
like	NOUN	O
today	NOUN	O
,	.	O
a	DET	O
terrible	NOUN	O
earthquake	NOUN	O
battered	NOUN	O
my	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
remember	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
victims	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
we	PRON	O
express	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
ongoing	NOUN	O
solidarity	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
their	PRON	O
family	NOUN	O
members	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
wish	VERB	O
you	NOUN	O
every	DET	O
success	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Mexican	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
thank	NOUN	O
Mr.	NOUN	O
Jan	NOUN	I-PER
Eliasson	NOUN	I-PER
for	NOUN	O
his	PRON	O
leadership	NOUN	O
during	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
's	NOUN	O
sixtieth	NOUN	O
session	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
for	NOUN	O
his	PRON	O
contribution	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
reform	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Mexico	NOUN	I-LOC
warmly	NOUN	O
welcomes	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
people	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Montenegro	NOUN	I-LOC
to	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
Organization	NOUN	I-ORG
of	ADP	O
free	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
juridically	NOUN	O
equal	NOUN	O
nations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
welcome	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
nations	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
today	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
joined	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
free	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
democratic	NOUN	O
nations	NOUN	O
,	.	O
through	NOUN	O
genuine	NOUN	O
representation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
their	PRON	O
peoples	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
are	VERB	O
united	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
struggle	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
in	ADP	O
favour	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
.	.	O

A	DET	O
few	NOUN	O
days	NOUN	O
ago	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
commemorated	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
fifth	NOUN	O
anniversary	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
terrorist	NOUN	O
act	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
plunged	NOUN	O
many	NOUN	O
families	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
other	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
mourning	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
offer	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
sympathy	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
who	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
suffered	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
violence	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
cruelty	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Mexico	NOUN	I-LOC
strongly	NOUN	O
condemns	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
terrible	NOUN	O
evil	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
condemns	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
acts	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
aggression	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
violence	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
repudiate	NOUN	O
any	NOUN	O
action	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
undermines	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
conflicts	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
noble	NOUN	O
principles	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
purposes	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
Organization	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

Throughout	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
past	NOUN	O
six	NOUN	O
decades	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
peoples	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
have	NOUN	O
seen	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
use	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
force	NOUN	O
does	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
solve	NOUN	O
problems	NOUN	O
;	.	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
contrary	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
often	NOUN	O
aggravates	NOUN	O
them	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
development	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
the	DET	O
fruit	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
mutual	NOUN	O
respect	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
which	DET	O
such	NOUN	O
respect	NOUN	O
gives	NOUN	O
rise	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
peoples	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
are	VERB	O
well	NOUN	O
aware	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
deterioration	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
security	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
result	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
insufficient	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
dialogue	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
know	NOUN	O
,	.	O
too	NOUN	O
,	.	O
that	NOUN	O
many	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
setbacks	NOUN	O
—	.	O
such	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
field	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
disarmament	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
those	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
form	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
aggression	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
other	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
environment	NOUN	O
—	.	O
are	VERB	O
caused	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
a	DET	O
lack	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
respect	NOUN	O
among	NOUN	O
nations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

These	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
very	ADV	O
challenging	NOUN	O
times	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Our	NOUN	O
peoples	NOUN	O
today	NOUN	O
face	NOUN	O
such	NOUN	O
situations	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
persistence	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
long-standing	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
conflicts	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
emergence	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
new	ADJ	O
tensions	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
threats	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
.	.	O

They	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
must	NOUN	O
tackle	NOUN	O
problems	NOUN	O
ranging	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
poverty	NOUN	O
,	.	O
disease	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
illiteracy	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
inequality	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
opportunity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
urgent	NOUN	O
need	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
inclusive	NOUN	O
dialogue	NOUN	O
aimed	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
increasing	NOUN	O
mutual	NOUN	O
understanding	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Humanity	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
desperately	NOUN	O
seeking	NOUN	O
respect	NOUN	O
,	.	O
understanding	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
among	NOUN	O
nations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

There	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
no	DET	O
peace	NOUN	O
without	NOUN	O
respect	NOUN	O
among	NOUN	O
nations	NOUN	O
,	.	O
no	DET	O
development	NOUN	O
without	NOUN	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
among	NOUN	O
them	NOUN	O
.	.	O

These	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
challenging	NOUN	O
times	NOUN	O
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
also	ADV	O
times	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
hope	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
believe	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
hope	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
goodness	NOUN	O
alone	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
give	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
the	DET	O
necessary	NOUN	O
strength	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
drive	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
goals	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
fulfil	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
dreams	NOUN	O
.	.	O

This	NOUN	O
house	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
foremost	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
forums	NOUN	O
established	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
mankind	NOUN	O
,	.	O
is	VERB	O
built	NOUN	O
upon	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
principles	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
values	NOUN	O
shared	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
peoples	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
product	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
their	PRON	O
common	NOUN	O
essence	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Here	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
summon	NOUN	O
up	NOUN	O
what	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
best	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
us	PRON	O
.	.	O

Here	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
show	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
what	NOUN	O
unites	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
force	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
animosity	NOUN	O
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
hope	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
solidarity	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Here	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
united	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
ideals	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
our	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
to	NOUN	O
preserve	NOUN	O
future	NOUN	O
generations	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
scourge	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
war	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Here	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
work	NOUN	O
together	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
foster	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
dignity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
worth	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
human	NOUN	O
person	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
,	.	O
shoulder	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
shoulder	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
promote	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
economic	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
social	NOUN	O
progress	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
peoples	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Here	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
make	NOUN	O
firm	NOUN	O
commitments	NOUN	O
,	.	O
such	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Millennium	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
Goals	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
we	PRON	O
work	NOUN	O
enthusiastically	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
order	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
go	NOUN	O
forward	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
achieve	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
goals	NOUN	O
.	.	O

This	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
no	DET	O
small	NOUN	O
task	NOUN	O
.	.	O

There	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
many	NOUN	O
challenges	NOUN	O
,	.	O
because	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
goals	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
ambitious	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
magnitude	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
challenges	NOUN	O
cannot	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
should	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
overshadow	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
scope	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
common	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
.	.	O

Mexico	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
message	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
one	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
hope	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
of	ADP	O
faith	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
what	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
capable	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
achieving	NOUN	O
together	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
message	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
confidence	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
work	NOUN	O
done	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

This	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
message	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Mexico	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
whose	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
conquered	NOUN	O
democracy	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
2000	NUM	O
and	CONJ	O
in	ADP	O
so	NOUN	O
doing	NOUN	O
inspired	NOUN	O
hope	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
future	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
prosperity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
justice	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Mexico	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
country	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
well-established	NOUN	O
institutions	NOUN	O
which	DET	O
guide	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
lead	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
nation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

My	PRON	O
people	NOUN	O
live	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
work	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
peace	NOUN	O
,	.	O
enjoy	NOUN	O
stability	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
have	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
eyes	NOUN	O
set	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
new	ADJ	O
horizons	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
well-being	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
justice	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
democratic	NOUN	O
Mexico	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
firmly	NOUN	O
committed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
protecting	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
very	ADV	O
proud	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
founding	NOUN	O
member	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Human	NOUN	I-ORG
Rights	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
occupy	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
first	NOUN	O
presidency	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
continue	NOUN	O
working	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
enthusiasm	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
determination	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
order	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
an	DET	O
organ	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
responds	NOUN	O
effectively	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
challenges	NOUN	O
posed	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Mexico	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
country	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
cherishes	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
roots	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
traditions	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
treasures	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
heritage	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
land	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
many	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
diverse	NOUN	O
cultures	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
prize	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
legacy	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
indigenous	NOUN	O
peoples	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
are	VERB	O
proud	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
indigenous	NOUN	O
present	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
actively	NOUN	O
engaged	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
recognition	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
promotion	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
rights	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
indigenous	NOUN	O
peoples	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
level	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
May	NOUN	O
,	.	O
a	DET	O
Rarámuri	NOUN	I-MISC
woman	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
state	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Chihuahua	NOUN	I-LOC
named	NOUN	O
Isabel	NOUN	I-PER
said	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
me	NOUN	O
,	.	O
"	.	O
Mr.	NOUN	O
President	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
certainly	NOUN	O
true	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
beings	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
different	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
one	NOUN	O
another	NOUN	O
,	.	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
see	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
through	NOUN	O
different	NOUN	O
lenses	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
do	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
share	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
same	NOUN	O
beliefs	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Nevertheless	NOUN	O
,	.	O
all	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
beings	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
equal	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
dignity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
stature	NOUN	O
"	.	O
.	.	O

She	NOUN	O
asked	NOUN	O
me	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
pass	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
that	NOUN	O
message	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
promised	NOUN	O
her	PRON	O
that	NOUN	O
I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
do	NOUN	O
so	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
today	NOUN	O
I	NOUN	O
am	VERB	O
keeping	NOUN	O
my	PRON	O
word	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
bringing	NOUN	O
Isabel	NOUN	I-PER
's	NOUN	O
voice	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
those	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
other	NOUN	O
indigenous	NOUN	O
sisters	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
brothers	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
forum	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Isabel	NOUN	I-PER
's	NOUN	O
voice	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
voice	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
Mexican	NOUN	I-MISC
women	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
men	NOUN	O
who	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
fighting	NOUN	O
discrimination	NOUN	O
.	.	O

On	ADP	O
behalf	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
indigenous	NOUN	O
peoples	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Mexico	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
rest	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
call	NOUN	O
upon	NOUN	O
each	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
every	DET	O
State	NOUN	O
Member	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
Organization	NOUN	I-ORG
to	NOUN	O
adopt	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
draft	NOUN	O
Declaration	NOUN	I-MISC
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
endow	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
means	NOUN	O
necessary	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
to	NOUN	O
promote	NOUN	O
respect	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
rights	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
indigenous	NOUN	O
peoples	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Five	NOUN	O
years	NOUN	O
ago	NOUN	O
,	.	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
spirit	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
great	NOUN	O
enthusiasm	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
quest	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
more	NOUN	O
just	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
human-centred	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
millions	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
people	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
disabilities	NOUN	O
,	.	O
my	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Mexico	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
presented	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
General	NOUN	I-ORG
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
with	ADP	O
a	DET	O
proposal	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
draft	NOUN	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
convention	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
protection	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
promotion	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
rights	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
dignity	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
persons	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
disabilities	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
now	ADV	O
have	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
draft	NOUN	O
text	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
prompt	NOUN	O
Governments	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
society	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
pay	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
attention	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
disabilities	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
urge	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
nations	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
sign	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
ratify	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
legal	NOUN	O
instrument	NOUN	O
—	.	O
proposed	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
my	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
already	ADV	O
endorsed	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
many	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
nations	NOUN	O
represented	NOUN	O
here	NOUN	O
—	.	O
with	ADP	O
a	DET	O
view	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
creating	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
greater	NOUN	O
justice	NOUN	O
,	.	O
humanity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
dignity	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Mexico	NOUN	I-LOC
believes	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
—	.	O
in	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
present	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
in	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
future	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
always	NOUN	O
worked	NOUN	O
here	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
constructive	NOUN	O
manner	NOUN	O
,	.	O
promoting	NOUN	O
consensus	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
harmony	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
putting	NOUN	O
forward	NOUN	O
initiatives	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
address	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
greatest	NOUN	O
challenges	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
times	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
thank	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
pay	NOUN	O
tribute	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
heads	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
State	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Algeria	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Australia	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Canada	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Chile	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Germany	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Japan	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Kenya	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
the	DET	O
Netherlands	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
New	ADJ	I-LOC
Zealand	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Singapore	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Spain	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
Sweden	NOUN	I-LOC
for	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
support	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Mexican	NOUN	I-MISC
initiative	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
establish	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Group	NOUN	I-ORG
of	ADP	I-ORG
Friends	NOUN	I-ORG
for	NOUN	I-ORG
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Reform	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

Together	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
presented	NOUN	O
proposals	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
were	NOUN	O
taken	NOUN	O
up	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
report	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
March	NOUN	O
2005	NUM	O
(	.	O
A/59/2005	NOUN	O
)	.	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
am	VERB	O
certain	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
commitment	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
will	VERB	O
result	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
stronger	NOUN	O
Organization	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
capable	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
accomplishing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
lofty	NOUN	O
objectives	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
which	DET	O
it	PRON	O
was	VERB	O
created	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Mexico	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
convinced	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
need	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
promote	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
reform	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
that	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
guarantee	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
's	NOUN	O
representativeness	NOUN	O
,	.	O
efficacy	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
transparency	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
well	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
ensure	NOUN	O
accountability	NOUN	O
.	.	O

That	NOUN	O
objective	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
reached	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
creating	NOUN	O
new	ADJ	O
permanent	NOUN	O
seats	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
an	DET	O
Organization	NOUN	O
based	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
principle	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
juridical	NOUN	O
equality	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
States	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

The	DET	O
reform	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
should	NOUN	O
ensure	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
frequent	NOUN	O
participation	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
Member	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
activities	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
that	NOUN	O
body	NOUN	O
.	.	O

That	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
why	NOUN	O
Mexico	NOUN	I-LOC
proposes	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
increase	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
number	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
non-permanent	NOUN	O
seats	NOUN	O
,	.	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
possibility	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
immediate	NOUN	O
re-election	NOUN	O
.	.	O

As	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
last	NOUN	O
time	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
I	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
speaking	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
in	ADP	O
my	PRON	O
capacity	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
President	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Mexico	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
express	NOUN	O
my	PRON	O
gratitude	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
Member	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
support	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
initiatives	NOUN	O
over	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
past	NOUN	O
six	NOUN	O
years	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
express	NOUN	O
my	PRON	O
deep	NOUN	O
appreciation	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
Kofi	NOUN	I-PER
Annan	NOUN	I-PER
,	.	O
a	DET	O
good	NOUN	O
friend	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Mexico	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

He	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
remembered	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
his	PRON	O
efforts	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
strengthen	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
Organization	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
for	NOUN	O
his	PRON	O
passion	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
harmony	NOUN	O
among	NOUN	O
nations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
reaffirm	NOUN	O
my	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
unconditional	NOUN	O
commitment	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
objectives	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
San	NOUN	I-LOC
Francisco	NOUN	I-LOC
Charter	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
reform	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
currently	NOUN	O
under	ADP	O
way	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
common	NOUN	O
quest	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
free	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
poverty	NOUN	O
,	.	O
fear	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
despair	NOUN	O
—	.	O
a	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
mutual	NOUN	O
respect	NOUN	O
,	.	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
harmony	NOUN	O
.	.	O

From	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
rostrum	NOUN	O
I	NOUN	O
appeal	NOUN	O
,	.	O
on	ADP	O
behalf	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Mexico	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
for	NOUN	O
respect	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
peace	NOUN	O
among	NOUN	O
nations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
particular	NOUN	O
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
call	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
to	NOUN	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
promote	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
effective	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Middle	NOUN	I-LOC
East	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

There	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
no	DET	O
greater	NOUN	O
enemy	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
obstacle	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
hopelessness	NOUN	O
,	.	O
unkindness	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
lack	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
solidarity	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Let	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
build	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
future	NOUN	O
based	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
strength	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
ideals	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
values	NOUN	O
,	.	O
confident	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
can	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
great	NOUN	O
things	NOUN	O
.	.	O

