The	DET	O
leaders	NOUN	O
who	NOUN	O
gathered	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Climate	NOUN	I-MISC
Summit	NOUN	I-MISC
have	NOUN	O
taken	NOUN	O
important	NOUN	O
steps	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
mobilize	NOUN	O
action	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
ambition	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
climate	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Now	ADV	O
we	PRON	O
need	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
sure	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
positive	NOUN	O
results	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
followed	NOUN	O
through	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
expanded	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
prepare	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
agreement	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Paris	NOUN	I-LOC
next	NOUN	O
year	NOUN	O
.	.	O

When	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
meet	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
General	NOUN	I-ORG
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
next	NOUN	O
year	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
adopt	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
set	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
global	ADJ	O
goals	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
common	NOUN	O
future	NOUN	O
—	.	O
the	DET	O
sustainable	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
goals	NOUN	O
(	.	O
SDGs	NOUN	I-MISC
)	.	O
.	.	O

They	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
build	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
success	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Millennium	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
Goals	NOUN	I-MISC
(	.	O
MDGs	NOUN	I-MISC
)	.	O
.	.	O

They	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
realistic	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
ambitious	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Like	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
MDGs	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
the	DET	O
SDGs	NOUN	I-MISC
should	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
few	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
number	NOUN	O
,	.	O
concrete	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
measurable	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Meanwhile	NOUN	O
,	.	O
achieving	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
eight	NOUN	O
Millennium	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
Goals	NOUN	I-MISC
will	VERB	O
create	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
solid	NOUN	O
foundation	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
sustainable	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
.	.	O

As	NOUN	O
co-chair	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
Ban	NOUN	I-PER
Ki-moon	NOUN	I-PER
's	NOUN	O
MDG	NOUN	I-MISC
Advocacy	NOUN	I-ORG
Group	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
use	NOUN	O
every	DET	O
opportunity	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
help	NOUN	O
build	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
foundation	NOUN	O
over	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
remaining	NOUN	O
462	NUM	O
days	NOUN	O
until	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
deadline	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
accelerate	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
do	NOUN	O
so	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
need	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
enter	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
broad	NOUN	O
partnerships	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
include	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
private	NOUN	O
sector	NOUN	O
,	.	O
civil	NOUN	O
society	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
Governments	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
need	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
use	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
best	NOUN	O
possible	NOUN	O
innovative	NOUN	O
solutions	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
technologies	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Governments	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
national	NOUN	O
political	NOUN	O
leaders	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
lead	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
ensure	NOUN	O
local	NOUN	O
ownership	NOUN	O
.	.	O

At	ADP	O
the	DET	O
same	NOUN	O
time	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
remarkable	NOUN	O
work	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
many	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
doing	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
implement	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
MDGs	NOUN	I-MISC
in	ADP	O
practice	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
frightening	NOUN	O
Ebola	NOUN	I-MISC
epidemic	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
West	NOUN	I-LOC
Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
reminds	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
fragility	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
progress	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
development	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
build	NOUN	O
health-care	NOUN	O
systems	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
courageous	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
determined	NOUN	O
individuals	NOUN	O
like	NOUN	O
Josephine	NOUN	I-PER
Finda	NOUN	I-PER
Sellu	NOUN	I-PER
.	.	O

Ms	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Sellu	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
deputy	NOUN	O
nurse	NOUN	O
matron	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
a	DET	O
Government	NOUN	O
hospital	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Sierra	NOUN	I-LOC
Leone	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
lost	NOUN	O
15	NUM	O
of	ADP	O
her	PRON	O
nurses	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
Ebola	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

Nevertheless	NOUN	O
,	.	O
she	NOUN	O
never	NOUN	O
stopped	NOUN	O
working	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
that	NOUN	O
death	NOUN	O
trap	NOUN	O
.	.	O

She	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
true	NOUN	O
fighter	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
MDGs	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

Education	NOUN	O
,	.	O
particularly	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
girls	NOUN	O
,	.	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
superhighway	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
ending	NOUN	O
poverty	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Poverty	NOUN	O
,	.	O
discrimination	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
use	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
force	NOUN	O
often	NOUN	O
prevent	NOUN	O
girls	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
getting	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
education	NOUN	O
they	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
entitled	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Sexual	NOUN	O
violence	NOUN	O
,	.	O
abductions	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
deadly	NOUN	O
attacks	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
the	DET	O
most	DET	O
despicable	NOUN	O
ways	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
which	DET	O
girls'	NOUN	O
right	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
education	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
being	NOUN	O
violated	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
condemn	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
abductions	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
schoolgirls	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
Boko	NOUN	I-ORG
Haram	NOUN	I-ORG
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
strongest	NOUN	O
possible	NOUN	O
terms	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Malala	NOUN	I-PER
brought	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
light	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
plight	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
millions	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
children	NOUN	O
around	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
who	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
denied	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
education	NOUN	O
.	.	O

If	CONJ	O
one	NOUN	O
schoolgirl	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Taliban	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
then	NOUN	O
surely	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
defeat	NOUN	O
extremism	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Terrorists	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
extremists	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
trying	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
stop	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
from	NOUN	O
educating	NOUN	O
children	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Peace	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
vital	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
achieving	NOUN	O
universal	NOUN	O
primary	NOUN	O
education	NOUN	O
.	.	O

That	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
why	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
focus	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
conflict-affected	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
.	.	O

A	DET	O
girl	NOUN	O
growing	NOUN	O
up	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Syria	NOUN	I-LOC
today	NOUN	O
cannot	NOUN	O
look	NOUN	O
forward	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
going	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
school	NOUN	O
,	.	O
because	CONJ	O
there	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
no	DET	O
school	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
go	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
.	.	O

A	DET	O
pregnant	NOUN	O
teenage	NOUN	O
girl	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
South	NOUN	I-LOC
Sudan	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
get	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
maternal	NOUN	O
health	NOUN	O
services	NOUN	O
she	NOUN	O
needs	NOUN	O
because	CONJ	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
too	NOUN	O
risky	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
health	NOUN	O
workers	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
travel	NOUN	O
.	.	O

From	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
Chamber	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
modest	NOUN	O
homes	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Swat	NOUN	I-LOC
Valley	NOUN	I-LOC
in	ADP	O
Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
can	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
help	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
end	NOUN	O
poverty	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
promoting	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
all	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
different	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
global	ADJ	O
,	.	O
regional	NOUN	O
,	.	O
national	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
local	NOUN	O
levels	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
work	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
concert	NOUN	O
.	.	O

￼It	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
70	NUM	O
years	NOUN	O
since	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
group	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
leaders	NOUN	O
met	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Washington	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
D	NOUN	O
.	.	O
C	NOUN	O
.	.	O
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
discuss	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
creation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

One	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
most	DET	O
fundamental	NOUN	O
tenets	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
world	NOUN	O
order	NOUN	O
created	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
1945	NUM	O
was	VERB	O
respect	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
internationally	NOUN	O
recognized	NOUN	O
borders	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Norway	NOUN	I-LOC
condemns	NOUN	O
Russia	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
violations	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
international	NOUN	O
law	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
its	NOUN	O
continuing	NOUN	O
destabilization	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
eastern	NOUN	O
Ukraine	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

The	DET	O
ceasefire	NOUN	O
agreed	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
5	NUM	O
September	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
respected	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
provisions	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
agreement	NOUN	O
implemented	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
ground	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Russia	NOUN	I-LOC
bears	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
particular	NOUN	O
responsibility	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
that	NOUN	O
regard	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
is	VERB	O
mandated	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
maintain	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
security	NOUN	O
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
has	NOUN	O
failed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
address	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
situation	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Syria	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
Ukraine	NOUN	I-LOC
effectively	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
know	NOUN	O
why	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Some	DET	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
big	NOUN	O
Powers	NOUN	O
still	ADV	O
believe	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
outdated	NOUN	O
ideas	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
zero-	NOUN	O
sum	NOUN	O
games	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
spheres	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
influence	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
hopeful	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
will	VERB	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
stand	NOUN	O
united	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
threat	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
terrorist	NOUN	O
group	NOUN	O
known	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Islamic	NOUN	I-ORG
State	NOUN	I-ORG
in	ADP	I-ORG
Iraq	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	I-ORG
the	DET	I-ORG
Levant	NOUN	I-ORG
(	.	O
ISIL	NOUN	I-ORG
)	.	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
support	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
States	NOUN	I-LOC
initiative	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
sponsored	NOUN	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
resolution	NOUN	O
2178	NUM	O
(	.	O
2014	NUM	O
)	.	O
on	ADP	O
foreign	NOUN	O
terrorist	NOUN	O
fighters	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
encourage	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
countries	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
region	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
leading	NOUN	O
role	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
fighting	NOUN	O
ISIL	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

Armed	NOUN	O
conflict	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
civil	NOUN	O
war	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
created	NOUN	O
man-	NOUN	O
made	NOUN	O
humanitarian	NOUN	O
disasters	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Syria	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
South	NOUN	I-LOC
Sudan	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
the	DET	O
Central	NOUN	I-LOC
African	NOUN	I-LOC
Republic	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
Somalia	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

Earlier	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
year	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Norway	NOUN	I-LOC
hosted	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
humanitarian	NOUN	O
donor	NOUN	O
conference	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
South	NOUN	I-LOC
Sudan	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
we	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
shortly	NOUN	O
co-host	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
donor	NOUN	O
conference	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
address	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
aftermath	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
conflict	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Gaza	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

Donor	NOUN	O
conferences	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
important	NOUN	O
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
we	PRON	O
need	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
look	NOUN	O
beyond	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
emergencies	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
need	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
build	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
and	CONJ	O
improve	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
current	NOUN	O
system	NOUN	O
,	.	O
when	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
meet	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
World	NOUN	I-MISC
Humanitarian	NOUN	I-MISC
Summit	NOUN	I-MISC
in	ADP	O
2016	NUM	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
sure	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
humanitarian	NOUN	O
aid	NOUN	O
supports	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
only	NOUN	O
short-term	NOUN	O
recovery	NOUN	O
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
also	ADV	O
long-term	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Besides	NOUN	O
,	.	O
long-term	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
help	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
prevent	NOUN	O
,	.	O
prepare	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
,	.	O
withstand	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
recover	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
humanitarian	NOUN	O
crises	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
future	NOUN	O
.	.	O

International	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
,	.	O
national	NOUN	O
security	NOUN	O
,	.	O
social	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
individual	NOUN	O
prosperity	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
best	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
fostered	NOUN	O
under	ADP	O
a	DET	O
system	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
good	NOUN	O
democratic	NOUN	O
governance	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Efforts	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
promote	NOUN	O
respect	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
help	NOUN	O
prevent	NOUN	O
armed	NOUN	O
conflict	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
mass	NOUN	O
atrocities	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Nobel	NOUN	O
Peace	NOUN	O
Prize	NOUN	O
laureate	NOUN	O
Shirin	NOUN	I-PER
Ebadi	NOUN	I-PER
,	.	O
herself	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
leading	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
defender	NOUN	O
,	.	O
stated	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
her	PRON	O
Nobel	NOUN	O
lecture	NOUN	O
that:	NOUN	O
"	.	O
[i]f	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
twenty-first	NOUN	O
century	NOUN	O
wishes	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
free	NOUN	O
itself	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
cycle	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
violence	NOUN	O
,	.	O
acts	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
terror	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
war	NOUN	O
,	.	O
there	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
no	DET	O
other	NOUN	O
way	NOUN	O
except	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
understanding	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
putting	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
practice	NOUN	O
every	DET	O
human	NOUN	O
right	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
mankind	NOUN	O
,	.	O
irrespective	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
race	NOUN	O
,	.	O
gender	NOUN	O
,	.	O
faith	NOUN	O
,	.	O
nationality	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
social	NOUN	O
status	NOUN	O
.	.	O
"	.	O

I	NOUN	O
agree	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
that	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
one	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
three	NOUN	O
pillars	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
based	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Universal	NOUN	I-MISC
Declaration	NOUN	I-MISC
of	ADP	I-MISC
Human	NOUN	I-MISC
Rights	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
adopted	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
on	ADP	O
10	NUM	O
December	NOUN	O
1948	NUM	O
.	.	O

Norway	NOUN	I-LOC
endorses	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
"	.	O
Human	NOUN	O
Rights	NOUN	O
Up	NOUN	O
Front	NOUN	O
"	.	O
initiative	NOUN	O
,	.	O
which	DET	O
places	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
protection	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
heart	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
strategies	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
operational	NOUN	O
activities	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
needs	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
strong	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
assertive	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
pillar	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Only	NOUN	O
if	CONJ	O
we	PRON	O
fund	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
pillar	NOUN	O
properly	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
achieve	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
results	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
need	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
want	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
Organization	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
promotion	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
protection	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
first	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
foremost	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
responsibility	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
States	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
,	.	O
however	NOUN	O
,	.	O
facing	NOUN	O
large	NOUN	O
implementation	NOUN	O
gaps	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Attacks	NOUN	O
,	.	O
threats	NOUN	O
,	.	O
intimidation	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
reprisals	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
defenders	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
increasingly	NOUN	O
being	NOUN	O
reported	NOUN	O
.	.	O

New	ADJ	O
laws	NOUN	O
restricting	NOUN	O
freedom	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
expression	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
work	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
civil	NOUN	O
society	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
being	NOUN	O
adopted	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Discrimination	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
widespread	NOUN	O
,	.	O
particularly	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
minorities	NOUN	O
,	.	O
such	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
indigenous	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
lesbian	NOUN	O
,	.	O
gay	NOUN	O
,	.	O
bisexual	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
transgender	NOUN	O
persons	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
rule	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
law	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
civil	NOUN	O
liberties	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
also	ADV	O
fundamental	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
development	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
private	NOUN	O
sector	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
attracting	NOUN	O
investment	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Moreover	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
know	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
enabling	NOUN	O
women	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
fully	NOUN	O
enjoy	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
social	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
economic	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
unleashes	NOUN	O
tremendous	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
growth	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
stay	NOUN	O
focused	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
accelerating	NOUN	O
progress	NOUN	O
towards	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
MDGs	NOUN	I-ORG
during	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
remaining	NOUN	O
462	NUM	O
days	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
let	NOUN	O
ourselves	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
inspired	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
those	NOUN	O
who	NOUN	O
serve	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
front	NOUN	O
line	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
those	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
,	.	O
like	NOUN	O
Ms	NOUN	O
.	.	O
Sellu	NOUN	I-PER
and	CONJ	O
other	NOUN	O
doctors	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
nurses	NOUN	O
who	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
risking	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
lives	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
treat	NOUN	O
patients	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
Ebola	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

As	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
set	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
future	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
agenda	NOUN	O
beyond	NOUN	O
2015	NUM	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
make	NOUN	O
some	DET	O
adjustments	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
stability	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
included	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Climate	NOUN	O
issues	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
addressed	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Good	NOUN	O
,	.	O
democratic	NOUN	O
governance	NOUN	O
,	.	O
with	ADP	O
respect	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
rule	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
law	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
,	.	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
crucial	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
achieving	NOUN	O
sustainable	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
all	NOUN	O
.	.	O

And	CONJ	O
all	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
means	NOUN	O
,	.	O
quite	NOUN	O
simply	NOUN	O
,	.	O
is	VERB	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
doing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
right	NOUN	O
things	NOUN	O
right	NOUN	O
.	.	O
