I	O
should	O
also	O
like	O
to	O
express	O
my	O
deep	O
appreciation	O
to	O
his	O
predecessor	O
,	O
Mr.	O
Han	I-PER
Seung-soo	I-PER
,	O
Foreign	O
Minister	O
of	O
the	O
Republic	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
,	O
for	O
his	O
tireless	O
efforts	O
in	O
conducting	O
the	O
proceedings	O
of	O
the	O
fifty-sixth	O
session	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
of	O
the	O
twenty-seventh	O
special	O
session	O
of	O
the	O
Assembly	I-ORG
,	O
on	O
children	O
.	O

Furthermore	O
,	O
I	O
am	O
pleased	O
to	O
extend	O
my	O
congratulations	O
to	O
the	O
Swiss	I-LOC
Confederation	I-LOC
on	O
its	O
having	O
joined	O
the	O
Organization	I-ORG
.	O

I	O
would	O
like	O
also	O
to	O
congratulate	O
East	I-LOC
Timor	I-LOC
on	O
attaining	O
its	O
independence	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
also	O
my	O
pleasure	O
to	O
welcome	O
the	O
establishment	O
of	O
the	O
African	I-ORG
Union	I-ORG
,	O
the	O
successor	O
to	O
the	O
Organization	I-ORG
of	I-ORG
African	I-ORG
Unity	I-ORG
.	O

This	O
session	O
was	O
convened	O
on	O
the	O
first	O
anniversary	O
of	O
11	O
September	O
,	O
an	O
event	O
that	O
terrified	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
,	O
shocked	O
the	O
human	O
conscience	O
and	O
unified	O
international	O
efforts	O
to	O
face	O
up	O
to	O
an	O
enemy	O
that	O
has	O
no	O
religion	O
,	O
ethnicity	O
,	O
race	O
or	O
nationality	O
.	O

That	O
enemy	O
is	O
terrorism	O
.	O

On	O
this	O
painful	O
anniversary	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
incumbent	O
upon	O
us	O
to	O
again	O
extend	O
our	O
condolences	O
and	O
sympathy	O
to	O
the	O
United	I-LOC
States	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
America	I-LOC
and	O
its	O
friendly	O
people	O
,	O
and	O
to	O
the	O
families	O
of	O
the	O
victims	O
everywhere	O
,	O
and	O
to	O
condemn	O
terrorism	O
in	O
all	O
its	O
forms	O
and	O
manifestations	O
.	O

We	O
affirm	O
our	O
support	O
for	O
all	O
international	O
efforts	O
that	O
seek	O
to	O
combat	O
its	O
elements	O
and	O
to	O
uproot	O
it	O
.	O

Such	O
a	O
human	O
being	O
would	O
be	O
prepared	O
and	O
qualified	O
to	O
cope	O
with	O
the	O
political	O
,	O
economic	O
and	O
social	O
requirements	O
of	O
modern	O
life	O
.	O

My	O
country	O
was	O
proclaimed	O
a	O
constitutional	O
monarchy	O
following	O
a	O
plebiscite	O
on	O
our	O
National	I-MISC
Action	I-MISC
Charter	I-MISC
,	O
designed	O
to	O
promote	O
democratic	O
and	O
constitutional	O
life	O
in	O
Bahrain	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
municipal	O
elections	O
in	O
May	O
2002	O
,	O
in	O
which	O
women	O
participated	O
both	O
as	O
voters	O
and	O
as	O
candidates	O
,	O
were	O
a	O
success	O
;	O
preparations	O
are	O
now	O
under	O
way	O
for	O
parliamentary	O
elections	O
,	O
which	O
are	O
to	O
take	O
place	O
in	O
October	O
.	O

The	O
Government	O
and	O
the	O
people	O
have	O
made	O
a	O
concerted	O
effort	O
to	O
ensure	O
success	O
in	O
the	O
democratic	O
and	O
developmental	O
process	O
,	O
as	O
set	O
out	O
in	O
the	O
Kingdom	I-LOC
's	O
Constitution	O
and	O
in	O
its	O
policies	O
and	O
programmes	O
in	O
all	O
fields	O
.	O

Civic	O
activities	O
have	O
been	O
enhanced	O
and	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
non-governmental	O
organizations	O
has	O
risen	O
.	O

These	O
have	O
been	O
promoted	O
so	O
that	O
all	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
Bahrain	I-LOC
may	O
participate	O
in	O
expanding	O
national	O
efforts	O
to	O
ensure	O
the	O
well-being	O
of	O
the	O
people	O
and	O
respect	O
for	O
human	O
rights	O
in	O
all	O
civil	O
,	O
political	O
,	O
economic	O
,	O
social	O
and	O
cultural	O
areas	O
.	O

Furthermore	O
,	O
the	O
Arab	I-MISC
Human	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
Report	I-MISC
2002	O
has	O
also	O
mentioned	O
our	O
achievements	O
,	O
showing	O
once	O
again	O
the	O
success	O
of	O
the	O
Kingdom	I-LOC
's	O
democratic	O
and	O
development	O
strategy	O
in	O
all	O
areas	O
.	O

The	O
Kingdom	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
Bahrain	I-LOC
attaches	O
great	O
importance	O
to	O
the	O
question	O
of	O
regional	O
security	O
,	O
because	O
of	O
the	O
repercussions	O
it	O
has	O
on	O
the	O
security	O
and	O
stability	O
of	O
States	O
and	O
peoples	O
.	O

Accordingly	O
,	O
Bahrain	I-LOC
has	O
consistently	O
sought	O
to	O
consolidate	O
neighbourly	O
relations	O
and	O
mutual	O
respect	O
with	O
its	O
neighbouring	O
States	O
.	O

Furthermore	O
,	O
the	O
Arab	I-MISC
Summit	I-MISC
,	O
held	O
in	O
Beirut	I-LOC
last	O
March	O
,	O
confirmed	O
the	O
necessity	O
and	O
importance	O
of	O
security	O
and	O
stability	O
in	O
the	O
Gulf	I-MISC
region	O
and	O
of	O
creating	O
a	O
propitious	O
atmosphere	O
for	O
the	O
restoration	O
of	O
normal	O
relations	O
among	O
the	O
States	O
of	O
the	O
region	O
.	O

The	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
is	O
currently	O
facing	O
great	O
danger	O
as	O
a	O
result	O
of	O
Israel	I-LOC
's	O
policy	O
in	O
the	O
occupied	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
territories	O
and	O
of	O
its	O
perpetration	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
heinous	O
crimes	O
against	O
the	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
people	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
assassinations	O
,	O
blockades	O
and	O
the	O
destruction	O
of	O
the	O
infrastructure	O
and	O
the	O
economy	O
.	O

The	O
events	O
that	O
took	O
place	O
in	O
the	O
Jenin	I-MISC
refugee	O
camp	O
and	O
in	O
the	O
Gaza	I-LOC
Strip	I-LOC
,	O
along	O
with	O
the	O
daily	O
events	O
that	O
occur	O
in	O
all	O
other	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
cities	O
,	O
are	O
clear	O
indications	O
of	O
the	O
Israeli	I-MISC
Government	O
's	O
aggression	O
and	O
violation	O
of	O
international	O
law	O
and	O
norms	O
and	O
of	O
its	O
unwillingness	O
to	O
accept	O
peace	O
or	O
comply	O
with	O
the	O
international	O
agreements	O
it	O
has	O
signed	O
.	O

Furthermore	O
,	O
the	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
people	O
are	O
still	O
resisting	O
this	O
ferocious	O
assault	O
with	O
great	O
courage	O
and	O
determination	O
,	O
thus	O
asserting	O
their	O
right	O
to	O
fight	O
the	O
occupation	O
and	O
emphasizing	O
their	O
belief	O
in	O
their	O
just	O
cause	O
,	O
while	O
upholding	O
their	O
legitimate	O
leadership	O
and	O
defending	O
their	O
national	O
rights	O
,	O
as	O
endorsed	O
by	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
,	O
in	O
accordance	O
with	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
resolutions	O
242	O
(1967)	O
,	O
338	O
(1973)	O
,	O
and	O
other	O
relevant	O
resolutions	O
,	O
the	O
latest	O
being	O
Council	I-ORG
resolution	O
1397	O
(2002)	O
.	O

They	O
are	O
also	O
upholding	O
the	O
principle	O
of	O
land	O
for	O
peace	O
and	O
the	O
establishment	O
of	O
an	O
independent	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
State	O
on	O
their	O
national	O
land	O
,	O
with	O
Jerusalem	I-LOC
as	O
its	O
capital	O
.	O

On	O
the	O
basis	O
of	O
its	O
principles	O
and	O
in	O
support	O
of	O
justice	O
,	O
Bahrain	I-LOC
has	O
always	O
stood	O
by	O
the	O
brotherly	O
people	O
of	O
Palestine	I-LOC
.	O

It	O
affirms	O
its	O
full	O
support	O
for	O
the	O
Arab	I-MISC
peace	O
initiative	O
adopted	O
at	O
the	O
Arab	I-MISC
Summit	I-MISC
held	O
at	O
Beirut	I-LOC
in	O
March	O
2002	O
on	O
the	O
basis	O
of	O
the	O
vision	O
offered	O
by	O
His	O
Royal	O
Highness	O
Prince	O
Abdullah	I-PER
Bin	I-PER
Abdul-Aziz	I-PER
Al-Saud	I-PER
,	O
Crown	O
Prince	O
of	O
the	O
Kingdom	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
Saudi	I-LOC
Arabia	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
oppression	O
to	O
which	O
the	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
people	O
are	O
subjected	O
and	O
the	O
ongoing	O
situation	O
that	O
threatens	O
security	O
and	O
peace	O
in	O
the	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
and	O
the	O
world	O
require	O
immediate	O
intervention	O
by	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
and	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
to	O
stop	O
Israeli	I-MISC
practices	O
against	O
the	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
people	O
and	O
to	O
reactivate	O
the	O
Arab	I-MIS
peace	O
initiative	O
at	O
the	O
regional	O
and	O
international	O
levels	O
.	O

That	O
initiative	O
is	O
a	O
viable	O
basis	O
for	O
any	O
move	O
towards	O
the	O
achievement	O
of	O
a	O
just	O
and	O
comprehensive	O
peace	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
.	O

Bahrain	I-LOC
has	O
welcomed	O
the	O
initiative	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-LOC
States	I-LOC
Secretary	O
of	O
State	O
with	O
respect	O
to	O
convening	O
a	O
peace	O
conference	O
on	O
the	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
,	O
on	O
the	O
basis	O
of	O
ideas	O
and	O
principles	O
put	O
forward	O
by	O
the	O
Arab	I-MISC
Summit	I-MISC
in	O
the	O
Arab	I-MISC
peace	O
initiative	O
and	O
of	O
the	O
relevant	O
international	O
resolutions	O
.	O

It	O
hopes	O
that	O
a	O
just	O
and	O
comprehensive	O
peace	O
in	O
the	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
will	O
thus	O
be	O
achieved	O
,	O
leading	O
to	O
stability	O
and	O
security	O
,	O
ending	O
the	O
cycle	O
of	O
conflict	O
and	O
violence	O
,	O
and	O
bringing	O
instead	O
a	O
cycle	O
of	O
fruitful	O
cooperation	O
among	O
the	O
countries	O
of	O
the	O
region	O
.	O

Bahrain	I-LOC
has	O
also	O
reaffirmed	O
this	O
position	O
by	O
welcoming	O
the	O
positive	O
ideas	O
in	O
President	O
Bush	I-PER
's	O
24	O
June	O
2002	O
statement	O
on	O
the	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
Arab	I-MISC
side	O
,	O
through	O
the	O
Arab	I-MISC
peace	O
initiative	O
and	O
by	O
accepting	O
the	O
ideas	O
that	O
President	O
Bush	I-PER
has	O
put	O
forward	O
,	O
has	O
clearly	O
demonstrated	O
its	O
interest	O
in	O
security	O
and	O
stability	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
.	O

The	O
Israeli	I-MISC
side	O
has	O
yet	O
to	O
detail	O
what	O
plans	O
it	O
has	O
for	O
peace	O
and	O
what	O
position	O
it	O
has	O
taken	O
vis-à-	O
vis	O
the	O
Arab	I-MISC
peace	O
initiative	O
and	O
the	O
ideas	O
put	O
forward	O
by	O
President	O
Bush	I-PER
.	O

What	O
is	O
needed	O
now	O
is	O
to	O
translate	O
those	O
ideas	O
and	O
initiatives	O
into	O
plans	O
and	O
practical	O
steps	O
that	O
benefit	O
peace	O
and	O
put	O
an	O
end	O
to	O
the	O
present	O
deteriorating	O
situation	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
light	O
of	O
Bahrain	I-LOC
's	O
religious	O
and	O
cultural	O
traditions	O
,	O
as	O
reflected	O
in	O
our	O
Constitution	O
and	O
national	O
laws	O
and	O
as	O
reaffirmed	O
by	O
our	O
policies	O
that	O
focus	O
,	O
inter	O
alia	O
,	O
on	O
the	O
right	O
to	O
life	O
,	O
security	O
and	O
peace	O
,	O
we	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
reaffirm	O
our	O
strong	O
rejection	O
of	O
all	O
forms	O
and	O
manifestations	O
of	O
terrorism	O
.	O

We	O
would	O
also	O
welcome	O
the	O
convening	O
under	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
auspices	O
of	O
an	O
international	O
conference	O
on	O
terrorism	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
view	O
to	O
reaching	O
an	O
internationally	O
agreed	O
definition	O
of	O
terrorism	O
that	O
differentiates	O
between	O
unacceptable	O
terrorist	O
acts	O
and	O
legitimate	O
struggle	O
and	O
resistance	O
by	O
people	O
against	O
foreign	O
occupation	O
to	O
achieve	O
national	O
liberation	O
and	O
self-determination	O
,	O
and	O
to	O
defend	O
themselves	O
in	O
accordance	O
with	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Charter	I-MISC
,	O
to	O
which	O
we	O
adhere	O
in	O
word	O
and	O
deed	O
.	O

The	O
Kingdom	I-LOC
of	I-MISC
Bahrain	I-LOC
has	O
followed	O
with	O
great	O
interest	O
the	O
developments	O
in	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
,	O
a	O
country	O
that	O
has	O
lacked	O
stability	O
and	O
has	O
suffered	O
the	O
ravages	O
of	O
war	O
for	O
many	O
years	O
.	O

We	O
welcome	O
the	O
measures	O
taken	O
by	O
the	O
Government	O
of	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
with	O
a	O
view	O
to	O
promoting	O
security	O
and	O
stability	O
and	O
restoring	O
normal	O
life	O
for	O
its	O
people	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
also	O
cooperated	O
fully	O
with	O
the	O
Committee	I-ORG
established	O
pursuant	O
to	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
resolution	O
1373	O
(2001)	O
on	O
financial	O
and	O
logistical	O
measures	O
against	O
terrorist	O
activities	O
,	O
in	O
line	O
with	O
the	O
concept	O
of	O
collective	O
action	O
within	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

We	O
call	O
upon	O
all	O
our	O
neighbours	O
to	O
support	O
this	O
idea	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
release	O
resources	O
that	O
could	O
be	O
used	O
for	O
the	O
prosperity	O
and	O
development	O
of	O
peoples	O
.	O

A	O
number	O
of	O
internationally	O
known	O
intellectuals	O
from	O
the	O
Arab	I-MISC
and	O
Islamic	I-MISC
worlds	O
and	O
from	O
Japan	I-LOC
participated	O
in	O
the	O
seminar	O
,	O
which	O
was	O
convened	O
last	O
March	O
and	O
was	O
entitled	O
"	O
The	O
Dialogue	O
among	O
Civilizations:	O
The	O
Islamic	I-MISC
World	O
and	O
Japan	I-LOC
"	O
.	O

The	O
seminar	O
sought	O
to	O
promote	O
dialogue	O
between	O
Arab-Islamic	I-MISC
civilizations	O
and	O
other	O
civilizations	O
so	O
that	O
different	O
cultures	O
may	O
grow	O
closer	O
to	O
one	O
another	O
.	O

In	O
furtherance	O
of	O
this	O
approach	O
,	O
the	O
Kingdom	I-LOC
of	I-MISC
Bahrain	I-LOC
will	O
also	O
host	O
the	O
tenth	O
session	O
of	O
the	O
Islamic-Christian	I-MISC
Dialogue	O
Conference	O
,	O
to	O
be	O
held	O
from	O
28	O
to	O
30	O
October	O
2002	O
.	O

The	O
objective	O
is	O
to	O
promote	O
better	O
understanding	O
between	O
world	O
religions	O
and	O
cultures	O
,	O
and	O
to	O
enhance	O
interaction	O
and	O
exchange	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
preserve	O
the	O
progress	O
that	O
has	O
been	O
made	O
and	O
to	O
invigorate	O
an	O
informed	O
outlook	O
for	O
the	O
future	O
,	O
wherein	O
cooperation	O
in	O
the	O
interest	O
of	O
the	O
entire	O
human	O
race	O
,	O
without	O
discrimination	O
,	O
can	O
take	O
place	O
.	O

In	O
conclusion	O
,	O
I	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
state	O
that	O
,	O
thanks	O
to	O
cooperative	O
efforts	O
,	O
the	O
World	O
Summit	I-MISC
on	I-MISC
Sustainable	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
,	O
recently	O
held	O
in	O
Johannesburg	I-LOC
,	O
provided	O
a	O
favourable	O
opportunity	O
for	O
the	O
review	O
and	O
evaluation	O
of	O
achievements	O
made	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
10	O
years	O
,	O
the	O
identification	O
of	O
impediments	O
and	O
challenges	O
,	O
the	O
development	O
of	O
strategies	O
and	O
the	O
identification	O
of	O
objectives	O
and	O
priorities	O
for	O
joint	O
action	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
our	O
hope	O
that	O
all	O
States	O
will	O
implement	O
the	O
outcome	O
of	O
the	O
Johannesburg	I-LOC
Summit	I-MISC
and	O
will	O
address	O
the	O
challenges	O
facing	O
us	O
all	O
,	O
especially	O
the	O
developing	O
States	I-LOC
.	O

In	O
that	O
context	O
,	O
the	O
Kingdom	I-LOC
of	O
Bahrain	I-LOC
would	O
like	O
once	O
again	O
to	O
affirm	O
the	O
importance	O
of	O
practical	O
and	O
effective	O
implementation	O
of	O
the	O
Millennium	I-MISC
Declaration	I-MISC
with	O
regard	O
to	O
development	O
and	O
the	O
role	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
and	O
international	O
organizations	O
in	O
supporting	O
national	O
efforts	O
in	O
that	O
field	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
confident	O
that	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
with	O
the	O
determination	O
,	O
political	O
will	O
and	O
hard	O
work	O
of	O
its	O
Member	O
States	O
,	O
is	O
capable	O
of	O
efforts	O
that	O
will	O
help	O
us	O
achieve	O
our	O
shared	O
goals	O
of	O
just	O
peace	O
,	O
economic	O
prosperity	O
and	O
social	O
justice	O
throughout	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
in	O
our	O
interest	O
to	O
cooperate	O
with	O
one	O
another	O
to	O
make	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
the	O
main	O
engine	O
of	O
our	O
activities	O
,	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
achieve	O
a	O
better	O
world:	O
one	O
of	O
peace	O
,	O
security	O
,	O
prosperity	O
and	O
justice	O
for	O
all	O
peoples	O
and	O
all	O
States	O
.	O
