I	O
am	O
honoured	O
to	O
appear	O
before	O
the	O
Assembly	I-ORG
today	O
to	O
deliver	O
these	O
remarks	O
on	O
behalf	O
of	O
the	O
Government	O
of	O
Canada	I-LOC
in	O
this	O
,	O
the	O
seventieth	O
anniversary	O
year	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

There	O
can	O
be	O
little	O
doubt	O
that	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
seven	O
decades	O
,	O
through	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
,	O
other	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
bodies	O
and	O
the	O
myriad	O
of	O
agencies	O
,	O
funds	O
and	O
programmes	O
associated	O
with	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
the	O
Organization	O
has	O
often	O
helped	O
to	O
improve	O
the	O
lives	O
and	O
prospects	O
of	O
people	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

It	O
has	O
done	O
so	O
even	O
as	O
Member	O
States	O
and	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
itself	O
have	O
struggled	O
to	O
realize	O
the	O
Organization	O
's	O
most	O
fundamental	O
aspirations	O
.	O

Since	O
that	O
time	O
,	O
Canada	I-LOC
and	O
Canadians	I-MISC
have	O
been	O
steadfast	O
supporters	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
and	O
deeply	O
engaged	O
in	O
its	O
work	O
to	O
deliver	O
results	O
for	O
the	O
benefit	O
of	O
our	O
common	O
future	O
.	O

One	O
of	O
the	O
ways	O
in	O
which	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
led	O
the	O
way	O
in	O
its	O
early	O
years	O
,	O
and	O
in	O
which	O
it	O
continues	O
to	O
light	O
the	O
path	O
ahead	O
,	O
has	O
been	O
in	O
the	O
vital	O
area	O
of	O
international	O
development	O
.	O

Canada	I-LOC
is	O
proud	O
to	O
support	O
,	O
in	O
word	O
and	O
deed	O
,	O
the	O
commitments	O
in	O
the	O
2030	O
Agenda	I-MISC
for	I-MISC
Sustainable	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
(	O
resolution	O
70/1	O
)	O
.	O

The	O
Organization	O
and	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
it	O
represents	O
deserve	O
our	O
praise	O
for	O
aiming	O
to	O
eliminate	O
poverty	O
on	O
a	O
global	O
scale	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
an	O
objective	O
that	O
will	O
require	O
innovative	O
new	O
approaches	O
and	O
new	O
partnerships	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
also	O
need	O
to	O
promote	O
fundamental	O
freedoms	O
,	O
the	O
rule	O
of	O
law	O
and	O
accountable	O
governance	O
in	O
those	O
parts	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
where	O
the	O
critical	O
building	O
blocks	O
for	O
sustainable	O
development	O
are	O
weak	O
or	O
absent	O
.	O

Canada	I-LOC
looks	O
forward	O
to	O
collaborating	O
with	O
others	O
to	O
sustain	O
the	O
momentum	O
already	O
underway	O
as	O
a	O
result	O
of	O
the	O
Millennium	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
Goals	I-MISC
and	O
to	O
move	O
forward	O
with	O
renewed	O
determination	O
.	O

The	O
Government	O
of	O
Canada	I-LOC
has	O
identified	O
maternal	O
,	O
newborn	O
and	O
child	O
health	O
as	O
a	O
priority	O
for	O
development	O
,	O
in	O
support	O
for	O
which	O
we	O
have	O
committed	O
$3.5	O
billion	O
over	O
the	O
next	O
five	O
years	O
.	O

There	O
has	O
been	O
progress	O
,	O
to	O
be	O
sure	O
,	O
but	O
there	O
remains	O
much	O
to	O
do	O
.	O

As	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
commits	O
to	O
implementing	O
the	O
2030	O
Agenda	O
,	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
critical	O
questions	O
we	O
still	O
face	O
is	O
how	O
to	O
finance	O
the	O
Sustainable	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
Goals	I-MISC
.	O

While	O
current	O
official	O
development	O
assistance	O
will	O
retain	O
its	O
important	O
role	O
,	O
current	O
and	O
projected	O
levels	O
fall	O
well	O
short	O
of	O
the	O
trillions	O
of	O
dollars	O
required	O
to	O
implement	O
the	O
Goals	I-MISC
.	O

We	O
need	O
to	O
find	O
new	O
ways	O
to	O
blend	O
financing	O
from	O
donors	O
,	O
foundations	O
,	O
the	O
private	O
sector	O
and	O
other	O
sources	O
to	O
fill	O
the	O
gap	O
.	O

￼The	O
Global	I-MISC
Financing	I-MISC
Facility	I-MISC
(	O
GFF	I-MISC
)	O
in	O
support	O
of	O
Every	I-MISC
Woman	I-MISC
,	I-MISC
Every	I-MISC
Child	I-MISC
is	O
an	O
excellent	O
model	O
of	O
how	O
the	O
private	O
sector	O
can	O
be	O
brought	O
on	O
board	O
to	O
collaborate	O
with	O
national	O
Governments	O
to	O
sustainably	O
finance	O
maternal	O
,	O
newborn	O
and	O
child	O
health	O
initiatives	O
.	O

The	O
additional	O
investment	O
generated	O
through	O
the	O
GFF	I-MISC
and	O
other	O
innovative	O
financing	O
mechanisms	O
will	O
set	O
the	O
course	O
for	O
increasing	O
funding	O
from	O
the	O
current	O
billions	O
of	O
dollars	O
allocated	O
for	O
development	O
finance	O
to	O
the	O
trillions	O
required	O
if	O
we	O
want	O
to	O
achieve	O
the	O
post-2015	O
development	O
agenda	O
.	O

Canada	I-LOC
will	O
continue	O
to	O
play	O
a	O
leading	O
role	O
in	O
helping	O
to	O
establish	O
those	O
mechanisms	O
to	O
secure	O
sustainable	O
financing	O
and	O
leverage	O
the	O
expertise	O
and	O
resources	O
of	O
the	O
private	O
sector	O
in	O
support	O
of	O
the	O
development	O
outcomes	O
.	O

Humanitarian	O
assistance	O
is	O
even	O
more	O
important	O
,	O
as	O
progress	O
in	O
development	O
can	O
be	O
wiped	O
out	O
overnight	O
by	O
natural	O
disasters	O
,	O
political	O
violence	O
and	O
international	O
conflicts	O
or	O
crises	O
linked	O
to	O
acute	O
food	O
insecurity	O
or	O
the	O
spread	O
of	O
disease	O
.	O

When	O
considering	O
the	O
first-ever	O
World	I-MISC
Humanitarian	I-MISC
Summit	I-MISC
,	O
to	O
be	O
held	O
in	O
May	O
2016	O
,	O
we	O
all	O
must	O
strive	O
to	O
increase	O
countries'	O
determination	O
to	O
respect	O
international	O
humanitarian	O
law	O
,	O
to	O
protect	O
civilians	O
and	O
to	O
strengthen	O
resilience	O
when	O
faced	O
with	O
possible	O
crises	O
,	O
in	O
particular	O
by	O
ensuring	O
that	O
national	O
Governments	O
will	O
be	O
equipped	O
to	O
deal	O
with	O
those	O
crises	O
.	O

In	O
responding	O
to	O
the	O
needs	O
of	O
humankind	O
,	O
Canada	I-LOC
always	O
strives	O
to	O
act	O
with	O
generosity	O
,	O
speed	O
and	O
efficacy	O
to	O
save	O
lives	O
,	O
to	O
alleviate	O
suffering	O
and	O
to	O
preserve	O
the	O
dignity	O
of	O
the	O
people	O
most	O
affected	O
.	O

In	O
2014	O
,	O
Canada	I-LOC
increased	O
by	O
32	O
per	O
cent	O
its	O
financial	O
contribution	O
to	O
humanitarian	O
assistance	O
in	O
response	O
to	O
the	O
ever-increasing	O
needs	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
,	O
especially	O
for	O
countries	O
in	O
crisis	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
Iraq	I-LOC
,	O
Syria	I-LOC
,	O
the	O
Philippines	I-LOC
,	O
Ukraine	I-LOC
,	O
the	O
Central	I-LOC
African	I-LOC
Republic	I-LOC
,	O
South	I-LOC
Sudan	I-LOC
and	O
Yemen	I-LOC
.	O

Similarly	O
,	O
Canada	I-LOC
has	O
played	O
a	O
leading	O
role	O
in	O
the	O
prompt	O
and	O
effective	O
action	O
by	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
to	O
the	O
Ebola	I-MISC
epidemic	O
in	O
certain	O
regions	O
of	O
West	I-LOC
Africa	I-LOC
.	O

As	O
shown	O
at	O
numerous	O
times	O
in	O
the	O
past	O
,	O
Canada	I-LOC
has	O
the	O
capacity	O
and	O
the	O
will	O
to	O
assist	O
and	O
deal	O
with	O
the	O
crisis	O
of	O
refugees	O
and	O
migrants	O
currently	O
affecting	O
Europe	I-LOC
.	O

Since	O
the	O
establishment	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
has	O
been	O
confronted	O
with	O
many	O
situations	O
brought	O
about	O
by	O
the	O
voluntary	O
and	O
involuntary	O
displacement	O
of	O
people	O
.	O

In	O
some	O
cases	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
those	O
of	O
individuals	O
trying	O
to	O
escape	O
the	O
crisis	O
in	O
Syria	I-LOC
,	O
the	O
issue	O
is	O
urgent	O
.	O

In	O
others	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
part	O
of	O
a	O
long-term	O
phenomenon	O
.	O

We	O
work	O
in	O
collaboration	O
with	O
our	O
partners	O
to	O
address	O
those	O
difficulties	O
,	O
including	O
by	O
accelerating	O
the	O
resettlement	O
process	O
of	O
Syrians	I-MISC
and	O
Iraqis	I-MISC
in	O
our	O
own	O
country	O
this	O
year	O
.	O

We	O
know	O
that	O
Canadians	I-MISC
will	O
support	O
those	O
efforts	O
with	O
the	O
same	O
spirit	O
of	O
generosity	O
that	O
has	O
characterized	O
the	O
assistance	O
they	O
have	O
provided	O
when	O
others	O
were	O
in	O
distress	O
and	O
affected	O
by	O
disasters	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
we	O
cannot	O
stop	O
there	O
;	O
we	O
must	O
also	O
take	O
on	O
together	O
human	O
rights	O
violations	O
and	O
promote	O
stability	O
,	O
peace	O
and	O
prosperity	O
in	O
regions	O
subjected	O
to	O
instability	O
or	O
violent	O
conflicts	O
.	O

The	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
rooted	O
in	O
respect	O
for	O
fundamental	O
rights	O
and	O
freedoms	O
,	O
democracy	O
and	O
the	O
rule	O
of	O
law	O
,	O
was	O
established	O
specifically	O
for	O
that	O
purpose	O
.	O

Without	O
the	O
strong	O
and	O
collective	O
commitment	O
of	O
all	O
Member	O
States	O
to	O
those	O
principles	O
,	O
the	O
edifying	O
words	O
of	O
the	O
Preamble	O
to	O
the	O
Charter	I-MISC
risk	O
becoming	O
simply	O
hollow	O
and	O
meaningless	O
words	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
words	O
of	O
the	O
Prime	O
Minister	O
of	O
Canada:	I-LOC
"	O
Where	O
human	O
misery	O
abounds	O
,	O
where	O
grinding	O
poverty	O
is	O
the	O
rule	O
,	O
where	O
justice	O
is	O
systematically	O
denied	O
,	O
there	O
is	O
no	O
real	O
peace	O
—	O
only	O
the	O
seeds	O
of	O
future	O
conflict	O
.	O
"	O
(	O
A/69/PV.11	O
,	O
p	O
.	O
11	O
)	O
Canada	I-LOC
continues	O
to	O
support	O
a	O
wide	O
range	O
of	O
initiatives	O
and	O
measures	O
established	O
by	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
to	O
promote	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
most	O
recent	O
efforts	O
to	O
combat	O
terrorism	O
and	O
to	O
identify	O
new	O
ways	O
to	O
combat	O
violent	O
extremism	O
.	O

The	O
international	O
community	O
must	O
continue	O
to	O
take	O
significant	O
steps	O
to	O
combat	O
terrorism	O
together	O
.	O

Faced	O
with	O
that	O
situation	O
,	O
Canada	I-LOC
's	O
action	O
includes	O
not	O
only	O
its	O
role	O
in	O
the	O
military	O
coalition	O
that	O
is	O
fighting	O
against	O
the	O
immediate	O
threat	O
posed	O
by	O
Daesh	I-ORG
,	O
but	O
also	O
efforts	O
to	O
provide	O
humanitarian	O
assistance	O
.	O

Canada	I-LOC
will	O
continue	O
to	O
support	O
ethnic	O
and	O
religious	O
minorities	O
whose	O
very	O
existence	O
is	O
threatened	O
.	O

￼We	O
are	O
committed	O
to	O
drawing	O
everyone	O
's	O
attention	O
to	O
the	O
consequences	O
of	O
sexual	O
violence	O
and	O
other	O
barbaric	O
abuses	O
perpetrated	O
by	O
ISIS	I-ORG
against	O
women	O
and	O
girls	O
.	O

At	O
that	O
meeting	O
,	O
Canada	I-LOC
announced	O
an	O
additional	O
financial	O
contribution	O
for	O
the	O
survivors	O
of	O
abuses	O
committed	O
by	O
Daesh	I-ORG
and	O
in	O
support	O
of	O
the	O
essential	O
work	O
being	O
carried	O
out	O
by	O
Ms	O
.	O
Bangura	I-PER
.	O

Canada	I-LOC
has	O
long	O
been	O
determined	O
to	O
work	O
for	O
the	O
independence	O
of	O
women	O
and	O
girls	O
and	O
for	O
greater	O
respect	O
for	O
their	O
rights	O
in	O
conflict	O
situations	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
why	O
we	O
support	O
a	O
high-level	O
review	O
of	O
the	O
implementation	O
of	O
the	O
programme	O
on	O
women	O
and	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
,	O
as	O
we	O
have	O
done	O
for	O
the	O
past	O
15	O
years	O
,	O
that	O
is	O
,	O
since	O
the	O
adoption	O
of	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
resolution	O
1325	O
(	O
2000	O
)	O
,	O
the	O
first	O
resolution	O
on	O
that	O
issue	O
.	O

Canada	I-LOC
has	O
played	O
a	O
leading	O
role	O
in	O
the	O
global	O
campaign	O
to	O
eliminate	O
child	O
marriage	O
,	O
early	O
marriage	O
and	O
forced	O
marriage	O
,	O
a	O
widespread	O
and	O
harmful	O
practice	O
that	O
threatens	O
the	O
lives	O
and	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
girls	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
,	O
with	O
devastating	O
consequences	O
not	O
only	O
for	O
them	O
but	O
also	O
for	O
their	O
communities	O
.	O

Our	O
rules-based	O
international	O
system	O
must	O
be	O
preserved	O
.	O

International	O
guarantees	O
lose	O
their	O
meaning	O
if	O
rules	O
are	O
flagrantly	O
violated	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
face	O
acute	O
challenges	O
to	O
security	O
and	O
human	O
rights	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
in	O
Iraq	I-LOC
and	O
Syria	I-LOC
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
the	O
abuses	O
that	O
follow	O
in	O
the	O
wake	O
of	O
acts	O
of	O
aggression	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
the	O
Russian	I-LOC
invasion	O
of	O
Ukraine	I-LOC
,	O
the	O
illegal	O
annexation	O
of	O
Crimea	I-LOC
and	O
the	O
continued	O
interference	O
in	O
eastern	O
Ukraine	I-LOC
.	O

This	O
rostrum	O
must	O
not	O
be	O
used	O
by	O
leaders	O
to	O
subvert	O
the	O
principles	O
on	O
which	O
this	O
Organization	O
was	O
established	O
.	O

This	O
platform	O
should	O
be	O
used	O
to	O
respond	O
to	O
,	O
and	O
tackle	O
,	O
these	O
global	O
threats	O
.	O

Two	O
countries	O
that	O
persistently	O
violate	O
international	O
standards	O
in	O
this	O
area	O
and	O
whose	O
Governments	O
oppress	O
their	O
own	O
people	O
and	O
threaten	O
their	O
neighbours	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
global	O
peace	O
are	O
Iran	I-LOC
and	O
North	I-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
.	O

Non-compliance	O
over	O
the	O
course	O
of	O
decades	O
raises	O
questions	O
about	O
ambitions	O
and	O
intentions	O
.	O

Verbal	O
pledges	O
or	O
paper	O
promises	O
are	O
not	O
enough	O
.	O

There	O
must	O
be	O
verifiable	O
evidence	O
of	O
compliance	O
and	O
meaningful	O
penalties	O
for	O
continued	O
defiance	O
.	O

In	O
that	O
regard	O
,	O
while	O
we	O
appreciate	O
the	O
efforts	O
of	O
the	O
P5+1	O
,	O
the	O
real	O
test	O
of	O
the	O
Joint	O
Comprehensive	O
Plan	O
of	O
Action	O
concerning	O
Iran	I-LOC
,	O
or	O
any	O
similar	O
agreement	O
,	O
will	O
be	O
in	O
its	O
concrete	O
implementation	O
and	O
independent	O
verification	O
.	O

Actions	O
speak	O
louder	O
than	O
words	O
.	O

To	O
that	O
end	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
vital	O
to	O
support	O
,	O
sustain	O
and	O
,	O
where	O
necessary	O
,	O
enhance	O
the	O
monitoring	O
capabilities	O
of	O
the	O
relevant	O
agencies	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
the	O
International	I-ORG
Atomic	I-ORG
Energy	I-ORG
Agency	I-ORG
,	O
and	O
ensure	O
that	O
verifiable	O
deeds	O
match	O
conciliatory	O
words	O
.	O

Nothing	O
less	O
than	O
the	O
credibility	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
is	O
at	O
stake	O
on	O
such	O
matters	O
.	O

As	O
with	O
any	O
organization	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
vital	O
for	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
to	O
reassess	O
what	O
it	O
does	O
and	O
how	O
it	O
pursues	O
its	O
goals	O
in	O
the	O
light	O
of	O
the	O
remarkable	O
changes	O
since	O
its	O
founding	O
.	O

Canada	I-LOC
wholeheartedly	O
supports	O
the	O
high-	O
level	O
review	O
of	O
peace	O
operations	O
.	O

We	O
cannot	O
always	O
rely	O
on	O
the	O
instruments	O
of	O
the	O
past	O
to	O
deal	O
with	O
the	O
crises	O
of	O
today	O
.	O

Freedom	O
,	O
peace	O
and	O
stability	O
pave	O
the	O
way	O
to	O
lasting	O
prosperity	O
.	O

As	O
we	O
all	O
know	O
,	O
the	O
path	O
to	O
real	O
sustainable	O
development	O
requires	O
action	O
at	O
many	O
levels	O
and	O
with	O
many	O
partners	O
.	O

Private-sector-led	O
growth	O
is	O
a	O
key	O
ingredient	O
for	O
achieving	O
that	O
goal	O
and	O
for	O
reducing	O
poverty	O
.	O

Trade	O
and	O
investment	O
are	O
at	O
the	O
heart	O
of	O
that	O
effort	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
why	O
Canada	I-LOC
is	O
a	O
firm	O
supporter	O
of	O
a	O
free	O
and	O
open	O
trading	O
system	O
that	O
fosters	O
growth	O
,	O
contributes	O
to	O
development	O
and	O
supports	O
poverty	O
reduction	O
in	O
all	O
regions	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

Perhaps	O
no	O
issue	O
reminds	O
us	O
that	O
we	O
are	O
all	O
part	O
of	O
one	O
world	O
more	O
than	O
the	O
threat	O
to	O
our	O
collective	O
well-	O
being	O
posed	O
by	O
climate	O
change	O
,	O
a	O
global	O
challenge	O
that	O
requires	O
global	O
solutions	O
.	O

Canada	I-LOC
takes	O
the	O
challenge	O
of	O
climate	O
change	O
seriously	O
and	O
is	O
working	O
with	O
all	O
parties	O
under	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Framework	I-MISC
Convention	I-MISC
on	I-MISC
Climate	I-MISC
Change	I-MISC
to	O
reach	O
an	O
effective	O
post-2020	O
climate	O
change	O
agreement	O
at	O
the	O
twenty-first	O
session	O
of	O
the	O
Conference	I-MISC
of	I-MISC
the	I-MISC
Parties	I-MISC
to	I-MISC
the	I-MISC
Framework	I-MISC
Convention	I-MISC
,	O
to	O
be	O
held	O
later	O
this	O
year	O
in	O
Paris	I-LOC
.	O

For	O
Canada	I-LOC
,	O
an	O
effective	O
agreement	O
must	O
address	O
both	O
mitigation	O
and	O
adaptation	O
,	O
and	O
,	O
most	O
importantly	O
,	O
such	O
an	O
agreement	O
must	O
include	O
a	O
commitment	O
to	O
mitigation	O
actions	O
by	O
all	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
major	O
emitters	O
of	O
greenhouse	O
gases	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
an	O
ambitious	O
target	O
that	O
is	O
in	O
line	O
￼with	O
other	O
major	O
industrialized	O
countries	O
and	O
reflects	O
our	O
national	O
circumstances	O
,	O
including	O
Canada	I-LOC
's	O
position	O
as	O
a	O
world	O
leader	O
in	O
clean	O
electricity	O
generation	O
.	O

Canada	I-LOC
recognizes	O
that	O
financing	O
is	O
a	O
key	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
discussion	O
and	O
,	O
moving	O
forward	O
with	O
our	O
partners	O
,	O
we	O
will	O
,	O
as	O
we	O
have	O
done	O
in	O
the	O
past	O
,	O
continue	O
to	O
support	O
international	O
climate-change	O
financing	O
.	O

Canada	I-LOC
has	O
already	O
pledged	O
$300	O
million	O
to	O
the	O
Green	I-MISC
Climate	I-MISC
Fund	I-MISC
,	O
in	O
addition	O
to	O
a	O
previous	O
investment	O
of	O
$1.2	O
billion	O
that	O
we	O
provided	O
under	O
quick-start	O
climate-change	O
financing	O
,	O
which	O
has	O
supported	O
a	O
number	O
of	O
beneficial	O
projects	O
in	O
more	O
than	O
70	O
developing	O
countries	O
.	O

From	O
the	O
beginning	O
,	O
Canada	I-LOC
has	O
been	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
largest	O
and	O
most	O
reliable	O
financial	O
contributors	O
to	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

In	O
the	O
light	O
of	O
that	O
support	O
,	O
it	O
should	O
come	O
as	O
no	O
surprise	O
that	O
the	O
Government	O
of	O
Canada	I-LOC
and	O
Canadians	I-MISC
expect	O
that	O
money	O
to	O
be	O
spent	O
wisely	O
and	O
that	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
should	O
be	O
held	O
accountable	O
for	O
its	O
expenditures	O
.	O

As	O
I	O
said	O
at	O
the	O
outset	O
,	O
the	O
overarching	O
aims	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
since	O
its	O
creation	O
have	O
been	O
remarkably	O
consistent	O
,	O
namely	O
,	O
to	O
help	O
achieve	O
greater	O
prosperity	O
and	O
security	O
,	O
to	O
advance	O
mutual	O
respect	O
,	O
fairness	O
and	O
good	O
international	O
conduct	O
,	O
and	O
,	O
ultimately	O
,	O
to	O
inspire	O
and	O
sustain	O
the	O
hopes	O
of	O
people	O
everywhere	O
for	O
a	O
better	O
future	O
.	O

With	O
our	O
friends	O
and	O
partners	O
in	O
the	O
global	O
community	O
,	O
we	O
have	O
striven	O
to	O
make	O
this	O
world	O
a	O
better	O
place	O
and	O
to	O
make	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
a	O
better	O
instrument	O
for	O
achieving	O
those	O
goals	O
.	O

We	O
look	O
forward	O
to	O
working	O
together	O
with	O
other	O
nations	O
,	O
as	O
we	O
have	O
done	O
for	O
seven	O
decades	O
,	O
in	O
pursuit	O
of	O
that	O
common	O
purpose	O
.	O
