At	O
the	O
outset	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
a	O
great	O
pleasure	O
for	O
me	O
to	O
congratulate	O
the	O
President	O
on	O
his	O
election	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
a	O
sign	O
of	O
the	O
esteem	O
in	O
which	O
he	O
and	O
his	O
country	O
are	O
held	O
.	O

Coming	O
after	O
his	O
re-election	O
to	O
a	O
second	O
term	O
─	O
which	O
is	O
a	O
sign	O
of	O
the	O
general	O
confidence	O
he	O
has	O
earned	O
─	O
the	O
Nobel	I-MISC
Peace	I-MISC
Prize	I-MISC
that	O
has	O
been	O
awarded	O
to	O
the	O
Secretary-	O
General	O
is	O
a	O
well-deserved	O
tribute	O
to	O
his	O
work	O
and	O
,	O
through	O
him	O
,	O
to	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Organization	I-ORG
as	O
a	O
whole	O
,	O
thereby	O
inspiring	O
greater	O
hope	O
than	O
ever	O
before	O
.	O

On	O
this	O
my	O
third	O
visit	O
to	O
New	I-LOC
York	I-LOC
since	O
the	O
tragedy	O
of	O
11	O
September	O
,	O
I	O
also	O
want	O
to	O
express	O
once	O
again	O
my	O
profound	O
emotion	O
and	O
pay	O
homage	O
to	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
New	I-LOC
York	I-LOC
,	O
who	O
are	O
being	O
so	O
severely	O
tested	O
,	O
and	O
to	O
their	O
courageous	O
mayor	O
,	O
who	O
is	O
now	O
finishing	O
his	O
term	O
.	O

The	O
unprecedented	O
magnitude	O
and	O
gravity	O
of	O
the	O
terrorist	O
attacks	O
on	O
New	I-LOC
York	I-LOC
and	O
Washington	I-LOC
on	O
11	O
September	O
warrant	O
our	O
unfailing	O
solidarity	O
and	O
an	O
exceptional	O
response	O
.	O

In	O
its	O
resolution	O
1368	O
(2001)	O
,	O
which	O
was	O
adopted	O
unanimously	O
,	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
rightly	O
qualified	O
those	O
acts	O
as	O
attacks	O
and	O
,	O
hence	O
,	O
as	O
legitimately	O
meriting	O
a	O
defensive	O
response	O
under	O
Article	I-MISC
51	I-MISC
of	O
the	O
Charter	I-MISC
.	O

The	O
United	I-LOC
States	I-LOC
is	O
thus	O
entirely	O
within	O
its	O
legal	O
and	O
political	O
rights	O
in	O
carrying	O
out	O
its	O
targeted	O
military	O
response	O
against	O
the	O
terrorist	O
organizations	O
responsible	O
for	O
those	O
acts	O
.	O

The	O
military	O
action	O
under	O
way	O
was	O
therefore	O
inevitable	O
,	O
and	O
must	O
be	O
pursued	O
until	O
all	O
its	O
objectives	O
have	O
been	O
achieved	O
.	O

Given	O
the	O
preliminary	O
results	O
achieved	O
yesterday	O
,	O
I	O
hope	O
that	O
those	O
objectives	O
will	O
be	O
met	O
as	O
soon	O
as	O
possible	O
.	O

The	O
leaders	O
of	O
these	O
terrorist	O
networks	O
and	O
those	O
who	O
support	O
them	O
must	O
be	O
decisively	O
prevented	O
from	O
committing	O
further	O
harm	O
.	O

But	O
that	O
military	O
action	O
should	O
,	O
as	O
a	O
matter	O
of	O
course	O
,	O
form	O
part	O
of	O
an	O
overarching	O
strategy	O
that	O
includes	O
immediate	O
,	O
broad-scale	O
humanitarian	O
action	O
that	O
is	O
better	O
adapted	O
to	O
the	O
needs	O
of	O
people	O
in	O
distress	O
.	O

France	I-LOC
has	O
put	O
forward	O
several	O
proposals	O
in	O
this	O
regard	O
and	O
supports	O
the	O
current	O
initiatives	O
for	O
better	O
coordination	O
.	O

That	O
overarching	O
strategy	O
should	O
also	O
include	O
a	O
political	O
solution	O
—	O
something	O
that	O
has	O
now	O
become	O
urgent	O
—	O
and	O
strive	O
to	O
ensure	O
that	O
the	O
demise	O
of	O
the	O
Taliban	O
regime	O
does	O
not	O
lead	O
to	O
factional	O
infighting	O
and	O
chaos	O
;	O
and	O
it	O
must	O
once	O
again	O
make	O
the	O
Afghan	I-MISC
people	O
masters	O
of	O
their	O
own	O
future	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
the	O
aim	O
of	O
the	O
action	O
plan	O
for	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
that	O
France	I-LOC
proposed	O
back	O
on	O
1	O
October	O
,	O
and	O
of	O
the	O
other	O
contributions	O
it	O
has	O
made	O
with	O
the	O
same	O
goals	O
in	O
mind	O
.	O

We	O
await	O
Mr.	O
Lakhdar	I-PER
Brahimi	I-PER
's	O
proposals	O
with	O
interest	O
;	O
they	O
should	O
set	O
forth	O
broad	O
outlines	O
of	O
action	O
for	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

There	O
is	O
no	O
question	O
of	O
imposing	O
on	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
some	O
ready-made	O
solution	O
concocted	O
by	O
outsiders	O
.	O

I	O
call	O
on	O
all	O
the	O
constituents	O
of	O
the	O
Afghan	I-MISC
nation	O
and	O
all	O
neighbouring	O
countries	O
to	O
heed	O
the	O
general	O
interest	O
of	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
and	O
its	O
people	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
compatible	O
with	O
respect	O
for	O
the	O
legitimate	O
interests	O
of	O
the	O
various	O
parties	O
concerned	O
and	O
it	O
is	O
the	O
only	O
way	O
to	O
turn	O
our	O
backs	O
on	O
the	O
past	O
.	O

Beyond	O
immediate	O
military	O
,	O
diplomatic	O
and	O
humanitarian	O
action	O
,	O
our	O
common	O
fight	O
against	O
terrorism	O
needs	O
to	O
be	O
pursued	O
in	O
all	O
its	O
forms	O
,	O
including	O
police	O
,	O
judicial	O
and	O
others	O
.	O

The	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
will	O
have	O
a	O
crucial	O
role	O
to	O
play	O
in	O
this	O
difficult	O
struggle	O
,	O
laying	O
down	O
universal	O
obligations	O
for	O
each	O
State	O
and	O
the	O
framework	O
for	O
our	O
action	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
speed	O
up	O
the	O
signature	O
and	O
ratification	O
of	O
those	O
conventions	O
.	O

The	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
must	O
quickly	O
conclude	O
the	O
negotiations	O
on	O
the	O
comprehensive	O
convention	O
on	O
international	O
terrorism	O
.	O

For	O
its	O
part	O
,	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
should	O
oversee	O
the	O
coordinated	O
implementation	O
by	O
States	O
of	O
its	O
resolution	O
1373	O
(2001)	O
.	O

Action	O
against	O
terrorism	O
also	O
needs	O
to	O
be	O
carried	O
out	O
through	O
other	O
organizations	O
,	O
in	O
conjunction	O
with	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
and	O
consistent	O
with	O
its	O
policies	O
.	O

For	O
its	O
part	O
,	O
the	O
European	I-ORG
Union	I-ORG
(EU)	O
has	O
just	O
taken	O
unprecedented	O
steps	O
to	O
strengthen	O
police	O
and	O
judicial	O
cooperation	O
among	O
its	O
member	O
States	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
creation	O
of	O
a	O
European	I-MISC
arrest	O
warrant	O
.	O

An	O
ambitious	O
action	O
plan	O
has	O
been	O
agreed	O
.	O

The	O
29	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
Financial	I-ORG
Action	I-ORG
Task	I-ORG
Force	I-ORG
(FATF)	I-ORG
have	O
decided	O
to	O
extend	O
the	O
fight	O
against	O
money-	O
laundering	O
to	O
the	O
fight	O
against	O
the	O
financing	O
of	O
terrorism	O
.	O

Beyond	O
that	O
,	O
I	O
propose	O
the	O
creation	O
of	O
a	O
dialogue	O
forum	O
to	O
move	O
us	O
in	O
this	O
direction	O
.	O

Several	O
other	O
organizations	O
,	O
too	O
,	O
will	O
have	O
a	O
role	O
to	O
play	O
,	O
so	O
that	O
at	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
the	O
day	O
every	O
country	O
will	O
be	O
making	O
a	O
contribution	O
.	O

Leaving	O
aside	O
the	O
hoped-for	O
short-term	O
results	O
,	O
the	O
obstacles	O
notwithstanding	O
,	O
we	O
will	O
not	O
achieve	O
lasting	O
victory	O
against	O
all	O
forms	O
of	O
terrorism	O
unless	O
we	O
succeed	O
in	O
depriving	O
terrorists	O
of	O
their	O
breeding	O
ground	O
and	O
eliminating	O
the	O
pretexts	O
from	O
which	O
they	O
fallaciously	O
draw	O
their	O
justification	O
,	O
and	O
unless	O
we	O
eradicate	O
them	O
in	O
the	O
true	O
sense	O
of	O
the	O
term	O
.	O

That	O
implies	O
nothing	O
short	O
of	O
changing	O
our	O
world	O
.	O

And	O
let	O
no	O
one	O
claim	O
that	O
this	O
would	O
be	O
tantamount	O
to	O
justifying	O
the	O
terrorists	O
.	O

For	O
neither	O
my	O
country	O
,	O
nor	O
Europe	I-LOC
,	O
nor	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
—	O
in	O
other	O
words	O
,	O
none	O
of	O
us	O
—	O
waited	O
for	O
11	O
September	O
to	O
discover	O
,	O
condemn	O
and	O
seek	O
to	O
remedy	O
the	O
ills	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

Yet	O
how	O
many	O
good	O
intentions	O
have	O
come	O
to	O
naught	O
?	O

How	O
many	O
resolutions	O
have	O
gone	O
unimplemented	O
?	O

How	O
many	O
announcements	O
have	O
failed	O
to	O
materialize	O
,	O
which	O
now	O
feed	O
a	O
sense	O
of	O
bitterness	O
and	O
incomprehension	O
?	O

It	O
is	O
pointless	O
to	O
condemn	O
or	O
deny	O
the	O
theory	O
of	O
a	O
clash	O
of	O
civilizations	O
.	O

Rather	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
fight	O
against	O
such	O
a	O
risk	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
by	O
no	O
means	O
wholly	O
imaginary	O
,	O
and	O
against	O
those	O
who	O
would	O
make	O
it	O
a	O
reality	O
.	O

This	O
should	O
be	O
one	O
more	O
pressing	O
reason	O
for	O
us	O
all	O
to	O
find	O
a	O
solution	O
to	O
regional	O
crises	O
,	O
particularly	O
in	O
the	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
.	O

Since	O
1982	O
,	O
France	I-LOC
has	O
called	O
for	O
the	O
creation	O
of	O
a	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
State	O
.	O

Naturally	O
,	O
it	O
would	O
have	O
to	O
be	O
viable	O
,	O
democratic	O
and	O
peaceful	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
should	O
give	O
credible	O
undertakings	O
as	O
regards	O
Israel	I-LOC
's	O
security	O
.	O

Guarantees	O
will	O
be	O
needed	O
,	O
yet	O
the	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
State	O
is	O
not	O
the	O
problem	O
;	O
it	O
is	O
the	O
solution	O
for	O
reasons	O
based	O
on	O
rights	O
,	O
humanity	O
and	O
security	O
.	O

Such	O
is	O
the	O
EU	I-ORG
's	O
common	O
stance	O
today	O
.	O

This	O
morning	O
,	O
before	O
the	O
Assembly	I-ORG
,	O
President	O
Bush	I-PER
himself	O
has	O
made	O
this	O
his	O
objective	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
the	O
path	O
of	O
reason	O
—	O
the	O
only	O
path	O
that	O
can	O
halt	O
the	O
murderous	O
spiral	O
of	O
conflict	O
between	O
the	O
two	O
peoples	O
.	O

Admittedly	O
,	O
responsibility	O
for	O
a	O
lasting	O
peace	O
agreement	O
lies	O
first	O
and	O
foremost	O
with	O
the	O
protagonists	O
.	O

Unless	O
they	O
make	O
the	O
move	O
,	O
no	O
one	O
else	O
will	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
overcome	O
their	O
fears	O
and	O
resentment	O
and	O
put	O
an	O
end	O
to	O
the	O
suffering	O
of	O
these	O
two	O
peoples	O
.	O

Yet	O
,	O
the	O
increasing	O
threat	O
that	O
this	O
conflict	O
poses	O
to	O
international	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
requires	O
that	O
those	O
who	O
have	O
the	O
will	O
and	O
the	O
means	O
join	O
forces	O
in	O
a	O
push	O
for	O
peace	O
,	O
given	O
that	O
the	O
main	O
players	O
are	O
evidently	O
unable	O
to	O
do	O
so	O
unaided	O
.	O

The	O
urgency	O
of	O
the	O
situation	O
in	O
the	O
Near	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
obviously	O
should	O
not	O
make	O
us	O
forget	O
Iraq	I-LOC
.	O

Regional	O
security	O
still	O
needs	O
to	O
be	O
secured	O
by	O
restoring	O
an	O
international	O
monitoring	O
capability	O
and	O
by	O
alleviating	O
the	O
suffering	O
of	O
the	O
Iraqi	I-MISC
people	O
through	O
the	O
lifting	O
of	O
the	O
embargo	O
on	O
civilian	O
goods	O
.	O

I	O
hope	O
the	O
discussions	O
now	O
in	O
progress	O
in	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
will	O
finally	O
bring	O
this	O
about	O
.	O

Nor	O
should	O
we	O
forget	O
the	O
Caucasus	I-LOC
,	O
where	O
ancient	O
quarrels	O
live	O
on	O
and	O
where	O
new	O
ones	O
are	O
rising	O
to	O
the	O
fore	O
.	O

Yet	O
,	O
here	O
again	O
there	O
is	O
no	O
other	O
way	O
than	O
to	O
seek	O
negotiated	O
political	O
solutions	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
Balkans	I-LOC
,	O
we	O
realized	O
that	O
international	O
involvement	O
must	O
be	O
sustainable	O
.	O

Thanks	O
to	O
it	O
,	O
and	O
thanks	O
to	O
new	O
leaders	O
,	O
noteworthy	O
progress	O
has	O
been	O
achieved	O
towards	O
democracy	O
,	O
reconciliation	O
and	O
regional	O
cooperation	O
over	O
the	O
last	O
two	O
years	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
make	O
sure	O
these	O
positive	O
changes	O
are	O
not	O
challenged	O
by	O
outmoded	O
patterns	O
of	O
behaviour	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
maintain	O
and	O
pursue	O
the	O
Europeanization	I-MISC
of	O
the	O
Balkans	I-LOC
.	O

Turning	O
to	O
the	O
Great	I-LOC
Lakes	I-LOC
region	O
,	O
we	O
know	O
that	O
the	O
lasting	O
resolution	O
of	O
the	O
conflict	O
,	O
which	O
involves	O
more	O
than	O
eight	O
countries	O
,	O
will	O
be	O
a	O
negotiated	O
solution	O
that	O
will	O
ensure	O
the	O
restoration	O
of	O
the	O
sovereignty	O
of	O
the	O
Democratic	I-LOC
Republic	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
the	I-LOC
Congo	I-LOC
and	O
include	O
as	O
well	O
safeguard	O
clauses	O
to	O
protect	O
the	O
security	O
of	O
each	O
of	O
the	O
States	O
.	O

The	O
Lusaka	I-LOC
Agreement	I-MISC
and	O
the	O
relevant	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
resolutions	O
provide	O
the	O
framework	O
for	O
ending	O
this	O
crisis	O
,	O
but	O
they	O
should	O
be	O
applied	O
as	O
quickly	O
as	O
possible	O
.	O

To	O
halt	O
the	O
illegal	O
use	O
of	O
the	O
resources	O
of	O
the	O
Democratic	I-LOC
Republic	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
the	I-LOC
Congo	I-LOC
,	O
which	O
often	O
occurs	O
in	O
association	O
with	O
forced	O
child	O
labour	O
,	O
should	O
be	O
an	O
immediate	O
priority	O
.	O

In	O
all	O
the	O
cases	O
I	O
have	O
just	O
referred	O
to	O
briefly	O
—	O
and	O
there	O
are	O
others	O
—	O
the	O
problem	O
we	O
have	O
to	O
resolve	O
is	O
the	O
coexistence	O
of	O
peoples	O
who	O
are	O
at	O
once	O
close	O
and	O
antagonistic	O
,	O
deeply	O
affected	O
and	O
divided	O
by	O
history	O
and	O
separated	O
by	O
fear	O
and	O
the	O
spirit	O
of	O
revenge	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
achieve	O
this	O
only	O
through	O
perseverance	O
and	O
a	O
clear	O
understanding	O
of	O
each	O
particular	O
situation	O
,	O
guided	O
by	O
the	O
principles	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

Even	O
if	O
we	O
managed	O
to	O
resolve	O
all	O
these	O
regional	O
crises	O
and	O
others	O
as	O
well	O
,	O
our	O
task	O
would	O
still	O
not	O
be	O
over	O
because	O
,	O
at	O
the	O
global	O
level	O
,	O
the	O
gulf	O
between	O
intentions	O
for	O
the	O
world	O
as	O
stated	O
at	O
international	O
meetings	O
and	O
actual	O
realities	O
is	O
becoming	O
intolerable	O
for	O
many	O
peoples	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
redouble	O
our	O
efforts	O
to	O
create	O
humane	O
globalization	O
.	O

We	O
saw	O
this	O
in	O
Seattle	I-LOC
,	O
we	O
saw	O
it	O
in	O
Genoa	I-LOC
,	O
and	O
even	O
more	O
so	O
in	O
Durban	I-LOC
.	O

We	O
can	O
see	O
it	O
in	O
the	O
reactions	O
to	O
the	O
Afghan	I-MISC
crisis	O
and	O
to	O
many	O
other	O
issues	O
.	O

Despite	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
and	O
our	O
good	O
resolutions	O
,	O
there	O
is	O
still	O
no	O
real	O
universal	O
consensus	O
.	O

What	O
we	O
call	O
"	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
"	O
has	O
yet	O
to	O
be	O
built	O
.	O

Is	O
this	O
a	O
reason	O
to	O
throw	O
in	O
the	O
towel	O
?	O

To	O
the	O
contrary	O
–	O
absolutely	O
not	O
.	O

France	I-LOC
has	O
long	O
been	O
determined	O
to	O
add	O
its	O
stone	O
to	O
this	O
edifice	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
already	O
put	O
forward	O
numerous	O
proposals	O
to	O
that	O
end	O
and	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
do	O
so	O
,	O
with	O
increased	O
conviction	O
.	O

Need	O
I	O
recall	O
our	O
well-known	O
major	O
objectives	O
for	O
the	O
world	O
?	O

First	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
achieve	O
a	O
fairer	O
distribution	O
of	O
wealth	O
;	O
3	O
billion	O
people	O
currently	O
live	O
on	O
less	O
than	O
2	O
dollars	O
per	O
day	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
global	O
income	O
gap	O
between	O
the	O
richest	O
and	O
the	O
poorest	O
has	O
doubled	O
over	O
the	O
last	O
40	O
years	O
.	O

Second	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
end	O
impunity	O
.	O

Third	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
guarantee	O
sustainable	O
development	O
everywhere	O
—	O
"	O
sustainable	O
"	O
,	O
that	O
little	O
word	O
that	O
makes	O
all	O
the	O
difference	O
,	O
or	O
which	O
should	O
make	O
all	O
the	O
difference	O
.	O

The	O
World	I-MISC
Summit	I-MISC
in	O
Johannesburg	I-LOC
in	O
September	O
2002	O
will	O
provide	O
an	O
opportunity	O
to	O
affirm	O
a	O
vision	O
and	O
a	O
benchmark	O
of	O
development	O
based	O
on	O
three	O
intimately	O
linked	O
pillars:	O
economic	O
,	O
social	O
and	O
environmental	O
.	O

Fourth	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
help	O
refugees	O
and	O
fully	O
respect	O
the	O
right	O
of	O
asylum	O
.	O

Fifth	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
manage	O
population	O
movements	O
in	O
a	O
humanitarian	O
manner	O
.	O

Sixth	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
draft	O
international	O
standards	O
in	O
a	O
democratic	O
way	O
to	O
ensure	O
that	O
they	O
are	O
entirely	O
legitimate	O
and	O
that	O
everyone	O
will	O
consequently	O
be	O
bound	O
to	O
comply	O
with	O
them	O
.	O

Seventh	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
no	O
longer	O
tolerate	O
situations	O
of	O
human	O
distress	O
.	O

State	O
sovereignty	O
,	O
which	O
remains	O
an	O
essential	O
feature	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
system	O
,	O
cannot	O
,	O
in	O
extreme	O
emergencies	O
,	O
be	O
regarded	O
as	O
an	O
absolute	O
principle	O
serving	O
as	O
a	O
pretext	O
for	O
inaction	O
.	O

The	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
must	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
fully	O
assume	O
its	O
responsibilities	O
in	O
cases	O
of	O
gross	O
human	O
rights	O
violations	O
,	O
for	O
these	O
also	O
pose	O
threats	O
to	O
international	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
.	O

Eighth	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
aim	O
at	O
promoting	O
balanced	O
and	O
negotiated	O
disarmament	O
,	O
which	O
strengthens	O
security	O
and	O
strategic	O
stability	O
.	O

Ninth	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
strive	O
to	O
allow	O
all	O
languages	O
,	O
cultures	O
and	O
civilizations	O
to	O
exist	O
while	O
maintaining	O
a	O
dialogue	O
with	O
one	O
another	O
.	O

Tenth	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
seek	O
to	O
improve	O
the	O
state	O
of	O
health	O
worldwide	O
,	O
which	O
for	O
one	O
thing	O
means	O
devoting	O
more	O
resources	O
to	O
combating	O
HIV/AIDS	I-MISC
.	O

I	O
would	O
hope	O
that	O
the	O
new	O
Global	I-MISC
AIDS	I-MISC
and	I-MISC
Health	I-MISC
Fund	I-MISC
will	O
be	O
made	O
operational	O
by	O
the	O
beginning	O
of	O
2002	O
.	O

But	O
we	O
are	O
undoubtedly	O
now	O
more	O
aware	O
than	O
in	O
recent	O
years	O
that	O
the	O
attainment	O
of	O
these	O
objectives	O
,	O
which	O
are	O
both	O
indispensable	O
,	O
and	O
very	O
ambitious	O
,	O
calls	O
different	O
rules	O
and	O
different	O
mechanisms	O
,	O
starting	O
with	O
the	O
reform	O
and	O
enlargement	O
of	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
,	O
which	O
we	O
have	O
waited	O
for	O
all	O
too	O
long	O
;	O
with	O
respect	O
for	O
the	O
role	O
of	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
;	O
with	O
the	O
ratification	O
of	O
the	O
major	O
multilateral	O
instruments	O
—	O
I	O
am	O
thinking	O
of	O
the	O
Statute	I-MISC
of	O
the	O
International	I-MISC
Criminal	I-MISC
Court	I-MISC
and	O
the	O
Kyoto	I-MISC
Protocol	I-MISC
,	O
among	O
others	O
;	O
with	O
a	O
more	O
appropriate	O
and	O
less	O
indiscriminate	O
use	O
of	O
sanctions	O
when	O
they	O
are	O
needed	O
;	O
with	O
a	O
clarification	O
of	O
the	O
respective	O
and	O
legitimate	O
roles	O
of	O
Governments	O
and	O
civil	O
society	O
;	O
with	O
an	O
agreement	O
on	O
the	O
modalities	O
of	O
interference	O
to	O
deal	O
with	O
large-scale	O
and	O
extreme	O
emergency	O
situations	O
;	O
with	O
a	O
regulation	O
and	O
development	O
round	O
at	O
the	O
World	I-ORG
Trade	I-ORG
Organization	I-ORG
(WTO)	I-ORG
,	O
which	O
is	O
starting	O
today	O
in	O
Doha	I-LOC
;	O
with	O
closer	O
cooperation	O
and	O
greater	O
consistency	O
between	O
the	O
WTO	I-ORG
and	O
the	O
International	I-ORG
Labour	I-ORG
Organization	I-ORG
;	O
with	O
the	O
creation	O
of	O
a	O
world	O
environmental	O
organization	O
;	O
and	O
with	O
reform	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
financial	O
institutions	O
.	O

I	O
shall	O
stop	O
this	O
list	O
here	O
.	O

I	O
could	O
go	O
on	O
,	O
for	O
there	O
is	O
so	O
much	O
that	O
remains	O
to	O
be	O
done	O
.	O

All	O
of	O
us	O
,	O
as	O
Members	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
are	O
faced	O
with	O
this	O
challenge	O
.	O

Now	O
that	O
the	O
illusions	O
of	O
the	O
last	O
10	O
years	O
have	O
been	O
dispelled	O
,	O
the	O
choice	O
before	O
us	O
is	O
harsh	O
,	O
but	O
clear:	O
either	O
a	O
world	O
so	O
unjust	O
that	O
we	O
have	O
conflict	O
with	O
no	O
foreseeable	O
end	O
,	O
or	O
,	O
on	O
the	O
contrary	O
,	O
an	O
international	O
community	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
at	O
last	O
worthy	O
of	O
the	O
name	O
,	O
to	O
solve	O
together	O
humanity	O
's	O
common	O
problems	O
and	O
ensure	O
its	O
future	O
.	O

But	O
building	O
this	O
community	O
,	O
instead	O
of	O
just	O
talking	O
about	O
it	O
or	O
yearning	O
for	O
it	O
,	O
will	O
mean	O
for	O
some	O
of	O
us	O
giving	O
up	O
privileges	O
,	O
sharing	O
wealth	O
and	O
power	O
in	O
new	O
ways	O
,	O
and	O
rewriting	O
certain	O
rules	O
hitherto	O
held	O
to	O
be	O
inviolable	O
.	O

As	O
the	O
Nobel	I-MISC
Prize-winning	O
economist	O
Joseph	I-PER
Stiglitz	I-PER
has	O
written	O
,	O
free	O
trade	O
was	O
designed	O
by	O
Western	I-MISC
countries	O
for	O
the	O
Western	I-MISC
countries	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
debatable	O
,	O
of	O
course	O
,	O
but	O
none	O
of	O
this	O
will	O
happen	O
without	O
sacrifices	O
,	O
above	O
all	O
on	O
the	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
rich	O
and	O
powerful	O
countries	O
.	O

I	O
hope	O
—	O
I	O
truly	O
hope	O
—	O
that	O
this	O
will	O
help	O
to	O
bring	O
about	O
a	O
vital	O
awakening	O
and	O
that	O
my	O
country	O
,	O
Europe	I-LOC
and	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
will	O
follow	O
new	O
avenues	O
,	O
in	O
deeds	O
and	O
not	O
just	O
words	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
all	O
of	O
us	O
,	O
together	O
,	O
will	O
successfully	O
extend	O
the	O
needed	O
coalition	O
against	O
terrorism	O
to	O
turn	O
it	O
into	O
a	O
coalition	O
for	O
an	O
equitable	O
world	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
this	O
will	O
lay	O
the	O
groundwork	O
for	O
a	O
renewal	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
system	O
.	O
