I	O
also	O
wish	O
to	O
take	O
this	O
opportunity	O
to	O
commend	O
his	O
predecessor	O
for	O
his	O
invaluable	O
contribution	O
to	O
what	O
was	O
achieved	O
at	O
the	O
fifty-sixth	O
session	O
of	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
.	O

Allow	O
me	O
also	O
to	O
express	O
our	O
appreciation	O
to	O
our	O
Secretary-General	O
,	O
Mr.	O
Kofi	I-PER
Annan	I-PER
,	O
for	O
the	O
effort	O
he	O
has	O
been	O
making	O
to	O
ensure	O
that	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
becomes	O
a	O
more	O
effective	O
instrument	O
for	O
tackling	O
the	O
very	O
many	O
challenges	O
faced	O
by	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
.	O

My	O
delegation	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
join	O
others	O
in	O
welcoming	O
the	O
admission	O
of	O
the	O
Swiss	I-LOC
Confederation	I-LOC
to	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

It	O
is	O
a	O
country	O
that	O
has	O
,	O
indeed	O
,	O
contributed	O
so	O
much	O
to	O
the	O
Organization	I-ORG
over	O
the	O
years	O
.	O

Our	O
continent	O
,	O
Africa	I-LOC
,	O
and	O
its	O
peoples	O
,	O
continue	O
to	O
face	O
enormous	O
and	O
daunting	O
challenges	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
not	O
new	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
something	O
that	O
has	O
been	O
going	O
on	O
for	O
the	O
last	O
few	O
decades	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
general	O
economic	O
and	O
social	O
situation	O
in	O
the	O
continent	O
deteriorating	O
even	O
further	O
.	O

The	O
general	O
trend	O
has	O
been	O
one	O
of	O
an	O
ever-faster	O
marginalization	O
of	O
Africa	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
continent	O
has	O
yet	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
benefits	O
of	O
globalization	O
.	O

Africa	I-LOC
still	O
awaits	O
the	O
creation	O
of	O
an	O
enabling	O
international	O
economic	O
context	O
for	O
progress	O
in	O
its	O
efforts	O
to	O
wage	O
war	O
against	O
poverty	O
.	O

That	O
effort	O
is	O
unlikely	O
to	O
succeed	O
without	O
greater	O
international	O
cooperation	O
.	O

The	O
eradication	O
of	O
poverty	O
is	O
not	O
only	O
Africa	I-LOC
's	O
challenge	O
or	O
only	O
that	O
of	O
the	O
developing	O
world	O
.	O

As	O
was	O
reiterated	O
at	O
the	O
Johannesburg	I-LOC
World	I-MISC
Summit	I-MISC
on	I-MISC
Sustainable	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
,	O
poverty	O
is	O
the	O
greatest	O
global	O
challenge	O
facing	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

The	O
despair	O
and	O
hopelessness	O
engendered	O
by	O
poverty	O
have	O
implications	O
for	O
the	O
world	O
in	O
general	O
—	O
not	O
only	O
for	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
the	O
South	O
but	O
for	O
those	O
of	O
the	O
North	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
.	O

Many	O
might	O
have	O
felt	O
that	O
the	O
Johannesburg	I-LOC
Summit	I-MISC
failed	O
to	O
rise	O
to	O
the	O
occasion	O
and	O
that	O
its	O
achievement	O
was	O
not	O
commensurate	O
with	O
the	O
gravity	O
of	O
the	O
challenges	O
faced	O
by	O
the	O
peoples	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
in	O
a	O
variety	O
of	O
areas	O
,	O
most	O
of	O
all	O
,	O
in	O
areas	O
most	O
relevant	O
to	O
the	O
eradication	O
of	O
poverty	O
.	O

But	O
there	O
was	O
one	O
thing	O
which	O
was	O
unambiguously	O
evident	O
at	O
the	O
Johannesburg	I-LOC
Summit	I-MISC
.	O

Those	O
from	O
both	O
the	O
North	O
and	O
the	O
South	O
stressed	O
with	O
one	O
voice	O
that	O
the	O
global	O
apartheid	O
we	O
currently	O
have	O
is	O
unsustainable	O
.	O

How	O
can	O
one	O
implement	O
that	O
vision	O
?	O

This	O
is	O
what	O
continues	O
to	O
elude	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
.	O

It	O
remains	O
the	O
case	O
despite	O
some	O
progress	O
that	O
has	O
been	O
made	O
,	O
including	O
at	O
Monterrey	I-LOC
.	O

It	O
is	O
primarily	O
our	O
responsibility	O
to	O
put	O
our	O
houses	O
in	O
order	O
and	O
to	O
take	O
the	O
lead	O
in	O
rejuvenating	O
Africa	I-LOC
.	O

That	O
is	O
where	O
in	O
fact	O
today	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
new	O
development	O
in	O
Africa	I-LOC
.	O

Many	O
in	O
Africa	I-LOC
are	O
more	O
prepared	O
than	O
ever	O
before	O
to	O
take	O
charge	O
of	O
their	O
destiny	O
.	O

There	O
is	O
a	O
new	O
thinking	O
in	O
Africa	I-LOC
today	O
and	O
a	O
realistic	O
resolve	O
to	O
ensure	O
the	O
regeneration	O
of	O
the	O
continent	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
an	O
initiative	O
by	O
Africa	I-LOC
which	O
demonstrates	O
the	O
readiness	O
of	O
the	O
continent	O
to	O
take	O
charge	O
of	O
its	O
future	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
a	O
concrete	O
commitment	O
by	O
Africa	I-LOC
to	O
take	O
the	O
necessary	O
steps	O
in	O
both	O
the	O
economic	O
and	O
political	O
areas	O
towards	O
creating	O
enabling	O
conditions	O
for	O
economic	O
and	O
social	O
transformation	O
.	O

Good	O
governance	O
is	O
one	O
such	O
vital	O
obligation	O
to	O
which	O
the	O
initiative	O
accords	O
the	O
necessary	O
importance	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
a	O
major	O
step	O
for	O
Africa	I-LOC
and	O
one	O
whose	O
significance	O
should	O
be	O
underlined	O
.	O

The	O
commitment	O
to	O
democracy	O
and	O
good	O
governance	O
has	O
major	O
implications	O
for	O
Africa	I-LOC
not	O
only	O
in	O
economic	O
development	O
but	O
also	O
in	O
creating	O
conditions	O
for	O
nurturing	O
peace	O
and	O
stability	O
.	O

Nonetheless	O
,	O
NEPAD	I-MISC
cannot	O
succeed	O
without	O
the	O
cooperation	O
of	O
Africa	I-LOC
's	O
partners	O
and	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
.	O

And	O
succeed	O
it	O
must	O
,	O
not	O
only	O
because	O
NEPAD	I-MISC
's	O
success	O
is	O
in	O
the	O
vital	O
interest	O
of	O
Africa	I-LOC
but	O
also	O
because	O
it	O
is	O
in	O
the	O
interest	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
in	O
general	O
.	O

The	O
logic	O
of	O
globalization	O
makes	O
it	O
obvious	O
that	O
no	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
globe	O
is	O
immune	O
to	O
the	O
negative	O
influences	O
emanating	O
from	O
its	O
other	O
,	O
less	O
fortunate	O
parts	O
.	O

Realistically	O
speaking	O
,	O
we	O
swim	O
or	O
sink	O
together	O
.	O

It	O
would	O
be	O
unwise	O
to	O
believe	O
that	O
the	O
growing	O
marginalization	O
and	O
decay	O
of	O
Africa	I-LOC
will	O
have	O
no	O
significant	O
adverse	O
implications	O
for	O
the	O
stability	O
and	O
viability	O
of	O
the	O
globalizing	O
world	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
this	O
common	O
interest	O
that	O
we	O
all	O
share	O
which	O
is	O
the	O
basis	O
for	O
our	O
mutual	O
obligation	O
for	O
the	O
success	O
of	O
NEPAD	I-MISC
.	O

I	O
must	O
state	O
here	O
that	O
we	O
have	O
been	O
encouraged	O
by	O
the	O
preliminary	O
response	O
to	O
NEPAD	I-MISC
by	O
many	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
G-8	O
countries	O
and	O
others	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
still	O
hopeful	O
that	O
even	O
greater	O
support	O
and	O
enthusiasm	O
will	O
be	O
demonstrated	O
by	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
to	O
ensure	O
that	O
NEPAD	I-MISC
will	O
be	O
workable	O
.	O

Ethiopia	I-LOC
subscribes	O
fully	O
to	O
the	O
NEPAD	I-MISC
framework	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
indeed	O
at	O
present	O
in	O
the	O
process	O
of	O
implementing	O
the	O
principles	O
and	O
ideas	O
promoted	O
by	O
the	O
initiative	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
be	O
committed	O
to	O
carrying	O
out	O
our	O
obligations	O
for	O
good	O
governance	O
,	O
for	O
creating	O
enabling	O
conditions	O
for	O
economic	O
development	O
and	O
for	O
eradicating	O
poverty	O
.	O

All	O
the	O
efforts	O
we	O
are	O
making	O
to	O
ensure	O
success	O
in	O
the	O
fight	O
against	O
poverty	O
are	O
bound	O
to	O
fail	O
without	O
peace	O
and	O
durable	O
stability	O
.	O

Here	O
as	O
well	O
,	O
Africa	I-LOC
,	O
including	O
our	O
subregion	O
,	O
the	O
Horn	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
Africa	I-LOC
,	O
requires	O
the	O
effective	O
support	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
.	O

What	O
we	O
need	O
is	O
enlightened	O
support	O
which	O
is	O
transparent	O
and	O
targeted	O
at	O
ensuring	O
durable	O
peace	O
and	O
stability	O
.	O

What	O
we	O
require	O
is	O
support	O
not	O
compromised	O
by	O
tactical	O
considerations	O
which	O
are	O
short-sighted	O
and	O
likely	O
to	O
aggravate	O
already	O
existing	O
problems	O
.	O

Coddling	O
unaccountable	O
Governments	O
would	O
not	O
promote	O
peace	O
in	O
the	O
long	O
run	O
and	O
would	O
not	O
bring	O
about	O
durable	O
stability	O
.	O

Ours	O
is	O
a	O
region	O
which	O
has	O
suffered	O
so	O
much	O
,	O
among	O
other	O
things	O
because	O
of	O
strategic	O
considerations	O
which	O
made	O
expedient	O
the	O
propping	O
up	O
of	O
unaccountable	O
and	O
authoritarian	O
regimes	O
.	O

The	O
result	O
of	O
all	O
that	O
has	O
been	O
disastrous	O
for	O
the	O
region	O
.	O

Peace	O
and	O
stability	O
in	O
the	O
Horn	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
Africa	I-LOC
,	O
as	O
is	O
true	O
in	O
all	O
parts	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
,	O
is	O
dependent	O
in	O
a	O
critical	O
manner	O
on	O
the	O
creation	O
of	O
conditions	O
for	O
good	O
governance	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
a	O
value	O
which	O
ought	O
to	O
be	O
universally	O
applied	O
,	O
including	O
in	O
our	O
subregion	O
.	O

Durable	O
peace	O
demands	O
it	O
.	O

The	O
welfare	O
of	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
our	O
subregion	O
makes	O
it	O
imperative	O
.	O

Ethiopia	I-LOC
will	O
leave	O
no	O
stone	O
unturned	O
for	O
peace	O
in	O
our	O
subregion	O
and	O
in	O
Africa	I-LOC
as	O
a	O
whole	O
.	O

The	O
effort	O
we	O
have	O
been	O
making	O
for	O
peace	O
in	O
Somalia	I-LOC
within	O
the	O
framework	O
of	O
the	O
Intergovernmental	I-MISC
Authority	I-MISC
on	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
is	O
being	O
made	O
in	O
that	O
spirit	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
also	O
in	O
that	O
same	O
spirit	O
that	O
we	O
shall	O
continue	O
to	O
do	O
our	O
share	O
for	O
peace	O
and	O
national	O
reconciliation	O
in	O
the	O
Sudan	I-LOC
.	O

Most	O
of	O
all	O
,	O
we	O
draw	O
satisfaction	O
from	O
the	O
fact	O
that	O
we	O
have	O
managed	O
to	O
come	O
out	O
of	O
a	O
war	O
that	O
was	O
imposed	O
on	O
us	O
.	O

For	O
our	O
part	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
determined	O
to	O
leave	O
behind	O
the	O
crisis	O
we	O
had	O
with	O
Eritrea	I-LOC
.	O

We	O
shall	O
remain	O
committed	O
to	O
the	O
peace	O
process	O
until	O
its	O
conclusion	O
.	O

It	O
has	O
always	O
been	O
our	O
conviction	O
that	O
it	O
is	O
in	O
the	O
vital	O
interest	O
of	O
Ethiopia	I-LOC
to	O
nurture	O
peace	O
in	O
our	O
subregion	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
required	O
by	O
the	O
war	O
we	O
have	O
to	O
wage	O
against	O
poverty	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
the	O
only	O
real	O
enemy	O
we	O
have	O
.	O

But	O
the	O
promotion	O
of	O
the	O
cause	O
of	O
peace	O
in	O
the	O
Horn	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
Africa	I-LOC
has	O
not	O
been	O
that	O
easy	O
.	O

Our	O
subregion	O
is	O
an	O
area	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
that	O
has	O
long	O
been	O
vulnerable	O
to	O
terrorist	O
activities	O
.	O

Ours	O
has	O
been	O
an	O
area	O
that	O
,	O
due	O
in	O
part	O
to	O
the	O
prevalence	O
of	O
poverty	O
,	O
has	O
been	O
taken	O
advantage	O
of	O
very	O
recklessly	O
.	O

My	O
own	O
country	O
has	O
been	O
among	O
those	O
to	O
have	O
suffered	O
as	O
a	O
result	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
a	O
challenge	O
that	O
we	O
still	O
have	O
to	O
contend	O
with	O
,	O
and	O
which	O
we	O
still	O
continue	O
to	O
face	O
.	O

As	O
we	O
mark	O
the	O
first	O
anniversary	O
of	O
that	O
evil	O
deed	O
,	O
we	O
wish	O
once	O
again	O
to	O
express	O
our	O
solidarity	O
with	O
the	O
United	I-LOC
States	I-LOC
and	O
its	O
people	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
our	O
conviction	O
that	O
success	O
in	O
the	O
fight	O
against	O
international	O
terrorism	O
requires	O
the	O
genuine	O
cooperation	O
and	O
solidarity	O
of	O
the	O
entire	O
international	O
community	O
,	O
no	O
matter	O
who	O
might	O
be	O
the	O
target	O
of	O
such	O
terrorism	O
.	O

All	O
those	O
who	O
directly	O
or	O
indirectly	O
support	O
and	O
encourage	O
terrorism	O
should	O
be	O
held	O
accountable	O
.	O

Resources	O
made	O
available	O
to	O
terrorist	O
groups	O
,	O
in	O
whatever	O
guise	O
,	O
should	O
not	O
be	O
tolerated	O
regardless	O
of	O
the	O
area	O
where	O
this	O
is	O
taking	O
place	O
.	O

In	O
short	O
,	O
what	O
is	O
required	O
is	O
zero	O
tolerance	O
for	O
terrorism	O
regardless	O
of	O
its	O
intended	O
targets	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
not	O
without	O
reason	O
that	O
I	O
am	O
reiterating	O
this	O
point	O
.	O

For	O
us	O
in	O
Ethiopia	I-LOC
,	O
terrorism	O
is	O
not	O
a	O
theoretical	O
threat	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
a	O
practical	O
and	O
immediate	O
threat	O
that	O
we	O
have	O
had	O
to	O
face	O
both	O
before	O
and	O
after	O
11	O
September	O
,	O
including	O
most	O
recently	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
our	O
earnest	O
hope	O
that	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
will	O
do	O
whatever	O
is	O
necessary	O
to	O
eliminate	O
this	O
scourge	O
.	O

We	O
also	O
hope	O
that	O
there	O
will	O
be	O
better	O
days	O
ahead	O
,	O
when	O
we	O
will	O
all	O
concentrate	O
on	O
addressing	O
the	O
challenges	O
that	O
trouble	O
our	O
planet	O
.	O

I	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
conclude	O
by	O
renewing	O
Ethiopia	I-LOC
's	O
commitment	O
to	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
and	O
to	O
what	O
it	O
stands	O
for	O
.	O

We	O
wish	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
become	O
an	O
even	O
a	O
more	O
effective	O
universal	O
Organization	I-ORG
and	O
a	O
more	O
forceful	O
and	O
faithful	O
custodian	O
of	O
the	O
principles	O
of	O
international	O
law	O
.	O

Our	O
hope	O
and	O
our	O
dream	O
is	O
that	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
will	O
be	O
an	O
even	O
more	O
robust	O
universal	O
Organization	I-ORG
catering	O
to	O
the	O
legitimate	O
interests	O
of	O
both	O
big	O
and	O
small	O
counties	O
.	O

We	O
in	O
Ethiopia	I-LOC
will	O
continue	O
to	O
contribute	O
our	O
share	O
to	O
the	O
greater	O
nurturing	O
of	O
multilateralism	O
and	O
to	O
making	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
an	O
effective	O
custodian	O
of	O
those	O
values	O
.	O
