Despite	O
the	O
fact	O
that	O
two	O
years	O
have	O
elapsed	O
since	O
the	O
2005	O
World	I-MISC
Summit	I-MISC
and	O
seven	O
years	O
since	O
the	O
Millennium	I-MISC
Summit	I-MISC
,	O
we	O
continue	O
to	O
confront	O
challenges	O
and	O
dangers	O
to	O
international	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
terrorism	O
,	O
poverty	O
,	O
hunger	O
,	O
the	O
spread	O
of	O
dangerous	O
infectious	O
diseases	O
like	O
HIV/AIDS	I-MISC
and	O
malaria	O
,	O
deterioration	O
of	O
the	O
environment	O
and	O
violations	O
of	O
human	O
rights	O
.	O

Recent	O
times	O
have	O
seen	O
a	O
number	O
of	O
outstanding	O
achievements	O
,	O
most	O
important	O
among	O
them	O
the	O
establishment	O
of	O
the	O
Peacebuilding	I-ORG
Commission	I-ORG
,	O
the	O
Human	I-ORG
Rights	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
,	O
the	O
Central	I-MISC
Emergency	I-MISC
Response	I-MISC
Fund	I-MISC
and	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Democracy	I-MISC
Fund	I-MISC
,	O
and	O
the	O
introduction	O
of	O
administrative	O
and	O
financial	O
reforms	O
of	O
the	O
work	O
of	O
the	O
Secretariat	I-ORG
.	O

These	O
were	O
all	O
necessary	O
achievements	O
,	O
but	O
they	O
are	O
not	O
enough	O
to	O
combat	O
terrorism	O
,	O
eliminate	O
weapons	O
of	O
mass	O
destruction	O
,	O
affect	O
climate	O
change	O
and	O
achieve	O
sustainable	O
development	O
in	O
the	O
developing	O
countries	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
least	O
developed	O
among	O
them	O
.	O

The	O
Organization	I-ORG
must	O
be	O
strong	O
in	O
confronting	O
that	O
threat	O
seriously	O
and	O
firmly	O
.	O

The	O
time	O
has	O
come	O
for	O
us	O
to	O
change	O
our	O
method	O
and	O
approach	O
in	O
dealing	O
with	O
these	O
universal	O
challenges	O
and	O
dangers	O
and	O
to	O
move	O
from	O
the	O
phase	O
of	O
determining	O
what	O
should	O
be	O
done	O
to	O
the	O
phase	O
of	O
actual	O
work	O
and	O
the	O
faithful	O
fulfilment	O
of	O
the	O
commitments	O
we	O
have	O
taken	O
upon	O
ourselves	O
at	O
international	O
conferences	O
and	O
in	O
international	O
agreements	O
and	O
conventions	O
that	O
we	O
have	O
signed	O
and	O
ratified	O
.	O

The	O
State	O
of	O
Kuwait	I-LOC
has	O
made	O
good	O
progress	O
in	O
translating	O
the	O
commitments	O
and	O
resolutions	O
of	O
the	O
2005	O
World	I-MISC
Summit	I-MISC
into	O
tangible	O
realities	O
.	O

It	O
has	O
also	O
attained	O
the	O
Millennium	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
Goals	I-MISC
,	O
particularly	O
in	O
the	O
fields	O
of	O
education	O
,	O
health	O
and	O
advancing	O
the	O
role	O
of	O
women	O
in	O
society	O
.	O

It	O
has	O
designed	O
policies	O
capable	O
of	O
uplifting	O
society	O
and	O
achieving	O
further	O
progress	O
and	O
social	O
and	O
economic	O
development	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
raising	O
the	O
standard	O
of	O
living	O
of	O
individuals	O
.	O

Such	O
policies	O
contribute	O
to	O
efforts	O
to	O
consolidate	O
the	O
principles	O
of	O
tolerance	O
,	O
moderation	O
and	O
the	O
rejection	O
of	O
fanaticism	O
.	O

Based	O
upon	O
the	O
State	O
of	O
Kuwait	I-LOC
's	O
absolute	O
belief	O
in	O
the	O
human	O
values	O
of	O
supporting	O
the	O
downtrodden	O
and	O
helping	O
the	O
needy	O
,	O
my	O
country	O
has	O
,	O
since	O
its	O
independence	O
,	O
implemented	O
a	O
generous	O
aid	O
programme	O
for	O
developing	O
countries	O
.	O

In	O
1961	O
,	O
it	O
established	O
the	O
Kuwait	I-LOC
Fund	O
for	O
Arab	I-MISC
Economic	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
,	O
which	O
has	O
financed	O
hundreds	O
of	O
infrastructure	O
projects	O
in	O
more	O
than	O
100	O
countries	O
.	O

The	O
value	O
of	O
those	O
projects	O
exceeds	O
$12	O
billion	O
.	O

The	O
State	O
of	O
Kuwait	I-LOC
is	O
also	O
committed	O
to	O
providing	O
annual	O
voluntary	O
contributions	O
to	O
numerous	O
international	O
specialized	O
agencies	O
and	O
organizations	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
to	O
regional	O
organizations	O
and	O
funds	O
that	O
assist	O
developing	O
countries	O
in	O
achieving	O
their	O
development	O
goals	O
.	O

Recently	O
,	O
the	O
State	O
of	O
Kuwait	I-LOC
allocated	O
$300	O
million	O
to	O
the	O
Islamic	I-ORG
Development	I-ORG
Bank	I-ORG
for	O
the	O
elimination	O
of	O
poverty	O
in	O
Africa	I-LOC
.	O

That	O
is	O
in	O
addition	O
to	O
what	O
we	O
contribute	O
in	O
humanitarian	O
and	O
relief	O
aid	O
to	O
many	O
countries	O
ravaged	O
by	O
natural	O
disasters	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
regrettable	O
that	O
poverty	O
,	O
hunger	O
and	O
disease	O
persist	O
in	O
developing	O
countries	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
even	O
more	O
painful	O
to	O
see	O
that	O
more	O
than	O
half	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
population	O
is	O
living	O
on	O
less	O
than	O
$2	O
per	O
day	O
—	O
a	O
matter	O
that	O
requires	O
serious	O
examination	O
and	O
a	O
real	O
review	O
of	O
the	O
impediments	O
to	O
development	O
in	O
developing	O
countries	O
.	O

Kuwait	I-LOC
is	O
following	O
with	O
concern	O
the	O
developments	O
in	O
the	O
situation	O
in	O
Iraq	I-LOC
.	O

We	O
welcome	O
the	O
improvements	O
in	O
security	O
conditions	O
in	O
some	O
areas	O
and	O
provinces	O
of	O
Iraq	I-LOC
,	O
as	O
a	O
result	O
of	O
the	O
implementation	O
of	O
relevant	O
arrangements	O
and	O
a	O
security	O
enforcement	O
plan	O
carried	O
out	O
by	O
the	O
international	O
forces	O
in	O
Iraq	I-LOC
with	O
the	O
participation	O
of	O
Iraqi	I-MISC
security	O
forces	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
our	O
hope	O
that	O
the	O
Iraqi	I-MISC
Government	O
's	O
efforts	O
to	O
achieve	O
national	O
reconciliation	O
will	O
be	O
successful	O
and	O
produce	O
positive	O
results	O
that	O
can	O
lead	O
to	O
a	O
comprehensive	O
national	O
consensus	O
in	O
Iraq	I-LOC
that	O
takes	O
into	O
consideration	O
the	O
concerns	O
and	O
the	O
rights	O
of	O
all	O
sectors	O
of	O
the	O
Iraqi	I-MISC
people	O
.	O

National	O
reconciliation	O
is	O
the	O
only	O
way	O
to	O
build	O
a	O
democratic	O
,	O
free	O
,	O
secure	O
and	O
independent	O
Iraq	I-LOC
that	O
is	O
at	O
peace	O
with	O
itself	O
and	O
its	O
neighbours	O
and	O
that	O
respects	O
its	O
international	O
obligations	O
and	O
commitments	O
.	O

We	O
look	O
forward	O
to	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
playing	O
its	O
vital	O
role	O
in	O
helping	O
Iraq	I-LOC
to	O
fulfil	O
its	O
political	O
and	O
economic	O
obligations	O
within	O
the	O
context	O
of	O
the	O
International	I-MISC
Compact	I-MISC
with	O
Iraq	I-LOC
.	O

With	O
regard	O
to	O
the	O
issue	O
of	O
the	O
three	O
occupied	O
Emirati	I-MISC
islands	O
,	O
Kuwait	I-LOC
would	O
like	O
to	O
reaffirm	O
its	O
support	O
for	O
the	O
position	O
of	O
the	O
Gulf	I-ORG
Cooperation	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
on	O
this	O
issue	O
.	O

We	O
hope	O
that	O
efforts	O
and	O
contacts	O
at	O
all	O
levels	O
will	O
intensify	O
between	O
the	O
sisterly	O
United	I-LOC
Arab	I-LOC
Emirates	I-LOC
and	O
the	O
friendly	O
Islamic	I-LOC
Republic	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
Iran	I-LOC
in	O
order	O
to	O
find	O
a	O
solution	O
to	O
this	O
dispute	O
consistent	O
with	O
the	O
principles	O
and	O
rules	O
of	O
international	O
law	O
and	O
good-neighbourly	O
relations	O
,	O
thereby	O
contributing	O
to	O
strengthening	O
the	O
security	O
and	O
stability	O
of	O
the	O
region	O
.	O

The	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
crisis	O
has	O
been	O
stagnant	O
since	O
the	O
middle	O
of	O
the	O
past	O
century	O
.	O

The	O
plight	O
of	O
the	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
people	O
continues:	O
their	O
rights	O
are	O
violated	O
,	O
their	O
lands	O
are	O
occupied	O
and	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
resolutions	O
are	O
frozen	O
—	O
despite	O
intensive	O
international	O
and	O
regional	O
efforts	O
to	O
revive	O
the	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
peace	O
process	O
.	O

The	O
Israeli	I-MISC
Government	O
,	O
instead	O
of	O
putting	O
confidence-building	O
measures	O
in	O
place	O
,	O
continues	O
to	O
create	O
obstacles	O
that	O
serve	O
to	O
increase	O
tensions	O
and	O
violence	O
and	O
that	O
hinder	O
the	O
establishment	O
of	O
a	O
climate	O
conducive	O
to	O
moving	O
the	O
peace	O
process	O
ahead	O
.	O

Do	O
continuing	O
settlement	O
activities	O
help	O
to	O
achieve	O
peace	O
more	O
quickly	O
?	O

Do	O
the	O
policies	O
of	O
detention	O
,	O
land	O
confiscation	O
,	O
curfews	O
,	O
closures	O
and	O
restrictions	O
of	O
movement	O
promote	O
an	O
environment	O
of	O
trust	O
and	O
stability	O
?	O

The	O
answer	O
is	O
definitely	O
no	O
.	O

Who	O
could	O
think	O
that	O
this	O
conflict	O
is	O
subject	O
to	O
the	O
principles	O
of	O
a	O
zero-sum	O
game	O
?	O

Anyone	O
who	O
thinks	O
that	O
Israel	I-LOC
will	O
achieve	O
security	O
for	O
itself	O
at	O
the	O
expense	O
of	O
the	O
security	O
of	O
the	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
people	O
is	O
making	O
a	O
serious	O
mistake	O
.	O

Security	I-ORG
must	O
be	O
for	O
everyone	O
.	O

There	O
will	O
be	O
no	O
security	O
except	O
through	O
the	O
implementation	O
of	O
resolutions	O
of	O
international	O
legitimacy	O
.	O

The	O
State	O
of	O
Kuwait	I-LOC
therefore	O
reiterates	O
its	O
support	O
for	O
the	O
convening	O
of	O
an	O
international	O
conference	O
with	O
the	O
participation	O
of	O
all	O
the	O
parties	O
concerned	O
in	O
the	O
peace	O
process	O
.	O

That	O
meeting	O
should	O
follow	O
the	O
terms	O
of	O
reference	O
of	O
the	O
Madrid	I-LOC
Conference	I-MISC
—	O
including	O
the	O
provisions	O
of	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
resolutions	O
242	O
(	O
1967	O
)	O
and	O
338	O
(	O
1973	0
)	O
—	O
the	O
principle	O
of	O
land	O
for	O
peace	O
,	O
the	O
Road	I-MISC
Map	I-MISC
endorsed	O
by	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
in	O
its	O
resolution	O
1515	O
(	O
2003	O
)	O
and	O
the	O
Arab	I-MISC
Peace	I-MISC
Initiative	I-MISC
.	O

The	O
comprehensive	O
,	O
just	O
and	O
lasting	O
peace	O
that	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
seeks	O
to	O
achieve	O
must	O
ensure	O
that	O
the	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
people	O
attain	O
all	O
their	O
legitimate	O
political	O
rights	O
.	O

That	O
includes	O
the	O
establishment	O
of	O
their	O
own	O
independent	O
State	O
on	O
their	O
own	O
land	O
,	O
with	O
Jerusalem	I-LOC
as	O
its	O
capital	O
.	O

It	O
must	O
also	O
include	O
Israel	I-LOC
's	O
withdrawal	O
from	O
all	O
the	O
Arab	I-MISC
land	O
occupied	O
since	O
1967	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
Syrian	I-MISC
Golan	I-LOC
Heights	I-LOC
.	O

Turning	O
to	O
Lebanon	I-LOC
,	O
we	O
congratulate	O
the	O
Lebanese	I-MISC
Government	O
on	O
its	O
success	O
in	O
putting	O
a	O
decisive	O
end	O
to	O
the	O
Nahr	I-PER
Al-Bared	I-PER
sedition	O
.	O

We	O
would	O
also	O
like	O
to	O
express	O
our	O
gratitude	O
to	O
the	O
Lebanese	I-MISC
army	O
,	O
which	O
dealt	O
with	O
that	O
sedition	O
ably	O
and	O
firmly	O
.	O

We	O
hope	O
that	O
that	O
accomplishment	O
will	O
contribute	O
to	O
the	O
return	O
of	O
all	O
Lebanese	I-MISC
parties	O
to	O
the	O
negotiating	O
table	O
and	O
the	O
resumption	O
of	O
a	O
Lebanese	I-MISC
national	O
dialogue	O
to	O
address	O
the	O
issue	O
of	O
presidential	O
entitlement	O
and	O
the	O
political	O
process	O
,	O
in	O
accordance	O
with	O
the	O
constitution	O
.	O

While	O
we	O
commend	O
the	O
regional	O
and	O
international	O
efforts	O
to	O
achieve	O
national	O
reconciliation	O
among	O
all	O
Lebanese	I-MISC
parties	O
,	O
we	O
condemn	O
the	O
political	O
assassinations	O
and	O
the	O
recurrent	O
terrorist	O
bombings	O
aimed	O
at	O
disrupting	O
peace	O
and	O
stability	O
in	O
that	O
sisterly	O
country	O
.	O

We	O
renew	O
Kuwait	I-LOC
's	O
commitment	O
to	O
stand	O
by	O
Lebanon	I-LOC
and	O
to	O
support	O
it	O
in	O
a	O
manner	O
that	O
will	O
preserve	O
its	O
security	O
,	O
unity	O
,	O
territorial	O
integrity	O
and	O
political	O
independence	O
.	O

As	O
for	O
developments	O
on	O
the	O
Iranian	I-MISC
nuclear	O
issue	O
,	O
we	O
reaffirm	O
our	O
firm	O
belief	O
in	O
the	O
need	O
to	O
respect	O
internationally	O
recognized	O
principles	O
,	O
including	O
that	O
of	O
resolving	O
conflicts	O
through	O
peaceful	O
means	O
.	O

The	O
State	O
of	O
Kuwait	I-LOC
calls	O
upon	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
to	O
coordinate	O
its	O
efforts	O
and	O
to	O
continue	O
to	O
work	O
towards	O
achieving	O
a	O
peaceful	O
resolution	O
of	O
this	O
crisis	O
,	O
so	O
as	O
to	O
safeguard	O
the	O
peace	O
and	O
stability	O
of	O
the	O
Gulf	I-LOC
region	O
.	O

We	O
also	O
welcome	O
the	O
recent	O
agreement	O
reached	O
between	O
the	O
Islamic	I-LOC
Republic	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
Iran	I-LOC
and	O
the	O
International	I-ORG
Atomic	I-ORG
Energy	I-ORG
Agency	I-ORG
(	O
IAEA	I-ORG
)	O
as	O
an	O
important	O
step	O
towards	O
dispelling	O
fears	O
and	O
doubts	O
surrounding	O
the	O
Iranian	I-MISC
nuclear	O
programme	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
our	O
hope	O
that	O
dialogue	O
and	O
cooperation	O
will	O
resume	O
with	O
total	O
transparency	O
.	O

That	O
would	O
allow	O
us	O
to	O
address	O
all	O
the	O
elements	O
of	O
this	O
issue	O
,	O
so	O
as	O
to	O
foster	O
the	O
conditions	O
conducive	O
to	O
making	O
the	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
a	O
zone	O
free	O
of	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
and	O
all	O
other	O
weapons	O
of	O
mass	O
destruction	O
.	O

In	O
that	O
connection	O
,	O
we	O
call	O
upon	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
to	O
exert	O
pressure	O
on	O
Israel	I-LOC
to	O
join	O
the	O
Treaty	I-MISC
on	I-MISC
the	I-MISC
Non-Proliferation	I-MISC
of	I-MISC
Nuclear	I-MISC
Weapons	I-MISC
and	O
to	O
place	O
all	O
of	O
its	O
nuclear	O
facilities	O
under	O
IAEA	I-ORG
safeguards	O
.	O

We	O
emphasize	O
the	O
right	O
of	O
all	O
the	O
States	O
of	O
the	O
region	O
to	O
obtain	O
the	O
technology	O
and	O
know-how	O
necessary	O
to	O
peacefully	O
utilize	O
nuclear	O
energy	O
in	O
accordance	O
with	O
the	O
terms	O
specified	O
by	O
relevant	O
international	O
conventions	O
.	O

Finally	O
,	O
we	O
renew	O
our	O
commitment	O
to	O
work	O
through	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
to	O
fulfil	O
the	O
hopes	O
and	O
aspirations	O
of	O
our	O
peoples	O
to	O
live	O
together	O
in	O
a	O
world	O
where	O
peace	O
,	O
justice	O
and	O
equality	O
prevail	O
.	O
