This	O
was	O
a	O
tragedy	O
in	O
a	O
city	O
that	O
has	O
already	O
seen	O
more	O
than	O
its	O
share	O
of	O
tragedy	O
in	O
recent	O
times	O
.	O

We	O
meet	O
in	O
New	I-LOC
York	I-LOC
at	O
this	O
session	O
of	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
under	O
the	O
shadow	O
of	O
terrorist	O
attacks	O
on	O
this	O
city	O
just	O
two	O
months	O
ago	O
.	O

We	O
mourn	O
the	O
lives	O
of	O
nearly	O
5,000	O
people	O
from	O
79	O
countries	O
who	O
,	O
having	O
done	O
nothing	O
to	O
deserve	O
that	O
fate	O
,	O
died	O
in	O
the	O
attack	O
.	O

The	O
scale	O
,	O
premeditation	O
,	O
coordination	O
and	O
indifference	O
to	O
mass	O
murder	O
that	O
characterize	O
this	O
attack	O
represent	O
a	O
new	O
age	O
of	O
terrorism	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
a	O
terrorism	O
that	O
appears	O
to	O
set	O
no	O
limit	O
to	O
its	O
consequences	O
.	O

Those	O
responsible	O
for	O
it	O
foreshadow	O
a	O
willingness	O
to	O
use	O
biological	O
,	O
chemical	O
and	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
of	O
mass	O
destruction	O
.	O

The	O
potentially	O
catastrophic	O
effects	O
if	O
they	O
are	O
able	O
to	O
carry	O
out	O
that	O
threat	O
demand	O
an	O
urgent	O
and	O
comprehensive	O
response	O
to	O
pre-empt	O
any	O
such	O
action	O
.	O

We	O
cannot	O
allow	O
the	O
rule	O
of	O
terror	O
to	O
replace	O
the	O
rule	O
of	O
law	O
.	O

We	O
cannot	O
tolerate	O
the	O
damage	O
that	O
terrorism	O
has	O
already	O
done	O
to	O
the	O
global	O
economy	O
.	O

We	O
cannot	O
allow	O
terror	O
to	O
threaten	O
basic	O
human	O
rights	O
to	O
life	O
and	O
security	O
.	O

New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
welcomes	O
the	O
lead	O
by	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
in	O
coordinating	O
an	O
effective	O
and	O
enduring	O
response	O
to	O
terrorism	O
.	O

Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
resolution	O
1373	O
(	0
2001	O
)	O
,	O
adopted	O
unanimously	O
,	O
sets	O
out	O
a	O
blueprint	O
for	O
action	O
which	O
every	O
Member	O
State	O
has	O
an	O
obligation	O
to	O
implement	O
.	O

Its	O
emphasis	O
is	O
on	O
measures	O
to	O
close	O
off	O
financial	O
support	O
and	O
the	O
provision	O
of	O
refuge	O
for	O
terrorist	O
groups	O
in	O
every	O
country	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

International	O
cooperation	O
in	O
imposing	O
these	O
measures	O
and	O
bringing	O
the	O
terrorists	O
to	O
justice	O
will	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
longer	O
term	O
,	O
lie	O
at	O
the	O
heart	O
of	O
the	O
campaign	O
to	O
defeat	O
terrorism	O
.	O

Removing	O
the	O
immediate	O
threat	O
posed	O
by	O
terrorists	O
such	O
as	O
those	O
in	O
Al	O
Qaeda	O
and	O
those	O
who	O
harbour	O
them	O
will	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
require	O
more	O
than	O
resolutions	O
.	O

Time	O
and	O
again	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
three	O
years	O
,	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
has	O
called	O
on	O
the	O
Taliban	I-ORG
to	O
prevent	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
by	O
terrorists	O
to	O
launch	O
strikes	O
against	O
other	O
countries	O
.	O

Those	O
resolutions	O
and	O
the	O
sanctions	O
that	O
accompanied	O
them	O
have	O
been	O
ignored	O
by	O
the	O
Taliban	I-ORG
.	O

Where	O
groups	O
operate	O
beyond	O
the	O
rule	O
of	O
law	O
and	O
countries	O
put	O
themselves	O
outside	O
of	O
international	O
codes	O
of	O
behaviour	O
,	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
force	O
becomes	O
a	O
necessary	O
part	O
of	O
our	O
response	O
.	O

Multilateral	O
action	O
and	O
cooperation	O
on	O
a	O
wider	O
front	O
are	O
also	O
necessary	O
if	O
we	O
are	O
to	O
be	O
successful	O
in	O
removing	O
the	O
threat	O
of	O
terrorism	O
on	O
an	O
ongoing	O
and	O
lasting	O
basis	O
.	O

Comprehensive	O
action	O
is	O
needed	O
to	O
minimize	O
the	O
threat	O
of	O
chemical	O
,	O
biological	O
or	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
falling	O
into	O
the	O
hands	O
of	O
extremist	O
groups	O
.	O

No	O
State	O
should	O
develop	O
,	O
test	O
and	O
hold	O
weapons	O
of	O
this	O
nature	O
.	O

Such	O
weapons	O
are	O
a	O
threat	O
to	O
humanity	O
.	O

Their	O
use	O
by	O
States	I-LOC
would	O
destroy	O
and	O
otherwise	O
harm	O
innocent	O
human	O
beings	O
as	O
certainly	O
as	O
did	O
the	O
actions	O
of	O
the	O
terrorist	O
group	O
that	O
attacked	O
New	I-LOC
York	I-LOC
.	O

Nations	O
yet	O
to	O
sign	O
and	O
ratify	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Conventions	I-MISC
on	I-MISC
Chemical	I-MISC
and	I-MISC
Biological	I-MISC
Weapons	I-MISC
and	O
treaties	O
to	O
ban	O
mines	O
and	O
inhumane	O
weapons	O
must	O
do	O
so	O
.	O

Nations	O
must	O
equally	O
commit	O
themselves	O
to	O
the	O
elimination	O
of	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
,	O
the	O
early	O
entry	O
into	O
force	O
of	O
the	O
Comprehensive	I-MISC
Nuclear-Test-Ban	I-MISC
Treaty	I-MISC
,	O
and	O
an	O
immediate	O
start	O
to	O
negotiations	O
on	O
a	O
fissile	O
material	O
cut-off	O
treaty	O
.	O

The	O
attack	O
of	O
11	O
September	O
should	O
also	O
encourage	O
all	O
nations	O
to	O
ratify	O
the	O
Rome	I-LOC
Statute	O
to	O
bring	O
into	O
effect	O
the	O
International	I-ORG
Criminal	I-ORG
Court	I-ORG
as	O
a	O
forum	O
for	O
pursuing	O
action	O
against	O
those	O
responsible	O
for	O
crimes	O
against	O
humanity	O
.	O

Suppression	O
of	O
terrorism	O
must	O
also	O
involve	O
action	O
to	O
deal	O
with	O
its	O
causes	O
.	O

States	O
must	O
consider	O
whether	O
the	O
suppression	O
of	O
dissident	O
or	O
minority	O
groups	O
rather	O
than	O
allowing	O
legitimate	O
channels	O
to	O
voice	O
dissent	O
leaves	O
resort	O
to	O
force	O
as	O
the	O
only	O
option	O
.	O

The	O
events	O
of	O
11	O
September	O
should	O
encourage	O
all	O
countries	O
and	O
organizations	O
,	O
particularly	O
those	O
directly	O
involved	O
,	O
to	O
renew	O
efforts	O
to	O
find	O
a	O
just	O
and	O
peaceful	O
solution	O
to	O
the	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
crisis	O
.	O

To	O
achieve	O
a	O
peaceful	O
solution	O
between	O
Palestinians	I-MISC
and	O
Israelis	I-MISC
requires	O
good	O
will	O
and	O
flexibility	O
on	O
both	O
sides	O
.	O

There	O
can	O
be	O
no	O
double	O
standards	O
in	O
how	O
the	O
principles	O
of	O
human	O
rights	O
,	O
freedom	O
and	O
social	O
and	O
economic	O
opportunity	O
are	O
applied	O
to	O
all	O
peoples	O
.	O

One	O
consequence	O
of	O
the	O
campaign	O
against	O
terrorism	O
has	O
been	O
to	O
bring	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
attention	O
to	O
the	O
situation	O
in	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
.	O

Afghanistan	I-LOC
reminds	O
us	O
that	O
where	O
a	O
vacuum	O
is	O
created	O
by	O
the	O
absence	O
of	O
legitimate	O
government	O
and	O
the	O
rule	O
of	O
law	O
,	O
it	O
will	O
be	O
filled	O
by	O
extremist	O
elements	O
,	O
criminal	O
groups	O
dealing	O
in	O
drug	O
trafficking	O
and	O
terrorist	O
organizations	O
,	O
all	O
of	O
which	O
can	O
operate	O
with	O
impunity	O
.	O

The	O
international	O
community	O
has	O
for	O
too	O
long	O
been	O
indifferent	O
to	O
the	O
situation	O
in	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
and	O
to	O
the	O
long-standing	O
refugee	O
crisis	O
that	O
has	O
resulted	O
from	O
22	O
years	O
of	O
war	O
,	O
from	O
famine	O
and	O
from	O
Taliban	I-ORG
oppression	O
.	O

Pakistan	I-LOC
and	O
Iran	I-LOC
have	O
carried	O
the	O
burden	O
of	O
3.6	O
million	O
refugees	O
,	O
while	O
much	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
showed	O
concern	O
only	O
when	O
a	O
handful	O
of	O
those	O
refugees	O
in	O
desperation	O
sought	O
to	O
enter	O
other	O
countries	O
illegally	O
.	O

Too	O
little	O
concern	O
has	O
been	O
shown	O
internationally	O
to	O
the	O
300,000	O
Afghan	I-MISC
children	O
who	O
have	O
died	O
annually	O
from	O
preventable	O
causes	O
.	O

One	O
in	O
three	O
children	O
in	O
refugee	O
camps	O
die	O
before	O
they	O
reach	O
the	O
age	O
of	O
five	O
.	O

The	O
groups	O
now	O
protesting	O
against	O
military	O
intervention	O
were	O
silent	O
while	O
this	O
human	O
catastrophe	O
was	O
unfolding	O
over	O
the	O
last	O
few	O
years	O
.	O

Any	O
loss	O
of	O
innocent	O
life	O
in	O
conflict	O
is	O
tragic	O
,	O
and	O
extraordinary	O
measures	O
must	O
be	O
taken	O
to	O
avoid	O
it	O
.	O

But	O
a	O
failure	O
to	O
remove	O
the	O
Taliban	I-ORG
regime	O
and	O
a	O
failure	O
to	O
assist	O
the	O
Afghan	I-MISC
people	O
to	O
put	O
in	O
place	O
a	O
broad-	O
based	O
,	O
moderate	O
and	O
stable	O
Government	O
to	O
replace	O
the	O
Taliban	I-ORG
will	O
mean	O
the	O
ongoing	O
loss	O
of	O
hundreds	O
of	O
thousands	O
of	O
lives	O
and	O
the	O
continued	O
suffering	O
of	O
the	O
Afghan	I-MISC
people	O
.	O

Renewed	O
efforts	O
are	O
needed	O
through	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
agencies	O
to	O
provide	O
emergency	O
relief	O
to	O
people	O
within	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
and	O
in	O
the	O
refugee	O
camps	O
to	O
avoid	O
unnecessary	O
loss	O
of	O
life	O
through	O
the	O
winter	O
and	O
in	O
the	O
months	O
to	O
come	O
.	O

The	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
must	O
stand	O
ready	O
to	O
assist	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
to	O
rebuild	O
itself	O
once	O
the	O
conflict	O
is	O
over	O
,	O
working	O
with	O
as	O
broad	O
a	O
coalition	O
of	O
Afghan	I-MISC
groups	O
as	O
is	O
possible	O
to	O
create	O
a	O
viable	O
political	O
,	O
economic	O
and	O
social	O
infrastructure	O
.	O

Resolving	O
the	O
problems	O
that	O
have	O
forced	O
so	O
many	O
millions	O
of	O
people	O
from	O
their	O
homes	O
is	O
fundamental	O
to	O
solving	O
the	O
growing	O
refugee	O
crisis	O
.	O

In	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
and	O
elsewhere	O
,	O
people	O
flee	O
their	O
homelands	O
through	O
fear	O
of	O
death	O
or	O
persecution	O
,	O
or	O
because	O
of	O
poverty	O
and	O
lack	O
of	O
opportunity	O
.	O

Suppression	O
of	O
criminal	O
organizations	O
responsible	O
for	O
people	O
trafficking	O
is	O
a	O
challenge	O
which	O
demands	O
increased	O
international	O
cooperation	O
.	O

Those	O
who	O
profit	O
from	O
people	O
's	O
desperation	O
and	O
who	O
,	O
once	O
paid	O
,	O
are	O
careless	O
as	O
to	O
whether	O
or	O
not	O
their	O
human	O
cargo	O
survives	O
must	O
be	O
stamped	O
out	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
removing	O
the	O
causes	O
of	O
people	O
fleeing	O
from	O
their	O
countries	O
remains	O
fundamental	O
.	O

New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
's	O
own	O
region	O
of	O
the	O
Pacific	I-LOC
has	O
not	O
been	O
immune	O
from	O
violence	O
and	O
instability	O
.	O

In	O
recent	O
years	O
,	O
we	O
have	O
seen	O
conflict	O
in	O
East	I-LOC
Timor	I-LOC
,	O
violence	O
between	O
Government	O
and	O
separatist	O
movements	O
within	O
Indonesia	I-LOC
and	O
in	O
Bougainville	I-LOC
,	O
ethnic	O
conflict	O
in	O
the	O
Solomon	I-LOC
Islands	I-LOC
and	O
a	O
coup	O
that	O
overthrew	O
a	O
legitimate	O
Government	O
in	O
Fiji	I-LOC
.	O

Problems	O
remain	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
,	O
but	O
there	O
have	O
been	O
notable	O
areas	O
of	O
improvement	O
.	O

Fiji	I-LOC
has	O
held	O
democratic	O
elections	O
.	O

Indonesia	I-LOC
is	O
seeking	O
to	O
resolve	O
separatist	O
conflict	O
by	O
offering	O
greater	O
autonomy	O
.	O

In	O
East	I-LOC
Timor	I-LOC
,	O
there	O
have	O
been	O
free	O
elections	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
country	O
will	O
gain	O
independence	O
as	O
the	O
first	O
new	O
nation	O
of	O
the	O
twenty-first	O
century	O
in	O
May	O
2002	O
.	O

International	O
cooperation	O
and	O
a	O
capable	O
transitional	O
administration	O
by	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
have	O
achieved	O
a	O
remarkable	O
transformation	O
in	O
a	O
poor	O
and	O
devastated	O
country	O
.	O

I	O
congratulate	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
on	O
its	O
endorsement	O
of	O
the	O
Secretary-General	O
's	O
concept	O
for	O
a	O
post-independence	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
presence	O
in	O
East	I-ORG
Timor	I-ORG
to	O
consolidate	O
what	O
has	O
been	O
achieved	O
.	O

In	O
acknowledging	O
the	O
role	O
of	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
personnel	O
,	O
I	O
would	O
also	O
stress	O
the	O
need	O
to	O
ensure	O
their	O
proper	O
protection	O
in	O
situations	O
which	O
are	O
often	O
dangerous	O
.	O

The	O
murder	O
of	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
relief	O
workers	O
in	O
Atambua	I-LOC
,	O
West	I-LOC
Timor	I-LOC
,	O
and	O
the	O
failure	O
to	O
bring	O
to	O
account	O
those	O
fully	O
responsible	O
are	O
a	O
reminder	O
that	O
more	O
must	O
be	O
done	O
to	O
protect	O
our	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
personnel	O
.	O

We	O
endorse	O
the	O
Secretary-General	O
's	O
recommendations	O
on	O
extending	O
the	O
legal	O
protection	O
for	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
and	O
other	O
personnel	O
involved	O
in	O
humanitarian	O
operations	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
timely	O
at	O
this	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
to	O
stress	O
the	O
importance	O
of	O
the	O
role	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

The	O
critical	O
wars	O
of	O
the	O
twenty-first	O
century	O
will	O
not	O
be	O
won	O
by	O
single	O
nations	O
,	O
however	O
powerful	O
,	O
or	O
even	O
by	O
coalitions	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
acting	O
collectively	O
which	O
will	O
win	O
the	O
wars	O
against	O
terrorism	O
,	O
poverty	O
and	O
disease	O
;	O
threats	O
to	O
the	O
environment	O
;	O
and	O
the	O
threats	O
posed	O
by	O
conflict	O
and	O
weapons	O
of	O
mass	O
destruction	O
.	O

The	O
commitments	O
made	O
by	O
heads	O
of	O
State	O
and	O
Government	O
in	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Millennium	I-MISC
Declaration	I-MISC
last	O
year	O
take	O
on	O
even	O
greater	O
relevance	O
following	O
the	O
events	O
of	O
11	O
September	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
for	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
to	O
achieve	O
its	O
potential	O
,	O
it	O
must	O
undergo	O
reform	O
.	O

To	O
prevent	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
and	O
the	O
Secretariat	I-ORG
from	O
becoming	O
overwhelmed	O
by	O
so	O
many	O
tasks	O
that	O
they	O
fail	O
to	O
be	O
effective	O
in	O
tackling	O
any	O
of	O
them	O
,	O
we	O
need	O
to	O
prioritize	O
our	O
agenda	O
and	O
to	O
be	O
more	O
selective	O
.	O

The	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
needs	O
reform	O
.	O

Its	O
membership	O
should	O
be	O
expanded	O
to	O
reflect	O
contemporary	O
realities	O
,	O
but	O
without	O
maintaining	O
or	O
extending	O
the	O
veto	O
.	O

Countries	O
contributing	O
to	O
peacekeeping	O
operations	O
should	O
be	O
afforded	O
greater	O
involvement	O
in	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
's	O
decision-making	O
with	O
respect	O
to	O
those	O
operations	O
.	O

Peacekeeping	O
operations	O
must	O
be	O
sufficiently	O
resourced	O
.	O

The	O
capacity	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
for	O
rapid	O
reaction	O
must	O
be	O
strengthened	O
.	O

New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
is	O
ready	O
to	O
enter	O
into	O
discussions	O
on	O
a	O
memorandum	O
of	O
understanding	O
with	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
on	O
its	O
participation	O
in	O
the	O
standby	O
arrangements	O
system	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
consistent	O
with	O
New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
's	O
long-	O
standing	O
readiness	O
to	O
contribute	O
to	O
peacekeeping	O
operations	O
and	O
its	O
current	O
involvement	O
in	O
more	O
than	O
12	O
such	O
operations	O
,	O
including	O
its	O
commitment	O
since	O
1999	O
of	O
a	O
battalion	O
to	O
help	O
ensure	O
the	O
success	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
operation	O
in	O
East	O
Timor	O
.	O

The	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
was	O
founded	O
after	O
the	O
Second	I-MISC
World	I-MISC
War	I-MISC
to	O
build	O
a	O
world	O
free	O
from	O
poverty	O
,	O
violence	O
and	O
the	O
violation	O
of	O
human	O
rights	O
.	O

Nations	O
committed	O
themselves	O
to	O
a	O
collective	O
response	O
to	O
problems	O
that	O
could	O
not	O
be	O
solved	O
by	O
countries	O
individually	O
.	O

Countries	O
agreed	O
on	O
rules	O
of	O
international	O
behaviour	O
.	O

No	O
one	O
would	O
claim	O
that	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
has	O
an	O
unblemished	O
record	O
of	O
success	O
.	O

But	O
without	O
it	O
,	O
the	O
world	O
would	O
be	O
a	O
much	O
less	O
secure	O
place	O
,	O
much	O
less	O
able	O
to	O
confront	O
the	O
difficulties	O
which	O
we	O
face	O
.	O

Let	O
this	O
fifty-	O
sixth	O
session	O
of	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
reaffirm	O
our	O
commitment	O
to	O
work	O
collectively	O
to	O
defeat	O
terrorism	O
,	O
conflict	O
,	O
poverty	O
and	O
disease	O
,	O
and	O
set	O
the	O
agenda	O
for	O
peace	O
,	O
development	O
and	O
respect	O
for	O
human	O
rights	O
for	O
all	O
.	O
