I	O
am	O
confident	O
that	O
your	O
able	O
leadership	O
and	O
diplomatic	O
skills	O
will	O
steer	O
our	O
deliberations	O
to	O
a	O
successful	O
conclusion	O
.	O

I	O
assure	O
you	O
of	O
my	O
delegation	O
's	O
full	O
support	O
and	O
cooperation	O
.	O

This	O
year	O
marks	O
the	O
seventieth	O
anniversary	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

This	O
historic	O
occasion	O
affords	O
us	O
the	O
opportunity	O
to	O
reflect	O
on	O
and	O
look	O
back	O
at	O
the	O
achievements	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
Organization	O
.	O

The	O
Organization	O
deserves	O
the	O
highest	O
credit	O
for	O
its	O
achievement	O
in	O
preventing	O
the	O
outbreak	O
of	O
another	O
world	O
war	O
of	O
the	O
kind	O
that	O
has	O
plagued	O
us	O
twice	O
in	O
the	O
past	O
.	O

On	O
the	O
other	O
hand	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
confronted	O
with	O
regional	O
conflicts	O
,	O
a	O
rising	O
tide	O
of	O
non-traditional	O
threats	O
and	O
violent	O
extremism	O
.	O

We	O
need	O
to	O
do	O
more	O
to	O
address	O
these	O
challenges	O
,	O
collectively	O
.	O

There	O
are	O
also	O
achievements	O
in	O
bringing	O
a	O
better	O
life	O
to	O
all	O
.	O

Lifting	O
millions	O
out	O
of	O
poverty	O
,	O
sending	O
millions	O
more	O
children	O
to	O
school	O
,	O
combating	O
deadly	O
diseases	O
,	O
and	O
promoting	O
gender	O
equality	O
and	O
human	O
rights	O
are	O
remarkable	O
milestones	O
in	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
journey	O
.	O

The	O
unanimous	O
adoption	O
of	O
the	O
2030	I-MISC
Agenda	I-MISC
for	I-MISC
Sustainable	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
(	O
resolution	O
70/1	O
)	O
last	O
week	O
has	O
added	O
to	O
the	O
long	O
list	O
of	O
its	O
achievements	O
.	O

Still	O
,	O
daunting	O
challenges	O
remain	O
.	O

The	O
colonial	O
legacy	O
with	O
its	O
inherited	O
divisions	O
influences	O
today	O
's	O
conflicts	O
across	O
the	O
world	O
,	O
depriving	O
many	O
of	O
economic	O
and	O
social	O
development	O
.	O

The	O
rising	O
threats	O
of	O
terrorism	O
and	O
acts	O
of	O
violent	O
extremism	O
need	O
to	O
be	O
addressed	O
decisively	O
.	O

Climate	O
change	O
and	O
environmental	O
degradation	O
are	O
undermining	O
the	O
development	O
and	O
lives	O
of	O
the	O
poor	O
.	O

Inequalities	O
are	O
widening	O
,	O
pushing	O
the	O
poor	O
further	O
behind	O
.	O

The	O
time	O
is	O
now	O
opportune	O
to	O
do	O
soul-searching	O
on	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
the	O
Organization	O
and	O
to	O
strengthen	O
our	O
collective	O
resolve	O
to	O
address	O
the	O
challenges	O
of	O
our	O
time	O
,	O
particularly	O
to	O
advance	O
its	O
priorities	O
,	O
capacity	O
and	O
reform	O
.	O

Today	O
's	O
new	O
and	O
emerging	O
challenges	O
are	O
increasingly	O
calling	O
the	O
effectiveness	O
and	O
efficiency	O
of	O
the	O
Organization	O
into	O
question	O
.	O

While	O
the	O
cardinal	O
principles	O
of	O
the	O
Charter	I-MISC
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
remain	O
valid	O
today	O
,	O
the	O
world	O
Organization	O
,	O
which	O
was	O
founded	O
seven	O
decades	O
ago	O
,	O
needs	O
to	O
be	O
reformed	O
in	O
conformity	O
with	O
today	O
's	O
changing	O
realities	O
and	O
the	O
drastic	O
growth	O
in	O
membership	O
.	O

We	O
believe	O
that	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
also	O
has	O
to	O
be	O
reformed	O
to	O
make	O
it	O
more	O
representative	O
,	O
efficient	O
and	O
transparent	O
and	O
to	O
strengthen	O
its	O
capacity	O
to	O
better	O
discharge	O
its	O
responsibilities	O
to	O
maintain	O
international	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
,	O
as	O
entrusted	O
by	O
the	O
Charter	I-MISC
.	O

As	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
reform	O
,	O
we	O
set	O
up	O
the	O
Human	I-ORG
Rights	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
in	O
2006	O
to	O
redress	O
the	O
shortcomings	O
of	O
its	O
predecessor	O
,	O
the	O
Commission	I-ORG
on	I-ORG
Human	I-ORG
Rights	I-ORG
.	O

Yet	O
,	O
human	O
rights	O
issues	O
are	O
increasingly	O
politicized	O
and	O
exploited	O
.	O

The	O
principles	O
of	O
universality	O
,	O
objectivity	O
and	O
non-selectivity	O
are	O
at	O
stake	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
firmly	O
believes	O
that	O
the	O
universal	O
periodic	O
review	O
is	O
the	O
forum	O
where	O
promotion	O
and	O
protection	O
of	O
human	O
rights	O
can	O
best	O
be	O
addressed	O
with	O
objectivity	O
and	O
impartiality	O
on	O
an	O
equal	O
footing	O
.	O

The	O
most	O
significant	O
milestone	O
contribution	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
has	O
made	O
to	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
was	O
providing	O
the	O
Organization	O
with	O
a	O
Secretary-General	O
.	O

He	O
served	O
the	O
Organization	O
from	O
1961	O
to	O
1971	O
at	O
a	O
difficult	O
time	O
of	O
ideological	O
contention	O
,	O
mistrust	O
and	O
security	O
tensions	O
among	O
nations	O
.	O

He	O
played	O
an	O
important	O
role	O
in	O
enhancing	O
security	O
and	O
expanding	O
the	O
Organization	O
's	O
work	O
on	O
economic	O
and	O
social	O
development	O
in	O
poor	O
countries	O
.	O

The	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Development	I-ORG
Programme	I-ORG
and	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Environment	I-ORG
Programme	I-ORG
were	O
also	O
initiated	O
.	O

U	I-PER
Thant	I-PER
believed	O
that	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
needed	O
to	O
meet	O
the	O
needs	O
and	O
hopes	O
of	O
people	O
everywhere	O
.	O

That	O
vision	O
is	O
more	O
relevant	O
than	O
ever	O
to	O
the	O
work	O
of	O
the	O
Organization	O
and	O
should	O
guide	O
us	O
beyond	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
at	O
70	O
.	O

During	O
the	O
tenure	O
of	O
the	O
present	O
Government	O
,	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
has	O
moved	O
to	O
raise	O
its	O
profile	O
in	O
the	O
field	O
of	O
disarmament	O
.	O

We	O
started	O
with	O
the	O
signing	O
of	O
the	O
Additional	I-MISC
Protocol	I-MISC
of	O
the	O
International	I-ORG
Atomic	I-ORG
Energy	I-ORG
Agency	I-ORG
in	O
September	O
2013	O
.	O

That	O
was	O
followed	O
by	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
's	O
ratification	O
of	O
the	O
Convention	I-MISC
on	I-MISC
the	I-MISC
Prohibition	I-MISC
of	I-MISC
the	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
,	I-MISC
Production	I-MISC
and	I-MISC
Stockpiling	I-MISC
of	I-MISC
Bacteriological	I-MISC
(	I-MISC
Biological	I-MISC
)	I-MISC
and	I-MISC
Toxin	I-MISC
Weapons	I-MISC
and	I-MISC
on	I-MISC
Their	I-MISC
Destruction	I-MISC
in	O
December	O
2014	O
and	O
of	O
the	O
Convention	I-MISC
on	I-MISC
the	I-MISC
Prohibition	I-MISC
of	I-MISC
the	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
,	I-MISC
Production	I-MISC
,	I-MISC
Stockpiling	I-MISC
and	I-MISC
Use	I-MISC
of	I-MISC
Chemical	I-MISC
Weapons	I-MISC
and	I-MISC
on	I-MISC
Their	I-MISC
Destruction	I-MISC
.	O

These	O
actions	O
demonstrate	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
's	O
dedicated	O
commitment	O
to	O
the	O
cause	O
of	O
disarmament	O
.	O

Every	O
year	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
introduces	O
a	O
resolution	O
on	O
nuclear	O
disarmament	O
that	O
is	O
adopted	O
with	O
the	O
support	O
of	O
a	O
great	O
majority	O
of	O
Member	O
States	O
.	O

The	O
resolution	O
reflects	O
our	O
firm	O
conviction	O
that	O
our	O
world	O
will	O
be	O
more	O
secure	O
and	O
safer	O
without	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
.	O

As	O
the	O
main	O
sponsor	O
of	O
the	O
resolution	O
,	O
once	O
again	O
we	O
invite	O
all	O
Member	O
States	O
to	O
continue	O
to	O
support	O
the	O
resolution	O
this	O
year	O
.	O

Peacekeeping	O
has	O
been	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
effective	O
tools	O
available	O
to	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
to	O
assist	O
countries	O
struggling	O
on	O
their	O
difficult	O
path	O
from	O
conflict	O
to	O
peace	O
.	O

Today	O
,	O
the	O
nature	O
of	O
conflicts	O
is	O
changing	O
and	O
becomes	O
increasingly	O
complex	O
.	O

We	O
therefore	O
welcome	O
the	O
Secretary-General	O
's	O
timely	O
efforts	O
reviewing	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
peace	O
operations	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
of	O
paramount	O
importance	O
not	O
to	O
weaken	O
the	O
principles	O
enshrined	O
in	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Charter	I-MISC
as	O
well	O
as	O
the	O
cardinal	O
principles	O
of	O
traditional	O
peacekeeping	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

Fifteen	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
we	O
gathered	O
here	O
and	O
committed	O
ourselves	O
to	O
fight	O
against	O
poverty	O
.	O

We	O
set	O
ambitious	O
Millennium	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
Goals	I-MISC
(	O
MDGs	I-MISC
)	O
and	O
targets	O
.	O

While	O
we	O
have	O
lifted	O
more	O
than	O
1	O
billion	O
people	O
out	O
of	O
extreme	O
poverty	O
,	O
some	O
800	O
million	O
people	O
are	O
still	O
excessively	O
poor	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
has	O
made	O
notable	O
progress	O
in	O
poverty	O
and	O
hunger	O
reduction	O
,	O
eliminating	O
gender	O
disparity	O
in	O
basic	O
education	O
,	O
reducing	O
the	O
child	O
mortality	O
rate	O
,	O
improving	O
maternal	O
health	O
and	O
advancing	O
a	O
global	O
partnership	O
for	O
development	O
.	O

The	O
adoption	O
of	O
the	O
2030	I-MISC
Agenda	I-MISC
for	I-MISC
Sustainable	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
this	O
year	O
will	O
take	O
over	O
the	O
unfinished	O
business	O
of	O
the	O
MDGs	I-MISC
.	O

Political	O
commitment	O
,	O
enhanced	O
partnership	O
,	O
the	O
strengthening	O
of	O
capacity	O
and	O
the	O
provision	O
of	O
adequate	O
means	O
of	O
implementation	O
will	O
be	O
keys	O
to	O
success	O
in	O
realizing	O
ambitious	O
Sustainable	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
Goals	I-MISC
(	O
SDGs	I-MISC
)	O
.	O

Unilateral	O
economic	O
sanctions	O
imposed	O
on	O
developing	O
countries	O
have	O
a	O
negative	O
impact	O
on	O
their	O
efforts	O
on	O
behalf	O
of	O
their	O
people	O
.	O

They	O
will	O
also	O
hinder	O
the	O
realization	O
of	O
the	O
SDGs	I-MISC
.	O

We	O
therefore	O
call	O
for	O
the	O
early	O
lifting	O
of	O
such	O
measures	O
.	O

The	O
world	O
is	O
experiencing	O
shifting	O
patterns	O
of	O
rainfall	O
and	O
snowfall	O
,	O
rising	O
temperatures	O
and	O
heavy	O
rainstorms	O
.	O

While	O
we	O
envisage	O
a	O
sustainable	O
and	O
resilient	O
planet	O
,	O
scientific	O
agencies	O
agree	O
that	O
human	O
activities	O
are	O
contributing	O
to	O
climate	O
change	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
the	O
time	O
to	O
translate	O
commitments	O
into	O
action	O
and	O
not	O
to	O
argue	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
crucial	O
that	O
the	O
2015	O
Paris	I-LOC
Climate	I-MISC
Change	I-MISC
Conference	I-MISC
reach	O
a	O
meaningful	O
and	O
universal	O
climate	O
change	O
agreement	O
keeping	O
global	O
warming	O
below	O
2°	O
C	O
.	O

It	O
must	O
also	O
include	O
obligations	O
to	O
provide	O
the	O
least	O
developed	O
countries	O
with	O
adequate	O
and	O
additional	O
financial	O
and	O
technological	O
resources	O
to	O
help	O
address	O
the	O
impacts	O
of	O
climate	O
change	O
.	O

Migration	O
definitely	O
is	O
not	O
a	O
new	O
phenomenon	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
shares	O
the	O
concerns	O
expressed	O
by	O
many	O
in	O
this	O
Hall	O
about	O
the	O
migratiants	O
in	O
Europe	I-LOC
and	O
Asia	I-LOC
.	O

Saving	O
lives	O
on	O
the	O
journey	O
,	O
better	O
legal	O
migration	O
policies	O
,	O
creating	O
better	O
opportunities	O
at	O
home	O
and	O
the	O
suppression	O
of	O
people	O
smuggling	O
and	O
trafficking	O
networks	O
are	O
essential	O
to	O
addressing	O
illegal	O
migration	O
everywhere	O
.	O

We	O
strongly	O
believe	O
that	O
economic	O
migration	O
and	O
human	O
trafficking	O
must	O
be	O
urgently	O
addressed	O
in	O
a	O
comprehensive	O
manner	O
.	O

Let	O
me	O
turn	O
to	O
the	O
state	O
of	O
affairs	O
in	O
my	O
home	O
country	O
,	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
.	O

Democratic	O
reforms	O
started	O
in	O
2011	O
.	O

The	O
Government	O
is	O
now	O
consolidating	O
firm	O
foundations	O
for	O
democracy	O
.	O

The	O
reforms	O
have	O
widened	O
the	O
democratic	O
space	O
,	O
advanced	O
economic	O
performance	O
and	O
narrowed	O
differences	O
with	O
the	O
non-State	O
armed	O
groups	O
.	O

A	O
new	O
political	O
culture	O
of	O
dialogue	O
has	O
taken	O
root	O
as	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
opened	O
its	O
doors	O
to	O
different	O
political	O
forces	O
since	O
the	O
early	O
days	O
of	O
the	O
reforms	O
.	O

Amnesties	O
were	O
granted	O
on	O
several	O
occasions	O
allowing	O
former	O
prisoners	O
to	O
take	O
part	O
in	O
nation-building	O
endeavours	O
.	O

Activists	O
,	O
media	O
people	O
,	O
entrepreneurs	O
and	O
academicians	O
living	O
abroad	O
have	O
returned	O
home	O
.	O

They	O
are	O
working	O
hand	O
in	O
hand	O
with	O
the	O
Government	O
for	O
the	O
common	O
goal	O
of	O
a	O
peaceful	O
and	O
prosperous	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
.	O

Unavoidably	O
,	O
there	O
are	O
still	O
challenges	O
typical	O
of	O
a	O
young	O
democracy	O
,	O
but	O
we	O
believe	O
they	O
are	O
not	O
insurmountable	O
.	O

Economic	O
sector	O
reform	O
has	O
proven	O
successful	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
maintains	O
an	O
average	O
growth	O
rate	O
of	O
8	O
per	O
cent	O
gross	O
domestic	O
product	O
in	O
a	O
four-year	O
time	O
frame	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
is	O
aiming	O
at	O
graduating	O
from	O
the	O
least	O
developed	O
countries	O
(	O
LDCs	O
)	O
group	O
at	O
an	O
early	O
date	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
feasible	O
if	O
we	O
can	O
maintain	O
this	O
average	O
annual	O
growth	O
rate	O
over	O
the	O
coming	O
years	O
.	O

One	O
International	I-ORG
Monetary	I-ORG
Fund	I-ORG
evaluation	O
is	O
that	O
economic	O
prospects	O
of	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
remain	O
strong	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
is	O
a	O
multi-ethnic	O
and	O
multi-religious	O
country	O
where	O
freedom	O
of	O
religion	O
is	O
guaranteed	O
in	O
its	O
State	O
Constitution	O
.	O

The	O
houses	O
of	O
worship	O
of	O
different	O
faiths	O
stand	O
side	O
by	O
side	O
across	O
the	O
country	O
where	O
different	O
communities	O
share	O
the	O
same	O
neighbourhood	O
.	O

The	O
situation	O
in	O
Rakhine	O
state	O
has	O
changed	O
.	O

The	O
Government	O
has	O
managed	O
not	O
only	O
to	O
prevent	O
any	O
new	O
violence	O
but	O
has	O
also	O
started	O
to	O
promote	O
a	O
culture	O
of	O
peace	O
through	O
interfaith	O
dialogue	O
and	O
talks	O
among	O
communities	O
and	O
their	O
leaders	O
.	O

Peace	O
and	O
stability	O
has	O
been	O
restored	O
.	O

As	O
I	O
speak	O
,	O
more	O
than	O
20	O
different	O
aid	O
organizations	O
are	O
providing	O
humanitarian	O
and	O
other	O
assistance	O
in	O
Rakhine	I-LOC
state	O
.	O

We	O
thank	O
the	O
regional	O
and	O
international	O
partners	O
for	O
their	O
kind	O
assistance	O
to	O
humanitarian	O
,	O
resettlement	O
,	O
reintegration	O
and	O
development	O
needs	O
.	O

The	O
Interfaith	I-ORG
Friendship	I-ORG
Group	I-ORG
in	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
has	O
a	O
nationwide	O
set-up	O
and	O
is	O
composed	O
of	O
representatives	O
of	O
all	O
faiths	O
.	O

The	O
Group	O
holds	O
monthly	O
meetings	O
and	O
conveys	O
messages	O
of	O
peace	O
and	O
harmony	O
to	O
the	O
public	O
.	O

They	O
also	O
make	O
religious	O
site	O
visits	O
and	O
provide	O
assistance	O
to	O
the	O
needy	O
as	O
necessary	O
.	O

Various	O
civil	O
￼society	O
organizations	O
are	O
also	O
playing	O
their	O
part	O
in	O
bridging	O
different	O
communities	O
.	O

Peace	O
is	O
a	O
prerequisite	O
for	O
national	O
reconciliation	O
and	O
a	O
cornerstone	O
for	O
building	O
a	O
new	O
democratic	O
society	O
in	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
.	O

Democracy	O
will	O
not	O
flourish	O
in	O
the	O
absence	O
of	O
peace	O
.	O

Without	O
peace	O
,	O
economic	O
development	O
will	O
not	O
be	O
sustained	O
.	O

In	O
this	O
strong	O
conviction	O
,	O
President	O
Thein	I-PER
Sein	I-PER
extended	O
an	O
olive	O
branch	O
to	O
armed	O
groups	O
shortly	O
after	O
taking	O
office	O
with	O
the	O
aim	O
of	O
building	O
sustainable	O
and	O
lasting	O
peace	O
in	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
.	O

Negotiations	O
have	O
been	O
going	O
on	O
to	O
determine	O
the	O
timing	O
and	O
modality	O
for	O
the	O
signing	O
of	O
a	O
nationwide	O
ceasefire	O
agreement	O
.	O

The	O
Government	O
,	O
for	O
its	O
part	O
,	O
is	O
fully	O
prepared	O
and	O
patiently	O
waiting	O
for	O
signature	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
hoping	O
to	O
sign	O
the	O
nationwide	O
ceasefire	O
agreement	O
in	O
the	O
very	O
near	O
future	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
then	O
continue	O
discussions	O
over	O
the	O
framework	O
for	O
a	O
political	O
dialogue	O
.	O

We	O
appreciate	O
the	O
interest	O
in	O
and	O
support	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
for	O
our	O
peace	O
process	O
.	O

The	O
promotion	O
and	O
protection	O
of	O
human	O
rights	O
have	O
always	O
been	O
high	O
on	O
our	O
agenda	O
.	O

Recent	O
reforms	O
in	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
have	O
contributed	O
to	O
our	O
people	O
's	O
ability	O
to	O
better	O
enjoy	O
fundamental	O
human	O
rights	O
and	O
freedoms	O
.	O

Widening	O
the	O
space	O
for	O
people	O
to	O
express	O
their	O
views	O
and	O
opinions	O
has	O
been	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
visible	O
developments	O
in	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
.	O

Greater	O
media	O
freedom	O
has	O
been	O
granted	O
throughout	O
the	O
country	O
by	O
abolishing	O
press	O
censorship	O
and	O
permitting	O
the	O
publication	O
of	O
daily	O
newspapers	O
and	O
weekly	O
journals	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
suffered	O
a	O
devastating	O
natural	O
disaster	O
in	O
late	O
July	O
and	O
August	O
in	O
the	O
wake	O
of	O
Cyclone	O
Komen	I-MISC
.	O

The	O
damage	O
inflicted	O
by	O
floods	O
and	O
landslides	O
from	O
torrential	O
rains	O
this	O
year	O
is	O
more	O
intense	O
and	O
widespread	O
than	O
that	O
of	O
cyclone	O
Nargis	I-MISC
seven	O
years	O
ago	O
.	O

We	O
appreciate	O
the	O
kind	O
assistance	O
given	O
to	O
the	O
affected	O
people	O
by	O
friendly	O
countries	O
near	O
and	O
far	O
,	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
and	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
.	O

This	O
year	O
,	O
2015	O
,	O
is	O
vital	O
for	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
as	O
we	O
will	O
hold	O
general	O
elections	O
on	O
8	O
November	O
.	O

The	O
forthcoming	O
elections	O
will	O
be	O
transparent	O
,	O
free	O
and	O
fair	O
.	O

As	O
such	O
,	O
the	O
Government	O
is	O
working	O
together	O
with	O
local	O
stakeholders	O
and	O
international	O
partners	O
.	O

Over	O
the	O
past	O
four	O
and	O
a	O
half	O
years	O
,	O
we	O
have	O
been	O
able	O
to	O
enhance	O
peace	O
,	O
stability	O
and	O
the	O
rule	O
of	O
law	O
and	O
socioeconomic	O
development	O
in	O
the	O
country	O
.	O

Some	O
may	O
not	O
be	O
content	O
with	O
the	O
pace	O
of	O
our	O
reform	O
process	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
undeniable	O
that	O
we	O
have	O
been	O
able	O
to	O
create	O
better	O
political	O
and	O
socio-economic	O
conditions	O
,	O
foster	O
national	O
reconciliation	O
through	O
a	O
culture	O
of	O
dialogue	O
,	O
and	O
expand	O
space	O
for	O
civil	O
societies	O
in	O
nation-building	O
.	O

In	O
closing	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
important	O
to	O
highlight	O
that	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
's	O
democratic	O
reform	O
process	O
is	O
gaining	O
momentum	O
and	O
moving	O
in	O
the	O
right	O
direction	O
.	O

The	O
international	O
community	O
should	O
continue	O
its	O
support	O
to	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
in	O
an	O
objective	O
and	O
constructive	O
manner	O
.	O

We	O
shall	O
remain	O
fully	O
committed	O
and	O
relentless	O
in	O
our	O
efforts	O
for	O
peace	O
,	O
democracy	O
and	O
inclusive	O
socio-	O
economic	O
development	O
for	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
.	O
