I	O
should	O
like	O
at	O
the	O
outset	O
to	O
express	O
my	O
satisfaction	O
at	O
seeing	O
Mr.	O
Sam	I-PER
Kutesa	I-PER
,	O
Minister	O
for	O
Foreign	O
Affairs	O
of	O
Uganda	I-LOC
,	O
an	O
African	I-MISC
neighbour	O
,	O
brother	O
and	O
friend	O
,	O
presiding	O
over	O
this	O
important	O
session	O
of	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
and	O
to	O
assure	O
him	O
of	O
our	O
full	O
cooperation	O
.	O

I	O
should	O
also	O
like	O
to	O
hail	O
his	O
predecessor	O
the	O
outgoing	O
President	O
of	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
,	O
Mr.	O
John	I-PER
Ashe	I-PER
,	O
and	O
to	O
pay	O
homage	O
to	O
Secretary-General	O
Ban	I-PER
Ki-moon	I-PER
for	O
his	O
work	O
in	O
driving	O
forward	O
the	O
role	O
and	O
missions	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

The	O
theme	O
of	O
the	O
general	O
debate	O
focuses	O
on	O
the	O
future	O
and	O
the	O
prospects	O
for	O
future	O
generations	O
.	O

This	O
reminds	O
us	O
,	O
on	O
the	O
eve	O
of	O
the	O
global	O
summit	O
on	O
the	O
post-2015	O
development	O
agenda	O
and	O
of	O
the	O
seventieth	O
anniversary	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
of	O
the	O
urgency	O
of	O
making	O
a	O
renewed	O
commitment	O
to	O
multilateralism	O
founded	O
on	O
international	O
law	O
.	O

Given	O
the	O
persistence	O
and	O
varied	O
manifestations	O
of	O
the	O
current	O
crisis	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
have	O
a	O
comprehensive	O
vision	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
make	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
a	O
builder	O
of	O
lasting	O
solutions	O
to	O
modern	O
global	O
problems	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
banking	O
on	O
the	O
hope	O
that	O
the	O
new	O
sustainable	O
development	O
goals	O
(SDGs)	I-PER
will	O
contribute	O
to	O
bringing	O
about	O
a	O
world	O
that	O
makes	O
it	O
possible	O
for	O
us	O
effectively	O
to	O
protect	O
human	O
rights	O
,	O
guarantee	O
the	O
inclusive	O
participation	O
of	O
all	O
,	O
and	O
ensure	O
that	O
everyone	O
—	O
particularly	O
those	O
living	O
in	O
the	O
forlorn	O
regions	O
in	O
which	O
40	O
per	O
cent	O
of	O
the	O
poorest	O
people	O
live	O
—	O
shares	O
in	O
prosperity	O
.	O

That	O
was	O
the	O
formulation	O
expressed	O
by	O
the	O
Non-Aligned	I-ORG
Movement	I-ORG
(NAM)	I-ORG
at	O
the	O
seventeenth	O
Ministerial	I-MISC
Conference	I-MISC
hosted	O
by	O
Algeria	I-LOC
in	O
May	O
,	O
in	O
reaffirming	O
the	O
relevance	O
and	O
importance	O
of	O
the	O
right	O
to	O
development	O
and	O
the	O
pressing	O
need	O
to	O
eradicate	O
poverty	O
,	O
which	O
has	O
been	O
identified	O
as	O
a	O
global	O
challenge	O
and	O
a	O
central	O
objective	O
of	O
the	O
post-2015	O
development	O
agenda	O
.	O

Algeria	I-LOC
is	O
pursuing	O
its	O
efforts	O
to	O
reach	O
a	O
comprehensive	O
and	O
ambitious	O
agreement	O
on	O
the	O
SDGs	I-MISC
and	O
on	O
climate	O
,	O
to	O
include	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
case	O
of	O
the	O
latter	O
,	O
desertification	O
and	O
access	O
to	O
genetic	O
resources	O
.	O

Furthermore	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
see	O
the	O
implementation	O
of	O
commitments	O
,	O
whether	O
they	O
are	O
commitments	O
made	O
as	O
official	O
development	O
assistance	O
or	O
within	O
the	O
Monterrey	I-LOC
Consensus	I-MISC
,	O
in	O
the	O
Doha	I-LOC
Declaration	I-MISC
or	O
at	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Conference	I-MISC
on	O
Sustainable	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
.	O

At	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
Algeria	I-LOC
coordinates	O
the	O
NAM	I-ORG
working	O
group	O
on	O
the	O
revitalization	O
of	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
.	O

In	O
that	O
role	O
,	O
Algeria	I-LOC
will	O
continue	O
its	O
efforts	O
to	O
ensure	O
that	O
the	O
NAM	I-ORG
working	O
group	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
the	O
most	O
representative	O
in	O
the	O
international	O
system	O
,	O
assumes	O
its	O
full	O
role	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
,	O
Algeria	I-LOC
will	O
continue	O
to	O
work	O
with	O
its	O
partners	O
in	O
the	O
African	I-MISC
Union	I-LOC
Committee	I-ORG
of	I-ORG
Ten	I-ORG
towards	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
reform	O
,	O
aimed	O
at	O
putting	O
an	O
end	O
to	O
the	O
historical	O
injustices	O
vis-à-vis	O
the	O
African	O
continent	O
,	O
which	O
wants	O
,	O
more	O
than	O
anything	O
,	O
representation	O
and	O
legitimacy	O
in	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
.	O

In	O
that	O
context	O
,	O
the	O
strengthening	O
of	O
cooperation	O
and	O
the	O
multiform	O
partnerships	O
between	O
the	O
African	I-MISC
Union	I-LOC
and	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
should	O
be	O
encouraged	O
,	O
in	O
particular	O
in	O
the	O
context	O
of	O
the	O
many	O
conflicts	O
and	O
crises	O
that	O
continue	O
to	O
afflict	O
Africa	I-LOC
and	O
to	O
slow	O
down	O
the	O
conclusion	O
of	O
its	O
decolonization	O
process	O
.	O

From	O
that	O
perspective	O
,	O
the	O
global	O
review	O
that	O
Mr.	O
Ban	I-PER
Ki-moon	I-PER
is	O
called	O
upon	O
to	O
present	O
in	O
April	O
2015	O
on	O
the	O
question	O
of	O
Western	I-LOC
Sahara	I-LOC
,	O
which	O
pits	O
the	O
Kingdom	I-LOC
of	O
Morocco	I-LOC
against	O
the	O
Frente	I-ORG
Popular	I-ORG
para	I-ORG
la	I-ORG
Liberación	I-ORG
de	I-ORG
Saguía	I-ORG
el-Hamra	I-ORG
y	I-ORG
de	I-ORG
Río	I-ORG
de	I-ORG
Oro	I-ORG
,	O
must	O
honour	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
doctrine	O
in	O
the	O
matter	O
of	O
decolonization	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
stress	O
the	O
importance	O
of	O
the	O
relevant	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
and	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
resolutions	O
.	O

Algeria	I-LOC
supports	O
the	O
inalienable	O
right	O
of	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
Western	I-LOC
Sahara	I-LOC
to	O
self-determination	O
,	O
as	O
has	O
been	O
well	O
established	O
,	O
and	O
in	O
that	O
regard	O
Algeria	I-LOC
encourages	O
the	O
Secretary-General	O
and	O
his	O
Personal	O
Envoy	O
,	O
Ambassador	O
Christopher	I-PER
Ross	I-PER
,	O
to	O
intensify	O
their	O
efforts	O
to	O
ensure	O
the	O
success	O
of	O
that	O
effort	O
to	O
move	O
towards	O
peace	O
.	O

Algeria	I-LOC
is	O
a	O
stakeholder	O
in	O
the	O
common	O
destiny	O
of	O
the	O
peoples	O
of	O
the	O
Maghreb	I-LOC
.	O

Algeria	I-LOC
's	O
own	O
development	O
has	O
been	O
conceived	O
and	O
guided	O
by	O
the	O
desire	O
to	O
achieve	O
the	O
integration	O
of	O
the	O
vast	O
geopolitical	O
space	O
of	O
which	O
it	O
is	O
at	O
the	O
very	O
centre	O
.	O

The	O
policy	O
platform	O
on	O
which	O
President	O
Bouteflika	I-PER
was	O
re-elected	O
and	O
the	O
five-year	O
plan	O
of	O
action	O
of	O
his	O
Administration	O
hinge	O
on	O
a	O
deepening	O
of	O
participative	O
democracy	O
,	O
the	O
modernization	O
of	O
the	O
judiciary	O
,	O
equal	O
opportunities	O
for	O
men	O
and	O
women	O
,	O
and	O
good	O
governance	O
.	O

The	O
economic	O
effort	O
has	O
allocated	O
significant	O
public	O
investment	O
in	O
the	O
sectors	O
of	O
agriculture	O
,	O
industry	O
,	O
energy	O
,	O
the	O
environment	O
and	O
tourism	O
,	O
and	O
into	O
the	O
diversification	O
and	O
modernization	O
of	O
the	O
economy	O
,	O
all	O
based	O
on	O
objectives	O
tied	O
to	O
competitiveness	O
and	O
a	O
substantial	O
relaunching	O
of	O
growth	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
,	O
Algeria	I-LOC
is	O
working	O
to	O
promote	O
development	O
with	O
mutually	O
beneficial	O
strategic	O
partners	O
,	O
based	O
on	O
respect	O
for	O
sovereignty	O
and	O
a	O
balance	O
of	O
interests	O
,	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
bring	O
about	O
opportunities	O
for	O
cooperation	O
and	O
the	O
means	O
of	O
tackling	O
the	O
challenges	O
and	O
threats	O
of	O
a	O
transnational	O
nature	O
.	O

That	O
cooperation	O
excludes	O
unilateral	O
measures	O
such	O
as	O
the	O
embargo	O
imposed	O
on	O
Cuba	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
worrisome	O
spread	O
of	O
the	O
Ebola	I-MISC
virus	O
has	O
been	O
declared	O
by	O
the	O
World	I-ORG
Health	I-ORG
Organization	I-ORG
(WHO)	I-ORG
to	O
be	O
a	O
global	O
health	O
emergency	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
reminds	O
us	O
tragically	O
of	O
the	O
structural	O
precariousness	O
of	O
human	O
security	O
systems	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
of	O
the	O
responsibility	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
in	O
the	O
treatment	O
of	O
health	O
problems	O
that	O
affect	O
the	O
poor	O
,	O
who	O
have	O
no	O
means	O
or	O
role	O
in	O
decision-making	O
.	O

Algeria	I-LOC
adds	O
its	O
voice	O
to	O
that	O
of	O
the	O
Secretary-General	O
in	O
urging	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
agencies	O
and	O
other	O
donors	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
non-governmental	O
organizations	O
,	O
quickly	O
to	O
provide	O
the	O
international	O
assistance	O
needed	O
by	O
the	O
African	I-MISC
countries	O
that	O
have	O
been	O
hit	O
by	O
that	O
scourge	O
.	O

That	O
existential	O
threat	O
is	O
yet	O
another	O
that	O
Africa	I-LOC
must	O
collectively	O
take	O
on	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
ensure	O
its	O
rebirth	O
,	O
and	O
brings	O
with	O
it	O
challenges	O
in	O
the	O
area	O
of	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
behest	O
of	O
the	O
stakeholders	O
in	O
Mali	I-LOC
,	O
Algeria	I-LOC
is	O
undertaking	O
large-scale	O
mediation	O
between	O
the	O
Malian	I-MISC
Government	O
and	O
the	O
movements	O
in	O
the	O
north	O
of	O
that	O
country	O
,	O
working	O
with	O
a	O
team	O
that	O
is	O
representative	O
of	O
Africa	I-LOC
and	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
as	O
a	O
whole	O
.	O

The	O
adoption	O
of	O
a	O
road	O
map	O
for	O
negotiations	O
in	O
the	O
Algiers	I-LOC
process	O
and	O
the	O
declaration	O
of	O
a	O
cessation	O
of	O
hostilities	O
have	O
marked	O
the	O
effort	O
towards	O
the	O
launching	O
of	O
substantial	O
negotiations	O
since	O
1	O
September	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
aim	O
of	O
achieving	O
a	O
comprehensive	O
and	O
definitive	O
peace	O
accord	O
.	O

The	O
launching	O
of	O
those	O
negotiations	O
has	O
been	O
a	O
source	O
of	O
satisfaction	O
and	O
coincides	O
with	O
the	O
freeing	O
of	O
two	O
Algerian	I-MISC
diplomats	O
who	O
had	O
been	O
held	O
hostage	O
for	O
nearly	O
three	O
years	O
by	O
a	O
terrorist	O
organization	O
.	O

I	O
should	O
like	O
to	O
avail	O
myself	O
of	O
this	O
opportunity	O
to	O
pay	O
homage	O
to	O
the	O
memory	O
of	O
our	O
Consul	O
in	O
Gao	I-LOC
and	O
his	O
assistant	O
,	O
Tahar	I-PER
Touati	I-PER
,	O
who	O
lost	O
their	O
lives	O
during	O
their	O
period	O
of	O
captivity	O
.	O

The	O
twofold	O
Algerian	I-MISC
initiative	O
to	O
implement	O
a	O
common	O
plan	O
of	O
action	O
for	O
all	O
of	O
the	O
countries	O
neighbouring	O
Libya	I-LOC
and	O
for	O
launching	O
an	O
inclusive	O
dialogue	O
towards	O
national	O
reconciliation	O
,	O
which	O
would	O
also	O
seek	O
to	O
strengthen	O
State	O
institutions	O
,	O
has	O
made	O
a	O
valuable	O
contribution	O
towards	O
a	O
collective	O
,	O
healthy	O
step	O
towards	O
peace	O
for	O
the	O
Libyan	I-MISC
people	O
,	O
which	O
we	O
very	O
much	O
wish	O
for	O
them	O
.	O

The	O
difficult	O
state	O
of	O
affairs	O
in	O
our	O
region	O
requires	O
a	O
stepping	O
up	O
of	O
efforts	O
in	O
the	O
fight	O
against	O
terrorist	O
groups	O
in	O
the	O
Sahel	I-LOC
and	O
their	O
established	O
links	O
to	O
drug	O
trafficking	O
networks	O
and	O
transnational	O
organized	O
crime	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
global	O
forum	O
of	O
the	O
fight	O
against	O
terrorism	O
,	O
Algeria	I-LOC
will	O
continue	O
to	O
cooperate	O
,	O
including	O
in	O
its	O
work	O
as	O
co-Chair	O
of	O
the	O
Working	I-ORG
Group	I-ORG
on	I-ORG
the	I-ORG
Sahel	I-ORG
,	O
and	O
will	O
focus	O
on	O
securing	O
borders	O
and	O
on	O
preventing	O
ransom-seeking	O
abductions	O
by	O
terrorist	O
organizations	O
,	O
bearing	O
in	O
mind	O
the	O
recommendations	O
from	O
the	O
Algiers	I-LOC
workshop	O
in	O
September	O
2013	O
and	O
the	O
relevant	O
resolutions	O
of	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
and	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
.	O

In	O
that	O
spirit	O
,	O
Algeria	I-LOC
notes	O
with	O
interest	O
the	O
results	O
of	O
the	O
high-level	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
meeting	O
on	O
terrorism	O
and	O
foreign	O
combatants	O
,	O
convened	O
on	O
the	O
initiative	O
of	O
President	O
Obama	I-LOC
(S/PV	O
.	O
7272)	O
.	O

We	O
also	O
take	O
note	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
mobilization	O
against	O
transborder	O
terrorism	O
on	O
a	O
large	O
scale	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
relevant	O
to	O
Iraq	I-LOC
and	O
Syria	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
execution	O
of	O
French	O
citizen	O
Hervé	I-PER
Gourdel	I-PER
in	O
Algeria	I-LOC
underscores	O
the	O
need	O
to	O
strengthen	O
the	O
fight	O
against	O
terrorism	O
in	O
all	O
its	O
forms	O
.	O

The	O
earth-shattering	O
developments	O
that	O
affect	O
the	O
lives	O
of	O
people	O
in	O
the	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
add	O
new	O
questions	O
with	O
regard	O
to	O
the	O
uninterrupted	O
role	O
played	O
by	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
vis-à-vis	O
the	O
tragedy	O
inflicted	O
upon	O
the	O
brotherly	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
people	O
.	O

The	O
history	O
of	O
humankind	O
shows	O
that	O
armed	O
conflicts	O
give	O
rise	O
to	O
other	O
conflicts	O
and	O
that	O
only	O
by	O
working	O
towards	O
justice	O
within	O
law	O
and	O
morality	O
can	O
we	O
find	O
lasting	O
solutions	O
.	O

The	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
question	O
and	O
the	O
Syrian	I-MISC
crisis	O
must	O
be	O
approached	O
along	O
those	O
lines	O
.	O

I	O
should	O
also	O
like	O
to	O
avail	O
myself	O
of	O
this	O
opportunity	O
to	O
pay	O
homage	O
to	O
the	O
efforts	O
of	O
my	O
compatriot	O
,	O
Mr.	O
Lakhdar	I-PER
Brahimi	I-PER
,	O
and	O
to	O
reiterate	O
our	O
support	O
to	O
his	O
successor	O
,	O
Mr.	O
Staffan	I-PER
de	I-PER
Mistura	I-PER
.	O

Let	O
there	O
be	O
no	O
doubt	O
that	O
much	O
remains	O
to	O
be	O
done	O
when	O
it	O
comes	O
to	O
freeing	O
the	O
world	O
of	O
weapons	O
of	O
mass	O
destruction	O
.	O

Algeria	I-LOC
,	O
as	O
a	O
member	O
of	O
the	O
Human	I-ORG
Rights	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
,	O
is	O
motivated	O
by	O
a	O
strong	O
sense	O
of	O
responsibility	O
to	O
participate	O
actively	O
in	O
the	O
promotion	O
of	O
the	O
universal	O
and	O
interdependent	O
nature	O
of	O
human	O
rights	O
.	O

The	O
President	O
of	O
the	O
Republic	O
,	O
His	O
Excellency	O
Mr.	O
Bouteflika	I-PER
,	O
and	O
the	O
Algerian	I-MISC
authorities	O
are	O
working	O
hard	O
to	O
improve	O
the	O
living	O
conditions	O
of	O
Algerian	I-MISC
citizens	O
in	O
many	O
different	O
areas	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
laws	O
that	O
criminalize	O
violence	O
against	O
women	O
and	O
children	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
are	O
strengthening	O
the	O
protection	O
of	O
the	O
rights	O
of	O
divorced	O
women	O
and	O
other	O
legislative	O
efforts	O
that	O
add	O
to	O
our	O
political	O
and	O
institutional	O
success	O
in	O
supporting	O
Algerian	I-MISC
women	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
been	O
addressing	O
such	O
matters	O
in	O
our	O
elected	O
bodies	O
and	O
our	O
central	O
Government	O
.	O

The	O
celebration	O
in	O
2015	O
of	O
the	O
seventieth	O
anniversary	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
should	O
be	O
an	O
opportunity	O
to	O
renew	O
the	O
commitment	O
of	O
all	O
Member	O
States	O
to	O
bring	O
new	O
and	O
stronger	O
vigour	O
,	O
efficacy	O
and	O
credibility	O
to	O
multilateralism	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
the	O
joint	O
responsibility	O
to	O
work	O
to	O
establish	O
a	O
world	O
that	O
is	O
safer	O
and	O
fairer	O
and	O
shows	O
more	O
solidarity	O
.	O

This	O
powerful	O
juncture	O
,	O
at	O
which	O
we	O
bring	O
together	O
all	O
of	O
our	O
peoples	O
within	O
the	O
fold	O
of	O
our	O
founding	O
values	O
,	O
should	O
also	O
be	O
confirmed	O
by	O
action	O
.	O

There	O
are	O
apprehensions	O
,	O
uncertainties	O
and	O
challenges	O
tied	O
to	O
fear	O
and	O
need	O
,	O
but	O
if	O
we	O
face	O
up	O
to	O
them	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
will	O
certainly	O
live	O
up	O
to	O
its	O
role	O
as	O
the	O
last	O
haven	O
for	O
the	O
hope	O
of	O
humankind	O
in	O
a	O
better	O
future	O
.	O
