Since	O
the	O
last	O
time	O
we	O
gathered	O
here	O
in	O
this	O
great	O
Hall	O
,	O
we	O
have	O
passed	O
a	O
year	O
of	O
great	O
hopes	O
and	O
grave	O
fears	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
witnessed	O
the	O
hope-inspiring	O
glory	O
of	O
human	O
accomplishment	O
at	O
the	O
Olympic	I-MISC
Games	I-MISC
in	O
Beijing	I-LOC
but	O
shuddered	O
at	O
crumbling	O
stock	O
and	O
housing	O
markets	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
a	O
growing	O
global	O
understanding	O
on	O
climate	O
change	O
and	O
the	O
issues	O
relevant	O
to	O
it	O
,	O
but	O
seen	O
millions	O
of	O
lives	O
threatened	O
by	O
the	O
shortage	O
of	O
food	O
in	O
many	O
countries	O
and	O
witnessed	O
with	O
disbelief	O
the	O
brutal	O
slaughter	O
of	O
innocent	O
people	O
at	O
the	O
hands	O
of	O
terrorists	O
in	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
,	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
,	O
India	I-LOC
,	O
Algeria	I-LOC
and	O
several	O
other	O
parts	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

Since	O
I	O
spoke	O
at	O
this	O
rostrum	O
in	O
the	O
last	O
session	O
of	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
,	O
my	O
country	O
,	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
,	O
has	O
grappled	O
with	O
a	O
number	O
of	O
important	O
challenges	O
,	O
none	O
more	O
troubling	O
than	O
the	O
problem	O
of	O
international	O
terrorism	O
.	O

Terrorist	O
forces	O
have	O
significantly	O
increased	O
their	O
attacks	O
and	O
brutality	O
,	O
and	O
enjoyed	O
freedom	O
in	O
their	O
sanctuaries	O
.	O

While	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
has	O
borne	O
the	O
brunt	O
of	O
terrorist	O
violence	O
,	O
the	O
scourge	O
has	O
now	O
spread	O
like	O
a	O
wildfire	O
across	O
the	O
wider	O
region	O
.	O

In	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
,	O
where	O
,	O
until	O
recently	O
,	O
extremist	O
circles	O
remained	O
mainly	O
focused	O
on	O
destabilizing	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
,	O
today	O
terrorist	O
violence	O
is	O
unfortunately	O
also	O
directed	O
within	O
Pakistani	I-MISC
territory	O
and	O
against	O
the	O
Pakistani	I-MISC
people	O
.	O

Daily	O
acts	O
of	O
intimidation	O
and	O
violence	O
against	O
communities	O
in	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
and	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
,	O
in	O
particular	O
on	O
both	O
sides	O
of	O
the	O
Durand	I-LOC
Line	I-LOC
,	O
the	O
killing	O
of	O
political	O
and	O
tribal	O
leaders	O
and	O
the	O
burning	O
of	O
schools	O
are	O
the	O
upshots	O
of	O
the	O
continued	O
spawning	O
and	O
spread	O
of	O
terrorism	O
and	O
extremism	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
.	O

The	O
callous	O
attack	O
on	O
the	O
Marriot	O
hotel	O
in	O
Islamabad	I-LOC
over	O
the	O
weekend	O
,	O
the	O
bombing	O
of	O
the	O
Indian	I-MISC
Embassy	O
in	O
Kabul	I-LOC
and	O
the	O
terrorist	O
attacks	O
in	O
the	O
Indian	I-MISC
cities	O
of	O
Bangalore	I-LOC
and	O
Ahmedabad	I-LOC
were	O
the	O
most	O
disturbing	O
demonstration	O
of	O
terrorists'	O
growing	O
reach	O
.	O

Undoubtedly	O
,	O
terrorism	O
will	O
not	O
go	O
away	O
until	O
we	O
dismantle	O
the	O
elaborate	O
institutional	O
support	O
terrorists	O
enjoy	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
and	O
eliminate	O
their	O
secure	O
sanctuaries	O
.	O

That	O
will	O
be	O
possible	O
only	O
if	O
we	O
engage	O
in	O
sincere	O
regional	O
and	O
international	O
cooperation	O
.	O

The	O
democratic	O
transition	O
in	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
,	O
heralded	O
by	O
the	O
historic	O
elections	O
of	O
last	O
February	O
,	O
has	O
been	O
a	O
most	O
promising	O
development	O
in	O
our	O
region	O
.	O

We	O
in	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
have	O
warmly	O
welcomed	O
the	O
inauguration	O
of	O
the	O
civilian	O
democratic	O
Government	O
.	O

In	O
particular	O
,	O
I	O
take	O
the	O
opportunity	O
to	O
once	O
again	O
congratulate	O
my	O
brother	O
,	O
President	O
Asif	I-PER
Ali	I-PER
Zardari	I-PER
,	O
on	O
his	O
election	O
as	O
the	O
President	O
of	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
.	O

I	O
assure	O
my	O
brothers	O
,	O
President	O
Zardari	I-PER
and	O
Prime	O
Minister	O
Gillani	I-PER
,	O
that	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
stands	O
ready	O
to	O
take	O
several	O
steps	O
for	O
each	O
single	O
step	O
that	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
will	O
take	O
to	O
address	O
the	O
challenge	O
of	O
radicalism	O
and	O
terrorism	O
.	O

To	O
the	O
extent	O
that	O
terrorism	O
in	O
our	O
region	O
continues	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
global	O
threat	O
,	O
evolving	O
in	O
nature	O
and	O
tactics	O
,	O
the	O
struggle	O
against	O
it	O
must	O
continue	O
unabated	O
.	O

In	O
this	O
context	O
,	O
I	O
recall	O
with	O
appreciation	O
this	O
year	O
's	O
North	I-ORG
Atlantic	I-ORG
Treaty	I-ORG
Organization	I-ORG
(NATO)	I-ORG
Summit	I-MISC
in	O
Bucharest	I-LOC
,	O
where	O
around	O
40	O
countries	O
with	O
existing	O
military	O
commitments	O
in	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
once	O
again	O
reiterated	O
their	O
strong	O
resolve	O
to	O
stay	O
the	O
course	O
.	O

Among	O
the	O
most	O
significant	O
outcomes	O
of	O
the	O
summit	O
was	O
the	O
emphasis	O
on	O
the	O
Afghanization	I-MISC
of	O
the	O
security	O
sector	O
as	O
a	O
measure	O
to	O
ensure	O
sustainability	O
and	O
enhanced	O
effectiveness	O
.	O

To	O
that	O
end	O
,	O
I	O
call	O
for	O
a	O
redoubling	O
of	O
efforts	O
by	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
aimed	O
at	O
enabling	O
the	O
Afghan	I-MISC
national	O
security	O
institutions	O
,	O
both	O
the	O
army	O
and	O
the	O
police	O
,	O
to	O
take	O
on	O
a	O
greater	O
share	O
of	O
the	O
war	O
against	O
terrorism	O
and	O
for	O
the	O
protection	O
of	O
our	O
people	O
.	O

Above	O
all	O
,	O
Afghanization	I-MISC
of	O
military	O
operations	O
is	O
vital	O
if	O
the	O
problem	O
of	O
civilian	O
casualties	O
is	O
to	O
be	O
addressed	O
effectively	O
.	O

The	O
continuation	O
of	O
civilian	O
casualties	O
could	O
seriously	O
undermine	O
the	O
legitimacy	O
of	O
the	O
fight	O
against	O
terrorism	O
and	O
the	O
credibility	O
of	O
the	O
Afghan	I-MISC
people	O
's	O
partnership	O
with	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
.	O

Therefore	O
,	O
while	O
terrorism	O
and	O
a	O
persistent	O
environment	O
of	O
insecurity	O
are	O
at	O
work	O
to	O
subvert	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
's	O
growth	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
do	O
what	O
it	O
takes	O
to	O
win	O
the	O
battle	O
of	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
's	O
economic	O
development	O
.	O

Last	O
June	O
,	O
my	O
Government	O
launched	O
the	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
National	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
Strategy	I-MISC
at	O
the	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
donors	O
conference	O
in	O
Paris	I-LOC
.	O

If	O
the	O
pledges	O
made	O
at	O
the	O
conference	O
are	O
translated	O
into	O
timely	O
commitments	O
,	O
I	O
am	O
confident	O
that	O
we	O
will	O
attain	O
the	O
development	O
goals	O
set	O
out	O
in	O
our	O
Strategy	O
.	O

On	O
behalf	O
of	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
,	O
I	O
thank	O
President	O
Nicholas	I-PER
Sarkozy	I-PER
of	O
France	I-LOC
for	O
his	O
leadership	O
in	O
excellently	O
organizing	O
the	O
Paris	I-LOC
conference	O
.	O

I	O
also	O
thank	O
the	O
United	I-LOC
States	I-LOC
and	O
all	O
the	O
other	O
countries	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
that	O
pledged	O
generously	O
towards	O
the	O
implementation	O
of	O
the	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
National	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
Strategy	I-MISC
.	O

As	O
in	O
the	O
security	O
sector	O
,	O
Afghanization	I-MISC
of	O
the	O
development	O
process	O
is	O
the	O
key	O
not	O
just	O
to	O
the	O
goal	O
of	O
ensuring	O
ownership	O
but	O
also	O
to	O
the	O
effective	O
implementation	O
of	O
our	O
Development	I-MISC
Strategy	I-MISC
.	O

Afghanization	I-MISC
of	O
the	O
development	O
process	O
can	O
be	O
achieved	O
through	O
a	O
meaningful	O
commitment	O
by	O
our	O
friends	O
and	O
donors	O
to	O
aid	O
effectiveness	O
.	O

In	O
that	O
context	O
,	O
while	O
urging	O
a	O
shift	O
away	O
from	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
parallel	O
structures	O
and	O
wasteful	O
mechanisms	O
,	O
I	O
strongly	O
endorse	O
the	O
role	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
and	O
the	O
special	O
representative	O
of	O
the	O
Secretary-General	O
,	O
Mr.	O
Kai	I-PER
Eide	I-PER
,	O
in	O
coordinating	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
's	O
participation	O
in	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
's	O
development	O
and	O
State-building	O
processes	O
.	O

Thanks	O
to	O
the	O
selfless	O
sacrifices	O
of	O
men	O
and	O
women	O
of	O
Member	O
States	O
and	O
the	O
determination	O
and	O
sacrifices	O
of	O
our	O
own	O
people	O
,	O
the	O
journey	O
of	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
's	O
reconstruction	O
is	O
resolutely	O
under	O
way	O
.	O

Today	O
our	O
people	O
are	O
more	O
educated	O
,	O
healthier	O
,	O
better	O
off	O
and	O
more	O
optimistic	O
about	O
their	O
future	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
built	O
thousands	O
of	O
new	O
schools	O
and	O
reconstructed	O
many	O
more	O
,	O
where	O
millions	O
of	O
our	O
youngsters	O
go	O
to	O
school	O
and	O
prepare	O
for	O
the	O
responsibilities	O
of	O
tomorrow	O
.	O

Our	O
rapid	O
economic	O
growth	O
,	O
with	O
double-digit	O
growth	O
rates	O
almost	O
every	O
year	O
,	O
has	O
resulted	O
in	O
higher	O
income	O
and	O
better	O
living	O
conditions	O
for	O
our	O
people	O
.	O

Our	O
rural	O
development	O
programmes	O
have	O
improved	O
lives	O
in	O
thousands	O
of	O
our	O
villages	O
that	O
had	O
never	O
before	O
seen	O
an	O
agent	O
of	O
the	O
State	O
among	O
them	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
also	O
taken	O
a	O
number	O
of	O
legal	O
and	O
institutional	O
measures	O
to	O
intensify	O
our	O
anti-corruption	O
efforts	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
establishing	O
the	O
High	I-ORG
Office	I-ORG
of	I-ORG
Oversight	I-ORG
and	I-ORG
Anti-Corruption	I-ORG
,	O
including	O
special	O
units	O
in	O
the	O
Office	O
of	O
the	O
Attorney-General	O
and	O
in	O
the	O
judiciary	O
to	O
oversee	O
efforts	O
aimed	O
at	O
eliminating	O
corruption	O
through	O
preventive	O
,	O
educational	O
and	O
enforcement	O
measures	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
committed	O
to	O
ensuring	O
more	O
concrete	O
results	O
in	O
the	O
coming	O
years	O
.	O

Also	O
very	O
important	O
,	O
on	O
counter-narcotics	O
,	O
this	O
year	O
we	O
have	O
registered	O
a	O
20	O
per	O
cent	O
decline	O
in	O
total	O
opium	O
production	O
,	O
while	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
poppy-free	O
provinces	O
has	O
reached	O
18	O
,	O
making	O
50	O
per	O
cent	O
of	O
the	O
country	O
virtually	O
poppy-free	O
.	O

The	O
key	O
to	O
sustaining	O
our	O
success	O
will	O
be	O
ensuring	O
alternative	O
livelihoods	O
for	O
our	O
farmers	O
,	O
investing	O
to	O
a	O
greater	O
extent	O
in	O
law	O
enforcement	O
and	O
interdiction	O
and	O
,	O
above	O
all	O
,	O
addressing	O
the	O
far	O
greater	O
dimensions	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
drug	O
trade	O
that	O
lie	O
outside	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
,	O
such	O
as	O
reduction	O
of	O
demand	O
in	O
foreign	O
markets	O
and	O
stricter	O
border	O
controls	O
.	O

Our	O
efforts	O
in	O
counter-narcotics	O
and	O
in	O
other	O
areas	O
have	O
been	O
complicated	O
by	O
the	O
acute	O
shortage	O
of	O
food	O
within	O
the	O
country	O
.	O

In	O
collaboration	O
with	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
we	O
have	O
launched	O
a	O
humanitarian	O
appeal	O
that	O
we	O
hope	O
will	O
receive	O
a	O
timely	O
response	O
from	O
our	O
partners	O
in	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
.	O

The	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Charter	I-MISC
promises	O
freedom	O
,	O
justice	O
,	O
a	O
dignified	O
life	O
,	O
security	O
and	O
peace	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
is	O
incumbent	O
on	O
all	O
of	O
us	O
to	O
work	O
together	O
to	O
ensure	O
that	O
those	O
promises	O
are	O
kept	O
.	O

Today	O
,	O
there	O
are	O
still	O
too	O
many	O
corners	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
where	O
conflict	O
and	O
tension	O
are	O
putting	O
the	O
lives	O
and	O
livelihoods	O
of	O
millions	O
of	O
people	O
in	O
jeopardy	O
.	O

We	O
deeply	O
sympathize	O
with	O
our	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
brothers	O
and	O
sisters	O
and	O
their	O
struggle	O
and	O
suffering	O
.	O

We	O
urge	O
a	O
just	O
and	O
comprehensive	O
settlement	O
that	O
fully	O
realizes	O
the	O
rights	O
of	O
the	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
people	O
,	O
including	O
their	O
right	O
to	O
an	O
independent	O
State	O
,	O
living	O
in	O
peace	O
,	O
side	O
by	O
side	O
with	O
the	O
State	O
of	O
Israel	I-LOC
.	O

Today	O
,	O
once	O
again	O
,	O
this	O
Assembly	I-ORG
session	O
has	O
brought	O
us	O
together	O
at	O
a	O
time	O
when	O
our	O
world	O
is	O
poised	O
between	O
great	O
opportunities	O
and	O
menacing	O
challenges	O
.	O

I	O
am	O
confident	O
that	O
we	O
will	O
make	O
use	O
of	O
our	O
growing	O
collective	O
ability	O
as	O
a	O
community	O
of	O
nations	O
to	O
do	O
what	O
is	O
right	O
for	O
the	O
betterment	O
of	O
our	O
world	O
.	O
