This	O
year	O
has	O
been	O
an	O
unusual	O
one	O
in	O
China	I-LOC
's	O
development	O
.	O

China	I-LOC
's	O
new	O
central	O
collective	O
leadership	O
has	O
put	O
forward	O
the	O
concept	O
of	O
the	O
"	O
Chinese	I-MISC
dream	O
"	O
,	O
a	O
dream	O
of	O
the	O
great	O
renewal	O
of	O
the	O
Chinese	I-MISC
nation	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
is	O
leading	O
the	O
1	O
.	O
3	O
billion	O
Chinese	I-MISC
people	O
in	O
an	O
endeavour	O
to	O
fulfil	O
the	O
two	O
centennial	O
goals	O
,	O
namely	O
,	O
to	O
finish	O
building	O
a	O
moderately	O
prosperous	O
society	O
in	O
all	O
respects	O
by	O
2020	O
and	O
to	O
turn	O
China	I-LOC
into	O
a	O
modern	O
socialist	O
country	O
by	O
the	O
mid-twenty-first	O
century	O
.	O

Having	O
experienced	O
profound	O
changes	O
in	O
the	O
past	O
5	O
,000	O
years	O
and	O
especially	O
the	O
past	O
century	O
,	O
China	I-LOC
has	O
reached	O
a	O
new	O
historical	O
starting	O
point	O
today	O
.	O

What	O
development	O
path	O
will	O
China	I-LOC
take	O
in	O
the	O
future	O
?	O

What	O
domestic	O
and	O
foreign	O
policies	O
will	O
it	O
pursue	O
?	O

And	O
what	O
kind	O
of	O
international	O
role	O
will	O
it	O
play	O
?	O

I	O
understand	O
that	O
those	O
questions	O
are	O
of	O
great	O
interest	O
to	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
.	O

As	O
the	O
Foreign	O
Minister	O
of	O
the	O
new	O
Chinese	I-MISC
Government	O
,	O
I	O
wish	O
to	O
give	O
an	O
emphatic	O
answer	O
to	O
each	O
of	O
them	O
.	O

China	I-LOC
will	O
stay	O
firmly	O
on	O
the	O
path	O
of	O
peaceful	O
development	O
.	O

China	I-LOC
's	O
rapid	O
development	O
over	O
the	O
years	O
has	O
given	O
rise	O
to	O
worries	O
that	O
China	I-LOC
might	O
follow	O
the	O
old	O
pattern	O
of	O
wealth	O
breeding	O
arrogance	O
and	O
strength	O
leading	O
to	O
hegemony	O
,	O
and	O
various	O
versions	O
of	O
the	O
China	I-LOC
threat	O
theory	O
have	O
surfaced	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
what	O
happened	O
in	O
the	O
past	O
should	O
not	O
be	O
applied	O
to	O
today	O
's	O
China	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
outdated	O
Cold	I-MISC
War	I-MISC
mentality	O
has	O
no	O
place	O
in	O
the	O
new	O
era	O
of	O
globalization	O
.	O

The	O
Chinese	I-MISC
nation	O
loves	O
peace	O
and	O
the	O
Chinese	I-MISC
culture	O
values	O
harmony	O
.	O

Throughout	O
history	O
,	O
the	O
Chinese	I-MISC
people	O
have	O
always	O
embraced	O
international	O
exchanges	O
and	O
trade	O
,	O
not	O
foreign	O
aggression	O
and	O
expansion	O
,	O
and	O
have	O
adhered	O
to	O
the	O
patriotic	O
resolve	O
to	O
defend	O
the	O
homeland	O
rather	O
than	O
the	O
colonialist	O
doctrine	O
of	O
seizing	O
new	O
territories	O
.	O

The	O
culture	O
of	O
a	O
country	O
determines	O
its	O
values	O
,	O
and	O
its	O
history	O
points	O
the	O
way	O
to	O
its	O
future	O
.	O

Close	O
to	O
40	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
it	O
was	O
from	O
this	O
rsotrum	O
that	O
the	O
Chinese	O
leader	O
Deng	I-PER
Xiaoping	I-PER
solemnly	O
declared	O
on	O
behalf	O
of	O
the	O
Chinese	I-MISC
Government	O
that	O
China	I-LOC
would	O
never	O
seek	O
hegemony	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

Today	O
,	O
his	O
statement	O
remains	O
our	O
unchanging	O
commitment	O
and	O
conviction	O
.	O

China	I-LOC
has	O
honoured	O
and	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
honour	O
its	O
promise	O
and	O
remain	O
a	O
staunch	O
force	O
for	O
upholding	O
world	O
peace	O
.	O

China	I-LOC
pursues	O
peaceful	O
development	O
and	O
calls	O
on	O
all	O
other	O
countries	O
to	O
follow	O
the	O
same	O
path	O
.	O

Since	O
the	O
beginning	O
of	O
reform	O
and	O
opening	O
up	O
,	O
China	I-LOC
has	O
become	O
increasingly	O
interdependent	O
with	O
the	O
global	O
economy	O
and	O
integrated	O
into	O
the	O
international	O
system	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
committed	O
to	O
working	O
with	O
others	O
to	O
establish	O
a	O
new	O
type	O
of	O
international	O
relations	O
,	O
based	O
on	O
win-win	O
cooperation	O
,	O
and	O
to	O
seek	O
the	O
peaceful	O
resolution	O
of	O
international	O
and	O
regional	O
disputes	O
.	O

With	O
regard	O
to	O
China	I-LOC
's	O
disputes	O
with	O
some	O
countries	O
over	O
territorial	O
sovereignty	O
and	O
maritime	O
rights	O
and	O
interests	O
,	O
we	O
sincerely	O
hope	O
to	O
resolve	O
them	O
in	O
accordance	O
with	O
proper	O
procedures	O
,	O
through	O
negotiation	O
and	O
consultation	O
with	O
the	O
countries	O
directly	O
involved	O
.	O

Those	O
disputes	O
that	O
cannot	O
be	O
resolved	O
now	O
can	O
be	O
shelved	O
for	O
future	O
resolution	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
our	O
consistent	O
position	O
and	O
practice	O
.	O

On	O
the	O
other	O
hand	O
,	O
we	O
will	O
,	O
whatever	O
the	O
circumstances	O
,	O
firmly	O
safeguard	O
China	I-LOC
's	O
sovereignty	O
and	O
territorial	O
integrity	O
and	O
resolutely	O
uphold	O
China	I-LOC
's	O
legitimate	O
and	O
lawful	O
rights	O
and	O
interests	O
.	O

China	I-LOC
will	O
remain	O
committed	O
to	O
reform	O
,	O
to	O
opening	O
up	O
and	O
to	O
sustainable	O
development	O
.	O

It	O
has	O
been	O
five	O
years	O
since	O
the	O
outbreak	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
financial	O
crisis	O
.	O

The	O
global	O
economy	O
is	O
back	O
on	O
the	O
right	O
track	O
to	O
recovery	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
foundations	O
of	O
the	O
recovery	O
are	O
not	O
solid	O
and	O
the	O
speed	O
is	O
not	O
fast	O
enough	O
.	O

The	O
root	O
causes	O
of	O
the	O
financial	O
crisis	O
have	O
yet	O
to	O
be	O
removed	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
structural	O
problems	O
of	O
developed	O
countries	O
remain	O
unresolved	O
.	O

The	O
adjustment	O
of	O
unconventional	O
monetary	O
policies	O
from	O
the	O
outside	O
,	O
coupled	O
with	O
other	O
factors	O
,	O
have	O
posed	O
new	O
challenges	O
and	O
the	O
risk	O
of	O
financial	O
market	O
volatility	O
to	O
emerging	O
market	O
countries	O
.	O

Where	O
the	O
Chinese	I-MISC
economy	O
is	O
heading	O
engages	O
both	O
domestic	O
and	O
international	O
attention	O
.	O

In	O
that	O
regard	O
,	O
I	O
wish	O
to	O
inform	O
the	O
Assembly	I-ORG
that	O
both	O
the	O
fundamentals	O
and	O
the	O
overall	O
performance	O
of	O
China	I-LOC
's	O
economy	O
are	O
sound	O
,	O
and	O
China	I-LOC
's	O
development	O
prospects	O
are	O
bright	O
.	O

The	O
leading	O
indicators	O
of	O
the	O
Chinese	I-MISC
economy	O
are	O
generally	O
good	O
,	O
and	O
China	I-LOC
leads	O
the	O
major	O
economies	O
in	O
growth	O
rate	O
.	O

In	O
pursuit	O
of	O
progress	O
while	O
maintaining	O
stability	O
,	O
the	O
Chinese	I-MISC
Government	O
has	O
followed	O
a	O
macroeconomic	O
policy	O
that	O
addresses	O
both	O
immediate	O
and	O
long-term	O
needs	O
and	O
has	O
adopted	O
a	O
series	O
of	O
innovative	O
policy	O
measures	O
with	O
a	O
view	O
to	O
promoing	O
steady	O
growth	O
,	O
economic	O
structural	O
adjustment	O
and	O
reform	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
vigorously	O
pursuing	O
reform	O
,	O
opening	O
up	O
,	O
deepening	O
economic	O
structural	O
adjustment	O
and	O
accelerating	O
the	O
shift	O
in	O
our	O
growth	O
model	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
implementing	O
the	O
basic	O
State	O
policy	O
of	O
resource	O
conservation	O
and	O
environmental	O
protection	O
and	O
promoting	O
green	O
,	O
circular	O
and	O
low-carbon	O
development	O
to	O
build	O
a	O
sound	O
ecological	O
environment	O
and	O
a	O
beautiful	O
China	I-LOC
.	O

With	O
its	O
increasing	O
economic	O
output	O
and	O
its	O
changing	O
growth	O
model	O
,	O
China	I-LOC
's	O
economy	O
has	O
entered	O
a	O
phase	O
of	O
high-to-medium	O
growth	O
rate	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
dictated	O
by	O
the	O
law	O
of	O
economics	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
will	O
ensure	O
the	O
sustained	O
and	O
healthy	O
growth	O
of	O
the	O
Chinese	I-MISC
economy	O
.	O

The	O
Chinese	I-MISC
economy	O
is	O
being	O
upgraded	O
,	O
and	O
its	O
future	O
growth	O
will	O
deliver	O
major	O
dividends	O
in	O
four	O
areas	O
as	O
a	O
result	O
of	O
industrialization	O
,	O
information	O
technology	O
application	O
,	O
a	O
new	O
type	O
of	O
urbanization	O
and	O
agricultural	O
modernization	O
;	O
reform	O
and	O
innovation	O
;	O
structural	O
readjustment	O
;	O
and	O
further	O
opening	O
up	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
projected	O
that	O
in	O
the	O
coming	O
five	O
years	O
,	O
China	I-LOC
's	O
imports	O
of	O
commodities	O
will	O
exceed	O
$10	O
trillion	O
,	O
its	O
overseas	O
investment	O
will	O
reach	O
$500	O
billion	O
,	O
and	O
Chinese	I-MISC
tourists	O
will	O
make	O
over	O
400	O
million	O
outbound	O
visits	O
.	O

That	O
will	O
give	O
stronger	O
impetus	O
to	O
the	O
world	O
economy	O
and	O
bring	O
an	O
increasing	O
number	O
of	O
tangible	O
benefits	O
to	O
other	O
countries	O
.	O

China	I-LOC
will	O
firmly	O
promote	O
reform	O
of	O
the	O
global	O
governance	O
system	O
with	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
at	O
its	O
core	O
.	O

The	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
is	O
a	O
big	O
stage	O
for	O
all	O
countries	O
to	O
conduct	O
consultation	O
and	O
cooperation	O
with	O
one	O
another	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
also	O
a	O
big	O
family	O
where	O
people	O
of	O
all	O
countries	O
are	O
brought	O
together	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
our	O
consistent	O
position	O
that	O
the	O
purposes	O
and	O
principles	O
of	O
the	O
Charter	I-MISC
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
form	O
the	O
cornerstone	O
of	O
current	O
international	O
relations	O
and	O
provide	O
safeguards	O
for	O
world	O
peace	O
and	O
stability	O
.	O

Respecting	O
national	O
sovereignty	O
and	O
opposing	O
interference	O
in	O
internal	O
affairs	O
,	O
safeguarding	O
peace	O
and	O
opposing	O
aggression	O
,	O
and	O
promoting	O
equality	O
and	O
opposing	O
power	O
politics	O
;	O
those	O
are	O
important	O
principles	O
that	O
must	O
be	O
observed	O
.	O

China	I-LOC
is	O
committed	O
to	O
promoting	O
democracy	O
in	O
international	O
relations	O
and	O
the	O
trend	O
toward	O
a	O
multipolar	O
world	O
.	O

We	O
also	O
call	O
for	O
the	O
reform	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
monetary	O
and	O
financial	O
systems	O
and	O
want	O
the	O
role	O
of	O
the	O
World	I-ORG
Trade	I-ORG
Organization	I-ORG
as	O
the	O
main	O
forum	O
in	O
the	O
area	O
of	O
trade	O
to	O
be	O
maintained	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
opposed	O
to	O
trade	O
protectionism	O
and	O
are	O
working	O
to	O
make	O
economic	O
globalization	O
more	O
balanced	O
,	O
inclusive	O
and	O
beneficial	O
to	O
all	O
.	O

We	O
call	O
on	O
countries	O
to	O
enhance	O
macroeconomic	O
policy	O
coordination	O
and	O
be	O
mindful	O
of	O
the	O
spillover	O
effects	O
of	O
their	O
respective	O
adjustment	O
of	O
economic	O
policies	O
.	O

We	O
call	O
for	O
the	O
strengthening	O
of	O
North-South	O
dialogue	O
and	O
South-South	O
cooperation	O
to	O
make	O
development	O
benefits	O
more	O
accessible	O
to	O
people	O
of	O
all	O
countries	O
.	O

China	I-LOC
will	O
firmly	O
fulfil	O
its	O
international	O
responsibilities	O
and	O
obligations	O
.	O

The	O
Chinese	I-MISC
nation	O
is	O
responsible	O
and	O
ready	O
to	O
play	O
its	O
part	O
.	O

Although	O
it	O
remains	O
a	O
developing	O
country	O
facing	O
the	O
daunting	O
task	O
of	O
development	O
,	O
China	I-LOC
,	O
as	O
the	O
second-largest	O
economy	O
￼and	O
a	O
permanent	O
member	O
of	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
,	O
is	O
fully	O
aware	O
of	O
its	O
responsibilities	O
and	O
the	O
expectations	O
placed	O
on	O
it	O
by	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
be	O
fully	O
and	O
more	O
actively	O
engaged	O
in	O
international	O
affairs	O
and	O
work	O
closely	O
with	O
other	O
countries	O
to	O
meet	O
complex	O
global	O
challenges	O
and	O
tackle	O
the	O
difficult	O
issues	O
facing	O
humankind	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
voice	O
China	I-LOC
's	O
views	O
,	O
offer	O
China	I-LOC
's	O
wisdom	O
,	O
propose	O
China	I-LOC
's	O
solutions	O
,	O
play	O
China	I-LOC
's	O
due	O
role	O
and	O
provide	O
more	O
public	O
goods	O
to	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
vigorously	O
advocate	O
the	O
right	O
vision	O
on	O
justice	O
versus	O
special	O
interests	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
will	O
endeavour	O
to	O
build	O
a	O
community	O
of	O
common	O
destiny	O
with	O
other	O
developing	O
countries	O
.	O

In	O
our	O
exchanges	O
and	O
cooperation	O
with	O
other	O
developing	O
countries	O
,	O
we	O
will	O
uphold	O
justice	O
and	O
place	O
it	O
above	O
special	O
interests	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
provide	O
assistance	O
to	O
other	O
developing	O
countries	O
to	O
the	O
best	O
of	O
our	O
ability	O
,	O
so	O
as	O
to	O
enable	O
developing	O
countries	O
to	O
realize	O
independent	O
and	O
sustainable	O
development	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
play	O
a	O
more	O
proactive	O
and	O
constructive	O
role	O
in	O
addressing	O
international	O
and	O
regional	O
hotspot	O
issues	O
to	O
promote	O
peace	O
and	O
dialogue	O
,	O
defuse	O
conflicts	O
and	O
safeguard	O
world	O
peace	O
and	O
stability	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
maintain	O
our	O
escort	O
missions	O
and	O
counter-piracy	O
operations	O
in	O
the	O
Gulf	I-MISC
of	O
Aden	I-LOC
and	O
increase	O
our	O
participation	O
in	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
peacekeeping	O
operations	O
so	O
as	O
to	O
contribute	O
more	O
to	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
in	O
Africa	I-LOC
and	O
other	O
relevant	O
regions	O
.	O

The	O
turmoil	O
in	O
Syria	I-LOC
has	O
lasted	O
for	O
nearly	O
three	O
years	O
,	O
causing	O
great	O
suffering	O
and	O
trauma	O
to	O
both	O
the	O
Syrian	O
people	O
and	O
Syria	I-LOC
's	O
neighbours	O
.	O

The	O
recent	O
use	O
of	O
chemical	O
weapons	O
has	O
met	O
with	O
universal	O
condemnation	O
.	O

China	I-LOC
firmly	O
opposes	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
chemical	O
weapons	O
.	O

We	O
hope	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
early	O
adoption	O
of	O
a	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
resolution	O
to	O
support	O
the	O
Organization	O
for	O
the	O
Prohibition	I-MISC
of	I-MISC
Chemical	I-MISC
Weapons	I-MISC
(OPCW)	I-MISC
in	O
launching	O
the	O
verification	O
and	O
destruction	O
of	O
chemical	O
weapons	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
stand	O
ready	O
to	O
make	O
financial	O
contributions	O
to	O
the	O
OPCW	I-MISC
for	O
the	O
destruction	O
of	O
chemical	O
weapons	O
in	O
Syria	I-LOC
and	O
to	O
send	O
experts	O
to	O
work	O
there	O
on	O
the	O
ground	O
.	O

China	I-LOC
calls	O
for	O
an	O
immediate	O
end	O
to	O
hostilities	O
and	O
violence	O
in	O
Syria	I-LOC
so	O
that	O
the	O
necessary	O
conditions	O
for	O
the	O
verification	O
and	O
destruction	O
of	O
chemical	O
weapons	O
can	O
be	O
created	O
.	O

We	O
call	O
for	O
the	O
early	O
convening	O
of	O
the	O
"	O
Geneva	I-LOC
II	O
"	O
conference	O
and	O
faster	O
progress	O
on	O
a	O
political	O
resolution	O
of	O
the	O
Syrian	I-MISC
issue	O
.	O

China	I-LOC
seeks	O
no	O
gains	O
for	O
itself	O
in	O
Syria	I-LOC
.	O

We	O
respect	O
the	O
aspirations	O
and	O
choice	O
of	O
the	O
Syrian	I-MISC
people	O
.	O

China	I-LOC
is	O
following	O
the	O
humanitarian	O
situation	O
in	O
Syria	I-LOC
with	O
great	O
concern	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
provided	O
and	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
provide	O
assistance	O
within	O
our	O
means	O
to	O
the	O
Syrian	I-MISC
people	O
,	O
including	O
Syrian	I-MISC
refugees	O
outside	O
the	O
country	O
.	O

China	I-LOC
has	O
been	O
working	O
to	O
promote	O
a	O
peaceful	O
settlement	O
to	O
the	O
Iranian	I-MISC
nuclear	O
issue	O
through	O
dialogue	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
played	O
a	O
constructive	O
role	O
in	O
seeking	O
a	O
comprehensive	O
,	O
lasting	O
and	O
appropriate	O
solution	O
to	O
the	O
Iranian	I-MISC
nuclear	O
issue	O
so	O
as	O
to	O
uphold	O
the	O
international	O
non-proliferation	O
regime	O
and	O
peace	O
and	O
stability	O
in	O
the	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
dialogue	O
between	O
Iran	I-LOC
and	O
the	O
permanent	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
and	O
Germany	I-LOC
has	O
created	O
new	O
opportunities	O
.	O

All	O
the	O
relevant	O
parties	O
should	O
scale	O
up	O
diplomatic	O
efforts	O
and	O
work	O
for	O
substantive	O
progress	O
in	O
the	O
dialogue	O
at	O
an	O
early	O
date	O
.	O

The	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
issue	O
is	O
at	O
the	O
core	O
of	O
the	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
conflict	O
.	O

Guided	O
by	O
President	O
Xi	I-PER
Jinping	I-PER
's	O
four-	O
point	O
proposal	O
on	O
resolving	O
the	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
issue	O
,	O
China	I-LOC
will	O
continue	O
to	O
work	O
for	O
a	O
comprehensive	O
,	O
just	O
and	O
durable	O
solution	O
to	O
the	O
issue	O
.	O

Thanks	O
to	O
the	O
concerted	O
efforts	O
of	O
all	O
the	O
relevant	O
parties	O
,	O
tensions	O
on	O
the	O
Korean	I-MISC
peninsula	O
are	O
easing	O
.	O

Achieving	O
the	O
denuclearization	O
of	O
the	O
Korean	I-MISC
peninsula	O
and	O
maintaining	O
long-term	O
peace	O
and	O
stability	O
on	O
the	O
peninsula	O
will	O
respond	O
to	O
the	O
common	O
interests	O
of	O
all	O
parties	O
concerned	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
China	I-LOC
's	O
consistent	O
position	O
that	O
a	O
negotiated	O
solution	O
through	O
dialogue	O
is	O
the	O
right	O
way	O
to	O
resolve	O
the	O
nuclear	O
issue	O
on	O
the	O
peninsula	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
Six-Party	I-MISC
Talks	I-MISC
are	O
an	O
effective	O
platform	O
to	O
promote	O
denuclearization	O
on	O
the	O
Korean	I-MISC
peninsula	O
.	O

This	O
year	O
marks	O
the	O
tenth	O
anniversary	O
of	O
the	O
launch	O
of	O
the	O
Six-	I-MISC
Party	I-MISC
Talks	I-MISC
.	O

We	O
hope	O
that	O
all	O
parties	O
will	O
create	O
conducive	O
conditions	O
,	O
build	O
consensus	O
,	O
work	O
towards	O
the	O
same	O
goal	O
and	O
resume	O
the	O
talks	O
at	O
an	O
early	O
date	O
.	O

International	O
development	O
cooperation	O
is	O
at	O
a	O
crucial	O
stage	O
,	O
where	O
we	O
must	O
build	O
on	O
past	O
achievements	O
to	O
make	O
new	O
progress	O
.	O

China	I-LOC
supports	O
the	O
continued	O
and	O
full	O
implementation	O
of	O
the	O
Millennium	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
Goals	I-MISC
and	O
the	O
early	O
launch	O
of	O
intergovernmental	O
negotiations	O
on	O
the	O
post-2015	O
development	O
agenda	O
.	O

The	O
post-2015	O
development	O
agenda	O
should	O
continue	O
to	O
focus	O
on	O
development	O
and	O
poverty	O
elimination	O
,	O
give	O
due	O
￼consideration	O
to	O
national	O
conditions	O
and	O
the	O
various	O
stages	O
of	O
development	O
in	O
the	O
different	O
countries	O
,	O
and	O
respect	O
their	O
independent	O
choice	O
of	O
development	O
path	O
.	O

The	O
agenda	O
should	O
give	O
priority	O
to	O
strengthening	O
global	O
development	O
partnerships	O
;	O
adhere	O
to	O
the	O
principles	O
of	O
common	O
but	O
differentiated	O
responsibilities	O
,	O
equity	O
and	O
respective	O
capabilities	O
;	O
improve	O
follow-up	O
mechanisms	O
;	O
step	O
up	O
development	O
financing	O
;	O
promote	O
trade	O
and	O
investment	O
liberalization	O
and	O
facilitation	O
;	O
and	O
increase	O
official	O
development	O
aid	O
and	O
technical	O
support	O
to	O
developing	O
countries	O
.	O

China	I-LOC
welcomes	O
the	O
positive	O
outcomes	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Climate	I-MISC
Change	I-MISC
Conference	I-MISC
held	O
in	O
Doha	I-LOC
in	O
late	O
2012	O
.	O

China	I-LOC
hopes	O
that	O
the	O
developed	O
countries	O
will	O
demonstrate	O
political	O
will	O
and	O
honour	O
their	O
commitments	O
by	O
scaling	O
up	O
emissions-reduction	O
efforts	O
and	O
providing	O
capital	O
,	O
technology	O
and	O
capacity-	O
building	O
support	O
to	O
developing	O
countries	O
.	O

The	O
Chinese	I-MISC
Government	O
takes	O
climate	O
change	O
seriously	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
many	O
forceful	O
policy	O
measures	O
it	O
has	O
taken	O
have	O
resulted	O
in	O
notable	O
progress	O
.	O

China	I-LOC
will	O
continue	O
to	O
play	O
its	O
due	O
role	O
in	O
addressing	O
global	O
climate	O
change	O
.	O

Time	O
flies	O
.	O

Born	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
ashes	O
of	O
the	O
Second	I-MISC
World	I-MISC
War	I-MISC
,	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
embodies	O
the	O
yearning	O
of	O
the	O
peoples	O
of	O
all	O
countries	O
for	O
world	O
peace	O
and	O
global	O
development	O
.	O

The	O
Chinese	I-MISC
dream	O
is	O
a	O
dream	O
of	O
prosperity	O
for	O
the	O
country	O
and	O
happiness	O
for	O
the	O
people	O
;	O
it	O
has	O
much	O
in	O
common	O
with	O
the	O
dream	O
of	O
people	O
across	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

