Let	O
me	O
begin	O
by	O
congratulating	O
you	O
,	O
Madam	O
President	O
,	O
on	O
your	O
election	O
to	O
the	O
presidency	O
of	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
at	O
this	O
session	O
.	O

I	O
join	O
those	O
who	O
have	O
expressed	O
thanks	O
to	O
the	O
Secretary-General	O
for	O
his	O
leadership	O
and	O
commitment	O
in	O
recent	O
years	O
in	O
addressing	O
the	O
very	O
serious	O
challenges	O
facing	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
.	O

Allow	O
me	O
also	O
to	O
take	O
this	O
opportunity	O
to	O
congratulate	O
the	O
Republic	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
Montenegro	I-LOC
on	O
its	O
accession	O
to	O
membership	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

The	O
commitment	O
to	O
global	O
partnership	O
for	O
development	O
is	O
a	O
timely	O
,	O
yet	O
sobering	O
,	O
theme	O
in	O
light	O
of	O
the	O
long	O
road	O
we	O
have	O
still	O
to	O
travel	O
and	O
the	O
setbacks	O
already	O
encountered	O
.	O

A	O
major	O
setback	O
has	O
been	O
the	O
crisis	O
in	O
global	O
trade	O
talks	O
.	O

Trade	O
can	O
be	O
the	O
single	O
most	O
important	O
vehicle	O
for	O
global	O
development	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
should	O
not	O
let	O
the	O
opportunity	O
presented	O
to	O
us	O
by	O
the	O
Doha	I-LOC
Development	I-MISC
Agenda	I-MISC
slip	O
from	O
our	O
grasp	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
ensure	O
that	O
gains	O
from	O
trade	O
liberalization	O
benefit	O
the	O
poor	O
and	O
are	O
fairly	O
distributed	O
.	O

Iceland	I-LOC
remains	O
strongly	O
committed	O
to	O
the	O
Agenda	O
.	O

Many	O
developing	O
countries	O
,	O
particularly	O
in	O
sub-Saharan	I-LOC
Africa	I-LOC
,	O
have	O
little	O
chance	O
of	O
achieving	O
the	O
Millennium	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
Goals	I-MISC
by	O
the	O
target	O
date	O
,	O
unless	O
significant	O
additional	O
resources	O
are	O
made	O
available	O
.	O

We	O
welcome	O
and	O
support	O
international	O
efforts	O
for	O
debt	O
relief	O
to	O
the	O
poorest	O
countries	O
.	O

We	O
also	O
applaud	O
those	O
countries	O
that	O
have	O
committed	O
to	O
increasing	O
official	O
development	O
assistance	O
.	O

Iceland	I-LOC
is	O
also	O
shouldering	O
its	O
responsibility	O
.	O

Over	O
the	O
next	O
three	O
years	O
Iceland	I-LOC
's	O
development	O
assistance	O
will	O
have	O
almost	O
tripled	O
in	O
size	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
are	O
determined	O
to	O
do	O
even	O
more	O
.	O

Beyond	O
2009	O
our	O
assistance	O
should	O
increase	O
even	O
further	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
ambition	O
of	O
reaching	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
target	O
of	O
0	O
.	O
7	O
per	O
cent	O
of	O
gross	O
national	O
income	O
.	O

The	O
global	O
partnership	O
rests	O
on	O
the	O
principles	O
of	O
transparency	O
,	O
accountability	O
,	O
good	O
governance	O
,	O
equity	O
and	O
commitment	O
to	O
poverty	O
reduction	O
.	O

Iceland	I-LOC
also	O
attaches	O
special	O
importance	O
to	O
the	O
rights	O
of	O
women	O
and	O
children	O
.	O

As	O
the	O
Iranian	I-MISC
Nobel	I-MISC
Peace	I-MISC
Prize	I-MISC
winner	O
,	O
Shirin	I-PER
Ebadi	I-PER
,	O
so	O
rightly	O
pointed	O
out	O
in	O
her	O
Nobel	I-MISC
Peace	I-MISC
Prize	I-MISC
Lecture	O
on	O
10	O
December	O
2003	O
,	O

"	O
To	O
disregard	O
women	O
and	O
bar	O
them	O
from	O
active	O
participation	O
in	O
political	O
,	O
social	O
,	O
economic	O
and	O
cultural	O
life	O
would	O
in	O
fact	O
be	O
tantamount	O
to	O
depriving	O
the	O
entire	O
population	O
of	O
every	O
society	O
of	O
half	O
its	O
capability	O
.	O

"	O

We	O
want	O
to	O
see	O
more	O
determined	O
efforts	O
by	O
development	O
partners	O
and	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
agencies	O
to	O
pursue	O
gender	O
equality	O
.	O

The	O
work	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Development	I-MISC
Fund	I-MISC
for	I-MISC
Women	I-MISC
(	O
UNIFEM	I-MISC
)	O
must	O
be	O
given	O
more	O
weight	O
within	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

Iceland	I-LOC
has	O
increased	O
its	O
support	O
for	O
the	O
work	O
of	O
UNIFEM	I-MISC
more	O
than	O
tenfold	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
two	O
years	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
will	O
increase	O
our	O
support	O
even	O
further	O
.	O

The	O
mission	O
statement	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Children	I-ORG
's	I-ORG
Fund	I-ORG
(	O
UNICEF	I-ORG
)	O
correctly	O
insists	O
that	O
the	O
survival	O
,	O
protection	O
and	O
development	O
of	O
children	O
are	O
central	O
to	O
human	O
progress	O
.	O

Nobody	O
questions	O
this	O
statement	O
,	O
yet	O
more	O
than	O
10	O
million	O
children	O
die	O
from	O
preventable	O
causes	O
every	O
year	O
.	O

Iceland	I-LOC
will	O
further	O
increase	O
its	O
contributions	O
to	O
the	O
vital	O
work	O
of	O
UNICEF	I-ORG
.	O

I	O
am	O
proud	O
to	O
say	O
that	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
Iceland	I-LOC
have	O
been	O
particularly	O
active	O
and	O
make	O
the	O
highest	O
contribution	O
per	O
capita	O
of	O
national	O
societies	O
to	O
UNICEF	I-ORG
.	O

At	O
least	O
half	O
of	O
the	O
eight	O
Millennium	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
Goals	I-MISC
relate	O
to	O
resource	O
use	O
and	O
environmental	O
conservation	O
,	O
that	O
is	O
,	O
to	O
sustainable	O
development	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
not	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
eradicate	O
extreme	O
poverty	O
or	O
hunger	O
if	O
we	O
cannot	O
safeguard	O
the	O
environment	O
,	O
the	O
basis	O
of	O
food	O
security	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

We	O
cannot	O
hope	O
to	O
reduce	O
child	O
mortality	O
unless	O
we	O
deal	O
with	O
the	O
contamination	O
of	O
fresh	O
water	O
.	O

There	O
is	O
a	O
close	O
relationship	O
between	O
the	O
health	O
of	O
the	O
earth	O
's	O
ecosystem	O
and	O
human	O
welfare	O
,	O
security	O
and	O
peace	O
.	O

Icelanders	I-MISC
base	O
their	O
livelihood	O
on	O
the	O
living	O
resources	O
of	O
the	O
sea	O
and	O
abundant	O
renewable	O
energy	O
.	O

Iceland	I-LOC
rose	O
from	O
relatively	O
recent	O
poverty	O
to	O
affluence	O
through	O
the	O
application	O
of	O
technological	O
innovations	O
and	O
by	O
drawing	O
on	O
international	O
cooperation	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
convinced	O
that	O
our	O
success	O
could	O
be	O
replicated	O
in	O
many	O
other	O
parts	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
,	O
given	O
the	O
right	O
incentives	O
and	O
an	O
enabling	O
environment	O
.	O

In	O
this	O
connection	O
,	O
I	O
should	O
like	O
to	O
refer	O
in	O
particular	O
to	O
two	O
areas	O
of	O
sustainable	O
development:	O
ocean	O
issues	O
and	O
energy	O
issues	O
.	O

Ocean	O
issues	O
have	O
far-reaching	O
development	O
implications	O
.	O

Ninety-five	O
per	O
cent	O
of	O
those	O
who	O
make	O
their	O
living	O
from	O
fisheries	O
are	O
in	O
the	O
developing	O
world	O
.	O

A	O
billion	O
people	O
depend	O
on	O
fisheries	O
for	O
their	O
main	O
intake	O
of	O
protein	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
seeing	O
a	O
rapid	O
increase	O
in	O
pollution	O
of	O
the	O
ocean	O
and	O
depletion	O
of	O
its	O
living	O
resources	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
why	O
Iceland	I-LOC
has	O
prioritized	O
this	O
area	O
in	O
its	O
development	O
cooperation	O
and	O
in	O
the	O
work	O
of	O
the	O
fisheries	O
department	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
University	I-ORG
in	0
Iceland	I-LOC
.	O

Energy	O
issues	O
also	O
loom	O
large	O
.	O

While	O
Icelanders	I-MISC
enjoy	O
the	O
good	O
fortune	O
of	O
having	O
clean	O
,	O
renewable	O
energy	O
for	O
70	O
per	O
cent	O
of	O
our	O
total	O
energy	O
use	O
,	O
energy	O
issues	O
are	O
increasingly	O
becoming	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
main	O
drivers	O
of	O
the	O
sustainable	O
development	O
agenda	O
within	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

Two	O
billion	O
people	O
lack	O
access	O
to	O
electricity	O
.	O

All	O
eight	O
Millennium	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
Goals	I-MISC
will	O
require	O
greater	O
energy	O
consumption	O
.	O

Unfortunately	O
,	O
more	O
energy	O
consumption	O
in	O
most	O
cases	O
means	O
greater	O
greenhouse	O
gas	O
emissions	O
.	O

One	O
of	O
our	O
greatest	O
challenges	O
today	O
is	O
to	O
square	O
the	O
development	O
circle	O
,	O
to	O
meet	O
our	O
development	O
needs	O
while	O
safeguarding	O
the	O
environment	O
.	O

One	O
way	O
certainly	O
is	O
to	O
increase	O
substantially	O
the	O
share	O
of	O
renewables	O
in	O
world	O
energy	O
demand	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
why	O
Iceland	I-LOC
is	O
taking	O
an	O
active	O
part	O
in	O
promoting	O
renewables	O
and	O
new	O
technologies	O
through	O
its	O
development	O
cooperation	O
and	O
the	O
work	O
of	O
the	O
geothermal	O
department	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
University	I-ORG
.	O

Another	O
example	O
of	O
our	O
commitment	O
in	O
this	O
area	O
is	O
the	O
international	O
seminar	O
on	O
hydrogen	O
use	O
for	O
the	O
developing	O
world	O
,	O
to	O
be	O
held	O
in	O
Reykjavik	I-LOC
later	O
this	O
week	O
.	O

Much	O
has	O
been	O
achieved	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
12	O
months	O
in	O
implementing	O
the	O
outcome	O
of	O
the	O
World	I-MISC
Summit	I-MISC
.	O

We	O
now	O
have	O
a	O
Peacebuilding	I-ORG
Commission	I-ORG
.	O

The	O
new	O
Human	I-ORG
Rights	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
has	O
also	O
been	O
established	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
the	O
duty	O
of	O
all	O
of	O
us	O
to	O
make	O
sure	O
that	O
we	O
strengthen	O
its	O
credibility	O
and	O
turn	O
it	O
into	O
a	O
powerful	O
defender	O
and	O
reinforcer	O
of	O
basic	O
human	O
rights	O
.	O

Its	O
credibility	O
will	O
depend	O
to	O
a	O
large	O
extent	O
on	O
its	O
even-handedness	O
.	O

Useful	O
work	O
has	O
already	O
been	O
done	O
on	O
internal	O
reform	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

The	O
success	O
of	O
these	O
reforms	O
—	O
I	O
think	O
in	O
particular	O
of	O
the	O
mandate	O
review	O
—	O
will	O
affect	O
the	O
long-term	O
credibility	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

It	O
is	O
with	O
great	O
interest	O
and	O
high	O
hopes	O
that	O
we	O
await	O
the	O
outcome	O
of	O
the	O
work	O
of	O
the	O
High-level	I-MISC
Panel	I-MISC
on	I-MISC
System-wide	I-MISC
Coherence	I-MISC
.	O

Peace	O
and	O
security	O
is	O
fundamental	O
to	O
implementing	O
a	O
global	O
partnership	O
for	O
development	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
face	O
of	O
the	O
crippling	O
effects	O
of	O
terrorism	O
,	O
we	O
welcome	O
the	O
agreement	O
on	O
the	O
Global	I-MISC
Counter-Terrorism	I-MISC
Strategy	I-MISC
.	O

In	O
the	O
fight	O
against	O
terrorism	O
,	O
human	O
rights	O
must	O
not	O
be	O
compromised	O
;	O
otherwise	O
,	O
we	O
undermine	O
the	O
values	O
that	O
we	O
seek	O
to	O
defend	O
.	O

Torture	O
cannot	O
be	O
justified	O
.	O

As	O
we	O
have	O
seen	O
recently	O
,	O
years	O
of	O
careful	O
development	O
can	O
be	O
reversed	O
almost	O
overnight	O
by	O
war	O
.	O

Conflict	O
prevention	O
,	O
restraint	O
by	O
the	O
parties	O
involved	O
and	O
a	O
commitment	O
by	O
other	O
actors	O
to	O
urge	O
restraint	O
,	O
rather	O
than	O
encourage	O
conflict	O
,	O
are	O
also	O
fundamental	O
to	O
the	O
partnership	O
.	O

Sixty	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
on	O
19	O
November	O
1946	O
,	O
Iceland	I-LOC
became	O
a	O
Member	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

Iceland	I-LOC
has	O
since	O
then	O
strongly	O
supported	O
the	O
principles	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
as	O
written	O
in	O
the	O
Charter	I-MISC
.	O

With	O
the	O
full	O
support	O
of	O
the	O
other	O
Nordic	I-MISC
countries	O
—	O
Denmark	I-LOC
,	O
Finland	I-LOC
,	O
Norway	I-LOC
and	O
Sweden	I-LOC
—	O
Iceland	I-LOC
decided	O
in	O
1998	O
to	O
present	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
its	O
candidature	O
for	O
a	O
seat	O
on	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
for	O
the	O
period	O
2009-2010	O
,	O
with	O
elections	O
to	O
be	O
held	O
in	O
2008	O
.	O

This	O
candidature	O
,	O
which	O
was	O
declared	O
within	O
the	O
Western	I-MISC
European	I-MISC
and	O
Others	I-MISC
Group	I-MISC
in	O
April	O
2000	O
,	O
is	O
based	O
on	O
our	O
readiness	O
to	O
shoulder	O
the	O
responsibility	O
of	O
serving	O
on	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
body	O
charged	O
with	O
maintaining	O
and	O
strengthening	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
.	O

As	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
almost	O
100	O
smaller	O
States	I-LOC
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
Iceland	I-LOC
makes	O
every	O
endeavour	O
to	O
cultivate	O
mutually	O
beneficial	O
relations	O
with	O
all	O
Members	O
of	O
the	O
Organization	O
and	O
believes	O
itself	O
to	O
be	O
favourably	O
positioned	O
to	O
exercise	O
with	O
fairness	O
and	O
firmness	O
the	O
role	O
of	O
a	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
member	O
.	O

The	O
task	O
of	O
building	O
a	O
global	O
partnership	O
for	O
development	O
is	O
not	O
easy	O
.	O

But	O
it	O
is	O
the	O
only	O
way	O
in	O
which	O
we	O
can	O
realistically	O
address	O
the	O
challenges	O
facing	O
us	O
,	O
whether	O
they	O
be	O
challenges	O
of	O
poverty	O
,	O
security	O
,	O
the	O
environment	O
or	O
health	O
.	O

