Humankind	O
faces	O
serious	O
,	O
unprecedented	O
crises	O
.	O

Now	O
is	O
the	O
time	O
for	O
us	O
to	O
stand	O
united	O
beneath	O
the	O
flag	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
to	O
confront	O
those	O
crises	O
together	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
is	O
resolved	O
to	O
continue	O
to	O
take	O
on	O
great	O
responsibility	O
,	O
working	O
hand	O
in	O
hand	O
with	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
.	O

The	O
Government	O
of	O
Japan	I-LOC
is	O
expending	O
its	O
best	O
possible	O
efforts	O
in	O
the	O
fight	O
against	O
the	O
Ebola	O
virus	O
.	O

The	O
international	O
community	O
should	O
come	O
together	O
to	O
address	O
that	O
crisis	O
,	O
which	O
directly	O
affects	O
the	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
of	O
Africa	I-LOC
.	O

In	O
that	O
regard	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
,	O
as	O
one	O
of	O
its	O
sponsors	O
,	O
has	O
strongly	O
supported	O
the	O
adoption	O
of	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
resolution	O
2177	O
(2014)	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
fifth	O
Tokyo	I-LOC
International	I-MISC
Conference	I-MISC
on	I-MISC
African	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
,	O
held	O
in	O
Japan	I-LOC
in	O
the	O
past	O
year	O
,	O
the	O
Government	O
of	O
Japan	I-LOC
announced	O
that	O
it	O
would	O
set	O
aside	O
$500	O
million	O
to	O
address	O
health	O
issues	O
in	O
Africa	I-LOC
and	O
launch	O
training	O
programmes	O
for	O
some	O
120,000	O
health	O
and	O
medical-service	O
providers	O
.	O

As	O
a	O
response	O
to	O
the	O
Ebola	I-MISC
outbreak	O
,	O
we	O
have	O
sent	O
highly	O
knowledgeable	O
and	O
experienced	O
Japanese	I-MISC
experts	O
,	O
as	O
members	O
of	O
World	I-ORG
Health	I-ORG
Organization	I-ORG
missions	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
also	O
extended	O
a	O
total	O
of	O
$	0
5	O
million	O
in	O
financial	O
assistance	O
and	O
will	O
provide	O
$
500,000	O
worth	O
of	O
personal	O
protective	O
equipment	O
for	O
health-care	O
workers	O
.	O

Furthermore	O
,	O
we	O
pledge	O
to	O
extend	O
additional	O
assistance	O
totaling	O
$40	O
million	O
in	O
future	O
.	O

What	O
is	O
important	O
now	O
is	O
to	O
prevent	O
extremism	O
from	O
taking	O
root	O
,	O
while	O
responding	O
swiftly	O
to	O
the	O
region	O
's	O
humanitarian	O
crises	O
.	O

To	O
assist	O
in	O
that	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
will	O
provide	O
$50	O
million	O
of	O
emergency	O
assistance	O
right	O
away	O
.	O

Placing	O
great	O
importance	O
on	O
the	O
stability	O
of	O
Ukraine	I-LOC
,	O
in	O
March	O
Japan	I-LOC
swiftly	O
announced	O
economic	O
assistance	O
of	O
up	O
to	O
$1	O
.	O
5	O
billion	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
now	O
being	O
implemented	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
also	O
preparing	O
new	O
assistance	O
towards	O
reconstruction	O
of	O
the	O
eastern	O
part	O
of	O
Ukraine	I-LOC
.	O

Next	O
year	O
will	O
be	O
a	O
momentous	O
one	O
for	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

We	O
will	O
celebrate	O
its	O
seventieth	O
anniversary	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
time	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
was	O
founded	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
was	O
recovering	O
from	O
having	O
been	O
reduced	O
to	O
ashes	O
.	O

Since	O
then	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
has	O
never	O
for	O
a	O
moment	O
forgotten	O
the	O
horrors	O
of	O
war	O
.	O

It	O
set	O
out	O
on	O
its	O
post-war	O
path	O
abhorring	O
the	O
atrocities	O
of	O
a	O
war	O
that	O
brought	O
tragedy	O
to	O
innocent	O
people	O
both	O
at	O
home	O
and	O
in	O
other	O
nations	O
and	O
renewing	O
its	O
pledge	O
towards	O
peace	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
made	O
a	O
wholehearted	O
commitment	O
to	O
shoulder	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
responsibilities	O
at	O
home	O
and	O
abroad	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
's	O
future	O
lies	O
in	O
a	O
straight	O
extension	O
of	O
our	O
history	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
70	O
years	O
.	O

Our	O
pledge	O
to	O
never	O
wage	O
war	O
will	O
be	O
handed	O
down	O
and	O
fostered	O
by	O
the	O
Japanese	I-MISC
people	O
for	O
generations	O
to	O
come	O
.	O

Peace	O
will	O
take	O
root	O
only	O
when	O
conflicts	O
are	O
deprived	O
of	O
places	O
to	O
reside	O
within	O
our	O
hearts	O
and	O
our	O
way	O
of	O
life	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
precisely	O
why	O
Japan	I-LOC
is	O
working	O
to	O
continue	O
taking	O
action	O
at	O
the	O
grass-roots	O
level	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
has	O
been	O
,	O
is	O
now	O
and	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
force	O
providing	O
momentum	O
for	O
proactive	O
contributions	O
to	O
peace	O
.	O

Moreover	O
,	O
I	O
wish	O
to	O
state	O
and	O
to	O
pledge	O
,	O
first	O
of	O
all	O
,	O
that	O
Japan	I-LOC
is	O
a	O
nation	O
that	O
has	O
worked	O
to	O
eliminate	O
the	O
war	O
culture	O
from	O
people	O
's	O
hearts	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
will	O
spare	O
no	O
effort	O
in	O
continuing	O
to	O
do	O
so	O
.	O

As	O
early	O
as	O
the	O
mid-1980s	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
launched	O
cooperation	O
in	O
Gaza	I-LOC
to	O
foster	O
human	O
resources	O
.	O

A	O
total	O
of	O
more	O
than	O
400	O
administrative	O
officials	O
and	O
technical	O
experts	O
have	O
come	O
to	O
Japan	I-LOC
to	O
receive	O
intensive	O
training	O
.	O

He	O
said:	O
"	O
Gaza	I-LOC
has	O
no	O
natural	O
resources	O
whatsoever	O
.	O

The	O
only	O
thing	O
we	O
have	O
is	O
people	O
,	O
a	O
situation	O
the	O
same	O
as	O
Japan	I-LOC
's	O
.	O

What	O
I	O
learned	O
in	O
Japan	I-LOC
is	O
the	O
spirit	O
of	O
never	O
,	O
ever	O
giving	O
up	O
.	O
"	O

After	O
being	O
educated	O
in	O
Japan	I-LOC
for	O
a	O
month	O
,	O
Najjar	I-PER
Osama	I-PER
brought	O
solar-power	O
technology	O
back	O
to	O
his	O
hometown	O
,	O
to	O
be	O
attached	O
to	O
the	O
facility	O
in	O
greatest	O
need	O
of	O
a	O
stand-alone	O
power	O
system	O
.	O

The	O
equipment	O
that	O
he	O
and	O
his	O
colleagues	O
introduced	O
to	O
the	O
largest	O
hospital	O
in	O
the	O
Gaza	I-LOC
Strip	I-LOC
has	O
endured	O
the	O
unrest	O
and	O
kept	O
the	O
lights	O
on	O
in	O
the	O
hospital	O
's	O
emergency	O
room	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
perhaps	O
more	O
than	O
just	O
a	O
coincidence	O
that	O
the	O
Somalia	I-LOC
story	O
I	O
wish	O
to	O
tell	O
also	O
relates	O
to	O
lighting	O
.	O

The	O
most	O
important	O
thing	O
for	O
Hamidah	I-PER
Hassan	I-PER
—	O
a	O
girl	O
10	O
years	O
of	O
age	O
,	O
living	O
in	O
the	O
camps	O
for	O
internally	O
displaced	O
persons	O
in	O
Mogadishu	I-LOC
—	O
was	O
lighting	O
to	O
illuminate	O
the	O
camp	O
's	O
tents	O
at	O
night	O
.	O

A	O
lit	O
tent	O
acts	O
as	O
a	O
deterrent	O
to	O
sexual	O
violence	O
.	O

Over	O
the	O
past	O
two	O
years	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
has	O
distributed	O
to	O
internally	O
displaced	O
persons	O
,	O
including	O
young	O
girls	O
such	O
as	O
Hamidah	I-PER
,	O
some	O
2,500	O
small	O
lanterns	O
,	O
made	O
by	O
Panasonic	I-ORG
,	O
that	O
bank	O
electricity	O
generated	O
from	O
sunlight	O
during	O
the	O
day	O
and	O
convert	O
it	O
to	O
lamplight	O
at	O
night	O
.	O

Hamidah	I-PER
is	O
now	O
working	O
hard	O
,	O
dreaming	O
that	O
one	O
day	O
she	O
will	O
become	O
a	O
doctor	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
continue	O
to	O
clear	O
away	O
anxiety	O
and	O
fear	O
from	O
people	O
's	O
hearts	O
and	O
cull	O
any	O
shoots	O
of	O
hatred	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
and	O
the	O
Japanese	I-MISC
people	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
do	O
our	O
best	O
to	O
offer	O
our	O
own	O
willingness	O
and	O
capacity	O
,	O
knowledge	O
and	O
experience	O
,	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
make	O
that	O
a	O
reality	O
.	O

First	O
and	O
foremost	O
,	O
we	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
assist	O
in	O
enhancing	O
education	O
,	O
which	O
will	O
form	O
the	O
basis	O
of	O
economic	O
growth	O
for	O
those	O
who	O
need	O
it	O
,	O
from	O
primary	O
education	O
to	O
vocational	O
training	O
.	O

Our	O
aim	O
,	O
always	O
,	O
is	O
to	O
internalize	O
the	O
joy	O
of	O
work	O
in	O
people	O
's	O
nature	O
.	O

We	O
hope	O
for	O
people	O
to	O
keenly	O
realize	O
that	O
the	O
sweat	O
brought	O
about	O
by	O
their	O
labour	O
is	O
an	O
investment	O
in	O
the	O
future	O
.	O

Expanding	O
roads	O
,	O
ports	O
and	O
the	O
increasingly	O
connected	O
power	O
grids	O
,	O
together	O
with	O
effective	O
governance	O
that	O
is	O
fully	O
in	O
step	O
with	O
those	O
improvements	O
,	O
will	O
help	O
to	O
bring	O
about	O
an	O
affluent	O
and	O
peaceful	O
society	O
that	O
values	O
human	O
rights	O
.	O

When	O
that	O
concept	O
receives	O
broad-based	O
support	O
,	O
people	O
become	O
the	O
owners	O
of	O
their	O
society	O
in	O
the	O
truest	O
sense	O
of	O
the	O
word	O
.	O

To	O
expand	O
that	O
kind	O
of	O
society	O
from	O
a	O
point	O
to	O
a	O
line	O
,	O
and	O
from	O
a	O
line	O
to	O
a	O
plane	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
has	O
always	O
sought	O
foundations	O
of	O
peace	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
always	O
focused	O
our	O
official	O
development	O
assistance	O
philosophy	O
on	O
that	O
approach	O
.	O

The	O
banner	O
of	O
a	O
proactive	O
contribution	O
to	O
peace	O
borne	O
by	O
the	O
Japanese	I-MISC
Government	O
is	O
a	O
flag	O
planted	O
atop	O
the	O
natural	O
development	O
of	O
conviction	O
and	O
self-confidence	O
that	O
we	O
have	O
acquired	O
through	O
many	O
years	O
of	O
promoting	O
human	O
security	O
,	O
that	O
is	O
,	O
working	O
as	O
hard	O
as	O
we	O
could	O
for	O
the	O
development	O
of	O
a	O
society	O
that	O
places	O
people	O
front	O
and	O
centre	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
carry	O
on	O
with	O
our	O
work	O
,	O
hoping	O
to	O
create	O
,	O
in	O
time	O
,	O
a	O
fair	O
and	O
just	O
society	O
that	O
places	O
human	O
beings	O
front	O
and	O
centre	O
and	O
a	O
democracy	O
that	O
values	O
human	O
rights	O
.	O

Seventy	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
proclaimed	O
its	O
determination	O

and	O
to	O

"	O
practice	O
tolerance	O
"	O

.	O

The	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
must	O
not	O
depart	O
from	O
those	O
ideals	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
with	O
exactly	O
that	O
determination	O
that	O
Japan	I-LOC
aspires	O
to	O
join	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
once	O
again	O
as	O
a	O
non-permanent	O
member	O
next	O
year	O
,	O
marking	O
the	O
seventieth	O
year	O
since	O
the	O
start	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

We	O
believe	O
that	O
our	O
efforts	O
have	O
been	O
second	O
to	O
none	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
my	O
wish	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
seventieth	O
anniversary	O
as	O
a	O
turning	O
point	O
,	O
that	O
countries	O
sharing	O
the	O
same	O
aims	O
can	O
all	O
work	O
together	O
to	O
finally	O
resolve	O
the	O
long-standing	O
issue	O
of	O
the	O
reform	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
in	O
a	O
way	O
that	O
reflects	O
the	O
realities	O
of	O
the	O
twenty-first	O
century	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
on	O
the	O
same	O
occasion	O
last	O
year	O
that	O
I	O
spoke	O
of	O
the	O
significance	O
and	O
importance	O
of	O
enhancing	O
the	O
power	O
of	O
women	O
and	O
appealed	O
for	O
us	O
to	O
create	O
a	O
society	O
in	O
which	O
women	O
shine	O
(see	O
A/68/PV.12	O
)	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
has	O
now	O
begun	O
to	O
work	O
towards	O
resolving	O
the	O
numerous	O
issues	O
we	O
face	O
,	O
together	O
with	O
private	O
industries	O
,	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
increase	O
women	O
's	O
participation	O
in	O
society	O
as	O
soon	O
as	O
possible	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
foster	O
environments	O
in	O
which	O
it	O
is	O
possible	O
to	O
balance	O
child	O
care	O
and	O
nursing	O
care	O
on	O
the	O
one	O
hand	O
and	O
work	O
on	O
the	O
other	O
.	O

In	O
addition	O
,	O
eliminating	O
biases	O
about	O
the	O
roles	O
of	O
women	O
that	O
still	O
exist	O
in	O
society	O
will	O
be	O
basic	O
,	O
more	O
so	O
than	O
anything	O
else	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
just	O
held	O
a	O
large-scale	O
international	O
conference	O
with	O
an	O
aim	O
of	O
promoting	O
the	O
dynamic	O
participation	O
of	O
women	O
.	O

With	O
an	O
eye	O
set	O
on	O
economic	O
development	O
and	O
the	O
resolution	O
of	O
global	O
issues	O
,	O
about	O
100	O
leaders	O
from	O
all	O
sectors	O
of	O
society	O
from	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
sent	O
out	O
a	O
message	O
to	O
the	O
world	O
of	O
their	O
commitment	O
to	O
bringing	O
the	O
power	O
of	O
women	O
to	O
fruition	O
.	O

In	O
less	O
than	O
a	O
year	O
,	O
the	O
empowerment	O
of	O
women	O
has	O
become	O
a	O
guiding	O
principle	O
that	O
has	O
driven	O
Japan	I-LOC
's	O
policies	O
both	O
domestically	O
and	O
overseas	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
has	O
focused	O
on	O
advancing	O
the	O
status	O
of	O
girls	O
and	O
mothers	O
in	O
Africa	I-LOC
,	O
a	O
region	O
that	O
receives	O
emphasis	O
within	O
our	O
foreign	O
aid	O
.	O

The	O
twentieth	O
century	O
had	O
a	O
history	O
of	O
profound	O
harm	O
to	O
women	O
's	O
honour	O
and	O
dignity	O
when	O
conflicts	O
broke	O
out	O
.	O

Around	O
the	O
globe	O
,	O
we	O
still	O
find	O
abhorrent	O
circumstances	O
in	O
which	O
women	O
are	O
denied	O
access	O
to	O
such	O
basic	O
services	O
as	O
medical	O
care	O
and	O
education	O
merely	O
because	O
they	O
were	O
born	O
female	O
,	O
thereby	O
depriving	O
them	O
of	O
opportunities	O
to	O
become	O
self-reliant	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
seeks	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
country	O
that	O
walks	O
alongside	O
such	O
women	O
throughout	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

We	O
intend	O
to	O
encourage	O
and	O
support	O
,	O
throughout	O
the	O
world	O
,	O
the	O
self-reliance	O
of	O
women	O
whose	O
hearts	O
have	O
suffered	O
grievous	O
harm	O
.	O

We	O
intend	O
to	O
make	O
the	O
twenty-first	O
century	O
a	O
world	O
without	O
human	O
rights	O
violations	O
against	O
women	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
will	O
stand	O
at	O
the	O
fore	O
and	O
lead	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
in	O
eliminating	O
sexual	O
violence	O
during	O
conflicts	O
.	O

Therein	O
lies	O
the	O
reason	O
for	O
Japan	I-LOC
to	O
reinforce	O
its	O
cooperation	O
with	O
Ms	O
.	O

Fundamental	O
rights	O
such	O
as	O
education	O
and	O
health	O
must	O
be	O
ensured	O
everywhere	O
throughout	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
necessary	O
for	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
and	O
,	O
indeed	O
,	O
the	O
world	O
to	O
come	O
together	O
as	O
one	O
to	O
take	O
action	O
so	O
that	O
girls	O
and	O
boys	O
can	O
attend	O
school	O
equally	O
and	O
that	O
expectant	O
mothers	O
can	O
receive	O
medical	O
care	O
with	O
peace	O
of	O
mind	O
.	O

Moreover	O
,	O
in	O
order	O
for	O
women	O
to	O
lead	O
lives	O
full	O
of	O
pride	O
and	O
hope	O
,	O
I	O
consider	O
it	O
essential	O
to	O
develop	O
their	O
ability	O
to	O
be	O
economically	O
self-reliant	O
,	O
above	O
all	O
else	O
.	O

I	O
do	O
not	O
have	O
the	O
slightest	O
doubt	O
that	O
the	O
creation	O
of	O
a	O
society	O
in	O
which	O
women	O
shine	O
holds	O
the	O
key	O
to	O
changing	O
the	O
whole	O
of	O
society	O
.	O

Last	O
year	O
I	O
pledged	O
in	O
my	O
address	O
here	O
,	O
before	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
,	O
that	O
Japan	I-LOC
would	O
implement	O
assistance	O
in	O
excess	O
of	O
$3	O
billion	O
over	O
three	O
years	O
,	O
aimed	O
chiefly	O
at	O
advancing	O
the	O
status	O
of	O
women	O
.	O

The	O
amount	O
already	O
implemented	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
year	O
is	O
$1	O
.	O
8	O
billion	O
,	O
more	O
than	O
half	O
the	O
amount	O
pledged	O
.	O

I	O
also	O
stated	O
Japan	I-LOC
respected	O
the	O
activities	O
of	O
UN-Women	I-ORG
,	O
which	O
is	O
responsible	O
for	O
women	O
's	O
issues	O
within	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
and	O
that	O
we	O
intended	O
to	O
become	O
one	O
of	O
its	O
leading	O
contributors	O
and	O
thus	O
a	O
model	O
country	O
in	O
that	O
area	O
.	O

Over	O
the	O
past	O
year	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
increased	O
its	O
contributions	O
to	O
UN-Women	I-ORG
fivefold	O
,	O
and	O
in	O
the	O
future	O
we	O
will	O
further	O
increase	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
projects	O
we	O
support	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
also	O
very	O
pleased	O
that	O
next	O
year	O
UN-Women	I-ORG
will	O
open	O
its	O
Tokyo	I-LOC
office	O
.	O

I	O
expect	O
that	O
Japan	I-LOC
will	O
further	O
enhance	O
its	O
coordination	O
with	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
through	O
that	O
new	O
office	O
.	O

As	O
we	O
draw	O
up	O
the	O
post-2015	O
development	O
agenda	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
will	O
continue	O
to	O
be	O
as	O
strongly	O
involved	O
as	O
it	O
has	O
been	O
to	O
date	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
I	O
strongly	O
urge	O
that	O
if	O
we	O
are	O
to	O
truly	O
attain	O
inclusiveness	O
,	O
sustainability	O
and	O
resilience	O
,	O
as	O
put	O
forth	O
in	O
that	O
agenda	O
,	O
then	O
protection	O
and	O
empowerment	O
of	O
the	O
vulnerable	O
,	O
irrespective	O
of	O
race	O
,	O
gender	O
,	O
or	O
age	O
,	O
is	O
important	O
.	O

This	O
year	O
Japan	I-LOC
marks	O
the	O
sixtieth	O
anniversary	O
of	O
the	O
start	O
of	O
its	O
official	O
development	O
assistance	O
(	O
ODA	I-MISC
)	O
.	O

Having	O
learned	O
from	O
the	O
determination	O
of	O
our	O
predecessors	O
,	O
who	O
began	O
working	O
to	O
extend	O
ODA	I-MISC
a	O
mere	O
nine	O
years	O
after	O
suffering	O
total	O
devastation	O
in	O
war	O
,	O
the	O
Government	O
of	O
Japan	I-LOC
is	O
now	O
in	O
the	O
process	O
of	O
establishing	O
new	O
guiding	O
principles	O
for	O
our	O
ODA	I-MISC
.	O

We	O
intend	O
to	O
once	O
more	O
emphasize	O
as	O
priorities	O
objectives	O
such	O
as	O
high-quality	O
economic	O
growth	O
,	O
ensuring	O
rule	O
of	O
law	O
and	O
realizing	O
a	O
peaceful	O
and	O
stable	O
society	O
.	O

The	O
objectives	O
that	O
Japan	I-LOC
has	O
continuously	O
targeted	O
through	O
its	O
ODA	O
over	O
those	O
60	O
years	O
will	O
not	O
change	O
in	O
the	O
slightest	O
.	O

There	O
will	O
be	O
no	O
change	O
in	O
our	O
deeply	O
rooted	O
approach	O
in	O
which	O
the	O
most	O
important	O
thing	O
in	O
the	O
fight	O
against	O
poverty	O
is	O
to	O
cultivate	O
a	O
sense	O
of	O
ownership	O
among	O
the	O
people	O
concerned	O
and	O
to	O
encourage	O
self-help	O
efforts	O
.	O

Nor	O
will	O
there	O
be	O
any	O
changes	O
in	O
our	O
efforts	O
to	O
fully	O
ensure	O
human	O
security	O
.	O

Moreover	O
,	O
as	O
we	O
pursue	O
enhancing	O
women	O
's	O
empowerment	O
as	O
the	O
leverage	O
point	O
,	O
I	O
consider	O
the	O
attainment	O
of	O
our	O
goals	O
to	O
be	O
that	O
much	O
nearer	O
.	O

Over	O
the	O
past	O
20	O
years	O
Japan	I-LOC
has	O
sent	O
about	O
9,700	O
people	O
on	O
13	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
peacekeeping	O
operations	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
10	O
years	O
since	O
the	O
establishment	O
of	O
the	O
Peacebuilding	I-MISC
Commission	I-MISC
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
's	O
contributions	O
to	O
the	O
Peacebuilding	I-MISC
Fund	I-MISC
have	O
surpassed	O
$40	O
million	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
future	O
,	O
we	O
intend	O
to	O
cultivate	O
still	O
further	O
our	O
human	O
resources	O
in	O
terms	O
of	O
both	O
quantity	O
and	O
quality	O
,	O
to	O
contribute	O
to	O
the	O
area	O
of	O
peacebuilding	O
.	O

With	O
regard	O
to	O
North	O
Korea	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
will	O
work	O
in	O
coordination	O
with	O
relevant	O
countries	O
towards	O
the	O
comprehensive	O
resolution	O
of	O
outstanding	O
issues	O
,	O
including	O
abduction	O
and	O
nuclear	O
and	O
missile	O
issues	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
has	O
been	O
among	O
the	O
biggest	O
beneficiaries	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

Going	O
forward	O
,	O
we	O
will	O
work	O
harder	O
than	O
ever	O
to	O
bring	O
about	O
realization	O
of	O
the	O
principles	O
set	O
forth	O
by	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
is	O
a	O
nation	O
that	O
implements	O
its	O
pledges	O
without	O
fail	O
.	O

With	O
that	O
,	O
I	O
will	O
end	O
my	O
discussion	O
.	O
