Today	O
,	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
is	O
striving	O
to	O
meet	O
challenges	O
that	O
the	O
founders	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
could	O
not	O
have	O
envisioned	O
sixty	O
years	O
ago	O
.	O

The	O
fight	O
against	O
terrorism	O
and	O
efforts	O
to	O
ensure	O
non-proliferation	O
of	O
weapons	O
of	O
mass	O
destruction	O
are	O
just	O
a	O
few	O
examples	O
of	O
those	O
challenges	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
has	O
always	O
pursued	O
international	O
cooperation	O
centring	O
on	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

As	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
faces	O
new	O
realities	O
,	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
must	O
adapt	O
and	O
address	O
them	O
.	O

The	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
was	O
created	O
to	O
bring	O
about	O
a	O
peaceful	O
,	O
prosperous	O
,	O
and	O
just	O
world	O
.	O

To	O
that	O
end	O
,	O
Member	O
States	I-LOC
have	O
united	O
their	O
strengths	O
to	O
promote	O
international	O
cooperation	O
.	O

Convinced	O
that	O
it	O
can	O
contribute	O
to	O
creating	O
a	O
better	O
world	O
through	O
its	O
own	O
capabilities	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
has	O
endeavoured	O
steadfastly	O
to	O
fulfil	O
its	O
role	O
as	O
a	O
responsible	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Member	O
.	O

Our	O
activities	O
in	O
Iraq	I-LOC
and	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
offer	O
excellent	O
examples	O
.	O

In	O
Iraq	I-LOC
,	O
based	O
on	O
the	O
relevant	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
resolutions	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
has	O
joined	O
international	O
efforts	O
to	O
assist	O
in	O
the	O
Iraqi	O
people	O
's	O
own	O
struggle	O
towards	O
a	O
democratic	O
and	O
prosperous	O
nation	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
has	O
been	O
cooperating	O
with	O
the	O
Iraqi	O
people	O
to	O
help	O
them	O
improve	O
their	O
daily	O
life	O
and	O
rebuild	O
the	O
foundation	O
of	O
their	O
public	O
life	O
.	O

The	O
humanitarian	O
and	O
reconstruction	O
activities	O
of	O
Japan	I-LOC
's	O
Self-	O
Defence	O
Forces	O
and	O
its	O
financial	O
assistance	O
of	O
$5	O
billion	O
are	O
working	O
in	O
tandem	O
to	O
that	O
end	O
.	O

In	O
order	O
to	O
promote	O
international	O
solidarity	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
will	O
host	O
the	O
third	O
Meeting	O
of	O
the	O
Donors'	O
Committee	O
of	O
the	O
International	O
Reconstruction	O
Fund	O
Facility	O
for	O
Iraq	I-LOC
next	O
month	O
.	O

In	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
has	O
from	O
the	O
very	O
beginning	O
taken	O
the	O
lead	O
in	O
assisting	O
national	O
reconstruction	O
efforts	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
hosted	O
the	O
International	O
Conference	O
on	O
Reconstruction	O
Assistance	O
to	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
in	O
January	O
2002	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
has	O
been	O
actively	O
promoting	O
Afghan	O
efforts	O
for	O
disarmament	O
,	O
demobilization	O
and	O
reintegration	O
.	O

The	O
Afghan	O
people	O
are	O
working	O
hard	O
to	O
prepare	O
for	O
presidential	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
parliamentary	O
elections	O
.	O

Those	O
elections	O
are	O
the	O
most	O
important	O
milestones	O
for	O
a	O
new	O
,	O
democratic	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
international	O
community	O
and	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
must	O
stand	O
by	O
the	O
Afghan	O
and	O
Iraqi	O
peoples	O
in	O
their	O
strenuous	O
efforts	O
to	O
rebuild	O
their	O
countries	O
.	O

Weapons	O
of	O
mass	O
destruction	O
,	O
missiles	O
and	O
terrorism	O
threaten	O
international	O
security	O
in	O
today	O
's	O
world	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
is	O
the	O
only	O
country	O
ever	O
to	O
have	O
suffered	O
nuclear	O
devastation	O
.	O

As	O
such	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
has	O
been	O
at	O
the	O
forefront	O
in	O
promoting	O
nuclear	O
disarmament	O
and	O
non-proliferation	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
hopes	O
to	O
achieve	O
a	O
peaceful	O
and	O
safe	O
world	O
free	O
of	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
.	O

Furthermore	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
has	O
collaborated	O
with	O
other	O
countries	O
to	O
prevent	O
States	I-LOC
of	O
concern	O
and	O
non-State	O
actors	O
from	O
acquiring	O
weapons	O
of	O
mass	O
destruction	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
allow	O
no	O
room	O
for	O
terrorism	O
to	O
prevail	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
fight	O
against	O
terrorism	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
is	O
doing	O
its	O
utmost	O
to	O
strengthen	O
domestic	O
legislation	O
and	O
related	O
measures	O
,	O
and	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
cooperate	O
with	O
other	O
countries	O
.	O

The	O
nuclear	O
and	O
missile	O
issues	O
on	O
the	O
Korean	O
peninsula	O
present	O
a	O
serious	O
challenge	O
to	O
the	O
peace	O
and	O
stability	O
of	O
north-east	O
Asia	I-LOC
and	O
to	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
as	O
a	O
whole	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
is	O
determined	O
to	O
continue	O
to	O
seek	O
a	O
comprehensive	O
resolution	O
of	O
the	O
nuclear	O
and	O
missile	O
issues	O
and	O
the	O
abduction	O
issue	O
in	O
line	O
with	O
the	O
Pyongyang	I-LOC
Declaration	I-MISC
.	O

The	O
six-party	O
talks	O
must	O
go	O
forward	O
.	O

There	O
is	O
no	O
benefit	O
for	O
it	O
in	O
continuing	O
to	O
pursue	O
its	O
nuclear	O
programme	O
.	O

After	O
the	O
Second	O
World	O
War	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
experienced	O
a	O
dramatic	O
economic	O
recovery	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
help	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
.	O

On	O
the	O
basis	O
of	O
our	O
own	O
experience	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
keenly	O
aware	O
that	O
,	O
in	O
promoting	O
international	O
cooperation	O
,	O
self-help	O
efforts	O
are	O
essential	O
to	O
overcoming	O
difficulties	O
and	O
achieving	O
a	O
prosperous	O
society	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
's	O
official	O
development	O
assistance	O
therefore	O
has	O
been	O
based	O
on	O
the	O
principles	O
of	O
ownership	O
and	O
partnership	O
.	O

Environmental	O
conservation	O
must	O
also	O
proceed	O
hand	O
in	O
hand	O
with	O
economic	O
development	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
has	O
taken	O
the	O
lead	O
in	O
global	O
efforts	O
in	O
such	O
areas	O
as	O
climate	O
change	O
and	O
environmental	O
protection	O
.	O

In	O
addressing	O
development	O
challenges	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
Millennium	O
Development	I-MISC
Goals	I-MISC
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
will	O
move	O
forward	O
,	O
making	O
further	O
efforts	O
for	O
the	O
strategic	O
and	O
effective	O
use	O
of	O
official	O
development	O
assistance	O
,	O
bearing	O
those	O
principles	O
in	O
mind	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
why	O
Japan	I-LOC
is	O
advocating	O
the	O
concept	O
of	O
human	O
security	O
.	O

Based	O
upon	O
that	O
idea	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
is	O
making	O
efforts	O
to	O
realize	O
a	O
seamless	O
transition	O
from	O
humanitarian	O
assistance	O
to	O
reconstruction	O
support	O
in	O
countries	O
such	O
as	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
,	O
Sri	O
Lanka	O
and	O
Timor-Leste	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
my	O
strong	O
belief	O
that	O
there	O
can	O
be	O
no	O
stability	O
and	O
prosperity	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
unless	O
Africa	O
's	O
issues	O
are	O
resolved	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
initiated	O
the	O
process	O
of	O
the	O
Tokyo	I-LOC
International	O
Conference	O
on	O
African	O
Development	I-MISC
(TICAD)	O
in	O
1993	O
.	O

Last	O
year	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
organized	O
TICAD	O
III	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
participation	O
of	O
89	O
countries	O
and	O
47	O
international	O
organizations	O
.	O

The	O
collaboration	O
between	O
TICAD	O
and	O
NEPAD	O
is	O
significant	O
,	O
because	O
both	O
processes	O
are	O
grounded	O
in	O
the	O
principles	O
of	O
ownership	O
and	O
partnership	O
.	O

A	O
stable	O
and	O
prosperous	O
Africa	O
depends	O
upon	O
the	O
promotion	O
of	O
trade	O
and	O
investment	O
,	O
together	O
with	O
official	O
development	O
assistance	O
.	O

This	O
autumn	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
will	O
host	O
the	O
TICAD	O
Asia-Africa	O
Trade	O
and	O
Investment	O
Conference	O
.	O

Today	O
,	O
in	O
Africa	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
witnessing	O
the	O
unfolding	O
of	O
another	O
humanitarian	O
crisis	O
.	O

We	O
share	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
's	O
grave	O
concern	O
over	O
Darfur	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
has	O
decided	O
to	O
provide	O
humanitarian	O
assistance	O
of	O
$21	O
million	O
.	O

In	O
addition	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
intends	O
to	O
provide	O
in-kind	O
assistance	O
to	O
the	O
Sudanese	O
refugees	O
in	O
Chad	I-LOC
.	O

In	O
East	O
Asia	I-LOC
,	O
there	O
has	O
been	O
remarkable	O
economic	O
development	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
has	O
been	O
working	O
with	O
the	O
countries	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
to	O
build	O
solid	O
foundations	O
for	O
their	O
own	O
efforts	O
towards	O
economic	O
development	O
.	O

In	O
that	O
region	O
,	O
active	O
efforts	O
are	O
also	O
under	O
way	O
to	O
foster	O
community-building	O
.	O

Building	O
upon	O
the	O
Association	O
of	O
South-East	O
Asian	O
Nations	I-ORG
(ASEAN)	O
Plus	O
Three	O
,	O
I	O
have	O
advocated	O
the	O
idea	O
of	O
an	O
East	O
Asia	I-LOC
community	O
.	O

This	O
year	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
is	O
a	O
candidate	O
for	O
non-permanent	O
membership	O
on	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
,	O
if	O
elected	O
,	O
will	O
redouble	O
its	O
efforts	O
to	O
play	O
a	O
constructive	O
and	O
innovative	O
role	O
in	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
,	O
based	O
on	O
its	O
global	O
contributions	O
.	O

As	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
rises	O
to	O
meet	O
the	O
challenges	O
we	O
face	O
in	O
today	O
's	O
world	O
,	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
must	O
not	O
be	O
left	O
on	O
the	O
sidelines	O
.	O

We	O
need	O
a	O
strong	O
and	O
effective	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

Indeed	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
create	O
a	O
new	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
for	O
the	O
new	O
era	O
.	O

I	O
applaud	O
the	O
timely	O
initiative	O
by	O
the	O
Secretary-General	O
of	O
establishing	O
the	O
High-level	O
Panel	O
on	O
Threats	O
,	O
Challenges	O
and	O
Change	O
.	O

I	O
trust	O
that	O
the	O
Panel	O
will	O
present	O
the	O
Secretary-	O
General	I-ORG
with	O
a	O
bold	O
and	O
ambitious	O
plan	O
for	O
reforming	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

Peace	O
and	O
security	O
,	O
and	O
economic	O
and	O
social	O
issues	O
are	O
increasingly	O
intertwined	O
.	O

The	O
response	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
must	O
be	O
coordinated	O
and	O
comprehensive	O
.	O

United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
agencies	O
and	O
organs	O
must	O
be	O
effective	O
and	O
efficient	O
.	O

Changes	O
are	O
needed	O
throughout	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
system	O
.	O

The	O
reform	O
of	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
must	O
be	O
at	O
the	O
core	O
of	O
those	O
changes	O
.	O

In	O
recent	O
years	O
,	O
the	O
role	O
of	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
has	O
expanded	O
dramatically	O
in	O
scope	O
and	O
nature	O
.	O

The	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
must	O
fulfil	O
its	O
expanded	O
role	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
maximum	O
cooperation	O
and	O
participation	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
.	O

To	O
that	O
end	O
,	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
must	O
improve	O
its	O
representation	O
to	O
better	O
reflect	O
today	O
's	O
world	O
.	O

In	O
addition	O
,	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
must	O
be	O
provided	O
with	O
adequate	O
resources	O
to	O
address	O
challenges	O
effectively	O
.	O

Countries	O
with	O
the	O
will	O
and	O
the	O
resources	O
to	O
play	O
a	O
major	O
role	O
in	O
international	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
must	O
always	O
take	O
part	O
in	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
's	O
decision-making	O
process	O
.	O

The	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
therefore	O
needs	O
to	O
be	O
expanded	O
,	O
both	O
in	O
its	O
permanent	O
and	O
non-permanent	O
categories	O
,	O
adding	O
new	O
members	O
from	O
both	O
developing	O
and	O
developed	O
countries	O
.	O

The	O
universal	O
purpose	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
—	O
our	O
common	O
goal	O
—	O
is	O
to	O
maintain	O
international	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
our	O
conviction	O
that	O
peace	O
cannot	O
be	O
achieved	O
through	O
force	O
alone	O
.	O

On	O
the	O
basis	O
of	O
that	O
conviction	O
,	O
Japan	I-LOC
has	O
played	O
an	O
active	O
and	O
distinctive	O
role	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
has	O
made	O
considerable	O
resources	O
available	O
for	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
peacekeeping	O
operations	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
for	O
reconstruction	O
efforts	O
to	O
assist	O
in	O
the	O
consolidation	O
of	O
peace	O
.	O

Japan	I-LOC
's	O
Self-Defense	O
Forces	O
have	O
conducted	O
humanitarian	O
and	O
reconstruction	O
activities	O
in	O
such	O
areas	O
as	O
Timor-Leste	O
and	O
Iraq	I-LOC
.	O

Such	O
global	O
contributions	O
to	O
peace	O
are	O
rooted	O
in	O
the	O
fundamental	O
,	O
cherished	O
beliefs	O
of	O
the	O
Japanese	O
people	O
,	O
who	O
have	O
been	O
seeking	O
an	O
honoured	O
place	O
in	O
an	O
international	O
community	O
that	O
strives	O
for	O
peace	O
and	O
prosperity	O
.	O

Those	O
contributions	O
are	O
,	O
I	O
believe	O
,	O
greatly	O
appreciated	O
by	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
.	O

Recent	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
peace	O
operations	O
show	O
that	O
there	O
are	O
many	O
dimensions	O
to	O
the	O
achievement	O
and	O
consolidation	O
of	O
peace	O
.	O

Making	O
peace	O
a	O
reality	O
requires	O
comprehensive	O
efforts	O
,	O
ranging	O
from	O
peace-building	O
to	O
nation-building	O
.	O

We	O
believe	O
that	O
the	O
role	O
that	O
Japan	I-LOC
has	O
played	O
provides	O
a	O
solid	O
basis	O
for	O
its	O
assumption	O
of	O
permanent	O
membership	O
of	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
.	O

In	O
order	O
to	O
better	O
reflect	O
today	O
's	O
world	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
also	O
necessary	O
to	O
remove	O
the	O

"	O
enemy	O
State	O
"	O

clauses	O
from	O
the	O
Charter	O
,	O
as	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
has	O
already	O
recognized	O
those	O
provisions	O
to	O
be	O
obsolete	O
.	O

The	O
scale	O
of	O
assessments	O
for	O
Member	O
States	I-LOC
needs	O
to	O
be	O
more	O
balanced	O
.	O

Next	O
year	O
,	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
will	O
celebrate	O
its	O
sixtieth	O
anniversary	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
hold	O
a	O
high-level	O
plenary	O
meeting	O
to	O
review	O
progress	O
on	O
all	O
of	O
the	O
commitments	O
in	O
the	O
Millennium	O
Declaration	I-MISC
.	O

Development	I-MISC
,	O
global	O
security	O
and	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
reform	O
are	O
all	O
high	O
on	O
the	O
agenda	O
.	O

Changes	O
are	O
needed	O
on	O
all	O
fronts	O
.	O

The	O
time	O
has	O
come	O
to	O
make	O
a	O
historic	O
decision	O
to	O
reform	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
and	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
in	O
particular	O
.	O

Time	O
is	O
limited	O
.	O

Our	O
future	O
—	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
—	O
is	O
at	O
stake	O
.	O

I	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
call	O
upon	O
the	O
members	O
of	O
this	O
body	O
to	O
work	O
together	O
and	O
take	O
a	O
bold	O
step	O
towards	O
the	O
creation	O
of	O
a	O
new	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
for	O
the	O
new	O
era	O
.	O
