We	O
wish	O
you	O
every	O
success	O
and	O
assure	O
you	O
of	O
our	O
fullest	O
cooperation	O
.	O

At	O
a	O
time	O
when	O
the	O
world	O
is	O
facing	O
multiple	O
challenges	O
,	O
there	O
is	O
renewed	O
attention	O
to	O
the	O
role	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
in	O
advancing	O
international	O
peace	O
,	O
security	O
and	O
prosperity	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
never	O
has	O
scepticism	O
about	O
the	O
capacity	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
to	O
do	O
so	O
been	O
higher	O
,	O
or	O
the	O
external	O
environment	O
less	O
propitious	O
for	O
multilateralism	O
.	O

The	O
nearly	O
seven	O
decades	O
of	O
work	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
hold	O
one	O
simple	O
lesson:	O
that	O
we	O
are	O
most	O
successful	O
when	O
we	O
adhere	O
to	O
the	O
letter	O
and	O
spirit	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Charter	I-MISC
,	O
basing	O
our	O
decisions	O
on	O
the	O
widest	O
possible	O
consensus	O
and	O
balancing	O
equitably	O
the	O
needs	O
and	O
responsibilities	O
of	O
nations	O
at	O
different	O
stages	O
and	O
levels	O
of	O
development	O
.	O

In	O
those	O
seven	O
decades	O
,	O
the	O
world	O
has	O
changed	O
in	O
fundamental	O
ways	O
.	O

Asia	I-LOC
and	O
Africa	I-LOC
are	O
independent	O
and	O
resurgent	O
.	O

Countries	O
are	O
now	O
not	O
only	O
more	O
interdependent	O
,	O
but	O
also	O
face	O
new	O
,	O
increasingly	O
complex	O
challenges	O
.	O

For	O
multilateralism	O
to	O
remain	O
relevant	O
and	O
effective	O
in	O
the	O
future	O
,	O
multilateral	O
institutions	O
need	O
to	O
be	O
reformed	O
urgently	O
.	O

The	O
place	O
to	O
begin	O
is	O
right	O
here	O
.	O

The	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
must	O
be	O
reformed	O
and	O
restructured	O
to	O
reflect	O
current	O
political	O
realities	O
.	O

More	O
developing	O
countries	O
should	O
be	O
included	O
as	O
both	O
permanent	O
and	O
non-permanent	O
members	O
.	O

The	O
multilateral	O
financial	O
institutions	O
should	O
also	O
enable	O
an	O
enhanced	O
voice	O
for	O
developing	O
countries	O
in	O
their	O
decision-making	O
structures	O
.	O

Multilateral	O
efforts	O
must	O
guide	O
our	O
quest	O
for	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
,	O
wherever	O
they	O
are	O
threatened	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
centrality	O
and	O
contribution	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
system	O
to	O
development	O
must	O
be	O
restored	O
.	O

Those	O
objectives	O
require	O
the	O
building	O
of	O
a	O
new	O
international	O
consensus	O
suited	O
to	O
our	O
time	O
and	O
rooted	O
in	O
today	O
's	O
realities	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
only	O
such	O
a	O
plan	O
of	O
action	O
that	O
will	O
enable	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
to	O
meet	O
the	O
twin	O
tests	O
of	O
legitimacy	O
,	O
and	O
effectiveness	O
and	O
efficiency	O
.	O

We	O
commend	O
your	O
choice	O
of	O
the	O
theme	O
of	O
this	O
session	O
.	O

Setting	O
the	O
stage	O
for	O
the	O
post-2015	O
development	O
agenda	O
is	O
especially	O
important	O
as	O
we	O
deal	O
with	O
a	O
lingering	O
global	O
economic	O
slowdown	O
and	O
continuing	O
volatility	O
in	O
financial	O
markets	O
.	O

These	O
have	O
imposed	O
disproportionately	O
heavy	O
costs	O
on	O
developing	O
countries	O
and	O
the	O
vulnerable	O
groups	O
within	O
them	O
.	O

Growth	O
and	O
inclusive	O
development	O
are	O
naturally	O
important	O
for	O
all	O
our	O
countries	O
.	O

They	O
require	O
a	O
supportive	O
international	O
economic	O
environment	O
,	O
enhanced	O
investment	O
flows	O
,	O
including	O
from	O
multilateral	O
development	O
banks	O
,	O
the	O
transfer	O
of	O
technology	O
,	O
and	O
an	O
open	O
multilateral	O
trading	O
regime	O
.	O

But	O
the	O
problems	O
of	O
the	O
more	O
than	O
1	O
billion	O
people	O
living	O
in	O
abject	O
poverty	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
need	O
to	O
be	O
attacked	O
more	O
directly	O
.	O

Poverty	O
remains	O
a	O
major	O
political	O
and	O
economic	O
challenge	O
,	O
and	O
its	O
eradication	O
requires	O
special	O
attention	O
and	O
a	O
new	O
collective	O
thrust	O
.	O

That	O
priority	O
should	O
anchor	O
the	O
post-2015	O
development	O
agenda	O
,	O
which	O
should	O
be	O
shaped	O
by	O
the	O
Member	O
States	O
so	O
that	O
it	O
enjoys	O
the	O
broadest	O
possible	O
support	O
and	O
acceptance	O
.	O

Issues	O
of	O
peace	O
,	O
security	O
,	O
human	O
rights	O
and	O
governance	O
are	O
important	O
and	O
need	O
to	O
be	O
addressed	O
.	O

But	O
we	O
will	O
fall	O
short	O
of	O
realizing	O
an	O
ambitious	O
post-2015	O
development	O
agenda	O
if	O
we	O
focus	O
merely	O
on	O
governance	O
issues	O
at	O
the	O
cost	O
of	O
robust	O
economic	O
growth	O
.	O

This	O
agenda	O
should	O
not	O
be	O
merely	O
about	O
reprioritizing	O
domestic	O
spending	O
,	O
but	O
also	O
about	O
fostering	O
genuine	O
international	O
partnerships	O
between	O
developing	O
and	O
developed	O
countries	O
to	O
bring	O
about	O
change	O
.	O

All	O
of	O
us	O
need	O
the	O
policy	O
space	O
necessary	O
to	O
set	O
our	O
own	O
domestic	O
priorities	O
.	O

No	O
one	O
knows	O
the	O
condition	O
of	O
developing	O
countries	O
better	O
than	O
the	O
developing	O
countries	O
themselves	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
therefore	O
important	O
that	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
set	O
clear	O
and	O
concise	O
goals	O
and	O
provide	O
practical	O
and	O
well-defined	O
means	O
of	O
implementation	O
,	O
including	O
an	O
adequate	O
flow	O
of	O
resources	O
and	O
the	O
transfer	O
of	O
technology	O
,	O
taking	O
the	O
views	O
of	O
developing	O
countries	O
fully	O
into	O
account	O
.	O

￼A	O
meaningful	O
post-2015	O
agenda	O
must	O
place	O
equally	O
high	O
priority	O
on	O
food	O
and	O
nutrition	O
,	O
health	O
,	O
education	O
,	O
infrastructure	O
,	O
water	O
,	O
sanitation	O
,	O
energy	O
and	O
combating	O
discrimination	O
against	O
women	O
.	O

Especially	O
critical	O
is	O
women	O
's	O
equal	O
access	O
to	O
economic	O
opportunities	O
and	O
ensuring	O
that	O
they	O
do	O
not	O
become	O
victims	O
of	O
violence	O
or	O
the	O
targets	O
of	O
prejudice	O
.	O

In	O
India	I-LOC
,	O
we	O
have	O
sought	O
to	O
promote	O
inclusive	O
development	O
in	O
multiple	O
ways	O
.	O

Legislation	O
has	O
broadened	O
access	O
to	O
education	O
and	O
secured	O
rural	O
livelihoods	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
now	O
building	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
largest	O
programme	O
for	O
food	O
security	O
.	O

Digital	O
technology	O
is	O
being	O
harnessed	O
to	O
improve	O
the	O
delivery	O
of	O
public	O
services	O
and	O
benefits	O
to	O
the	O
people	O
.	O

India	I-LOC
is	O
proud	O
of	O
its	O
partnerships	O
with	O
developing	O
countries	O
.	O

Using	O
modest	O
resources	O
,	O
we	O
have	O
built	O
strong	O
ties	O
with	O
Africa	I-LOC
and	O
the	O
least	O
developed	O
countries	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
committed	O
to	O
building	O
100	O
institutions	O
in	O
Africa	I-LOC
and	O
have	O
offered	O
capacity-building	O
support	O
,	O
including	O
thousands	O
of	O
scholarships	O
,	O
and	O
made	O
available	O
over	O
$9	O
.	O
5	O
billion	O
of	O
concessional	O
assistance	O
.	O

India	I-LOC
and	O
Africa	O
are	O
engaging	O
through	O
the	O
India-Africa	I-LOC
Forum	O
Summit	I-LOC
process	O
.	O

Climate	O
change	O
is	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
defining	O
challenges	O
of	O
our	O
times	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
summon	O
the	O
political	O
will	O
necessary	O
to	O
craft	O
a	O
robust	O
global	O
response	O
to	O
climate	O
change	O
on	O
the	O
basis	O
of	O
equity	O
and	O
the	O
principle	O
of	O
common	O
but	O
differentiated	O
responsibilities	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
deeply	O
concerned	O
about	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
West	I-LOC
Asia	I-LOC
,	O
a	O
region	O
with	O
which	O
India	I-LOC
shares	O
deep	O
bonds	O
of	O
history	O
and	O
one	O
that	O
is	O
critical	O
for	O
our	O
energy	O
security	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
the	O
livelihoods	O
of	O
the	O
nearly	O
7	O
million	O
Indians	I-MISC
who	O
work	O
and	O
live	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
.	O

Not	O
only	O
is	O
the	O
increasingly	O
lethal	O
conflict	O
in	O
Syria	I-LOC
a	O
tragedy	O
for	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
Syria	I-LOC
,	O
but	O
it	O
also	O
threatens	O
stability	O
and	O
security	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
and	O
beyond	O
.	O

It	O
has	O
been	O
made	O
worse	O
by	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
chemical	O
weapons	O
.	O

The	O
use	O
of	O
chemical	O
weapons	O
,	O
whosoever	O
may	O
have	O
deployed	O
them	O
,	O
must	O
be	O
condemned	O
in	O
the	O
strongest	O
possible	O
terms	O
.	O

India	I-LOC
strongly	O
supports	O
the	O
elimination	O
of	O
chemical-weapons	O
material	O
and	O
equipment	O
in	O
Syria	I-LOC
.	O
There	O
is	O
no	O
military	O
solution	O
to	O
that	O
conflict	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
intensify	O
efforts	O
to	O
end	O
the	O
conflict	O
and	O
seek	O
a	O
political	O
settlement	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
essential	O
that	O
the	O
"	O
Geneva	I-LOC
II	O
"	O
conference	O
be	O
convened	O
at	O
the	O
earliest	O
opportunity	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
encouraged	O
that	O
direct	O
talks	O
have	O
resumed	O
between	O
Israel	I-LOC
and	O
Palestine	I-LOC
.	O

India	I-LOC
supports	O
the	O
early	O
realization	O
of	O
a	O
sovereign	O
,	O
independent	O
,	O
viable	O
and	O
united	O
State	O
of	O
Palestine	I-LOC
,	O
with	O
East	I-LOC
Jerusalem	I-LOC
as	O
its	O
capital	O
,	O
living	O
within	O
secure	O
and	O
recognized	O
borders	O
,	O
side	O
by	O
side	O
and	O
at	O
peace	O
with	O
Israel	I-LOC
.	O

We	O
also	O
remain	O
committed	O
to	O
the	O
Palestinian	O
quest	O
for	O
full	O
membership	O
in	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

In	O
our	O
own	O
region	O
,	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
prepares	O
for	O
a	O
historic	O
political	O
,	O
security	O
and	O
economic	O
transition	O
.	O

The	O
international	O
community	O
must	O
support	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
through	O
this	O
transition	O
and	O
beyond	O
in	O
combating	O
terrorism	O
,	O
preserving	O
the	O
progress	O
of	O
the	O
past	O
decade	O
and	O
creating	O
a	O
stable	O
,	O
united	O
and	O
prosperous	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
.	O

Terrorism	O
remains	O
a	O
grave	O
threat	O
to	O
security	O
and	O
stability	O
everywhere	O
and	O
exacts	O
a	O
heavy	O
toll	O
of	O
innocent	O
lives	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

From	O
Africa	I-LOC
to	O
Asia	I-LOC
,	O
we	O
have	O
seen	O
several	O
manifestations	O
of	O
this	O
menace	O
in	O
the	O
last	O
few	O
days	O
alone	O
.	O

State-sponsored	O
,	O
cross-border	O
terrorism	O
is	O
of	O
particular	O
concern	O
to	O
India	I-LOC
,	O
also	O
on	O
account	O
of	O
the	O
fact	O
that	O
the	O
epicentre	O
of	O
terrorism	O
in	O
our	O
region	O
is	O
located	O
in	O
our	O
neighbourhood	O
,	O
in	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
.	O

From	O
this	O
rostrum	O
yesterday	O
,	O
Prime	O
Minister	O
Nawaz	I-PER
Sharif	I-PER
of	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
spoke	O
of	O
making	O
a	O
new	O
beginning	O
(see	O
A/68/PV	O
.	O
15)	O
.	O

I	O
reciprocate	O
his	O
sentiments	O
and	O
am	O
looking	O
forward	O
to	O
meeting	O
him	O
tomorrow	O
.	O

India	I-LOC
is	O
sincerely	O
committed	O
to	O
resolving	O
all	O
issues	O
with	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
,	O
including	O
the	O
issue	O
of	O
Jammu	I-LOC
and	O
Kashmir	I-LOC
,	O
through	O
bilateral	O
dialogue	O
on	O
the	O
basis	O
of	O
the	O
Simla	I-MISC
Agreement	I-MISC
.	O

However	O
,	O
for	O
progress	O
to	O
be	O
made	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
imperative	O
that	O
the	O
territory	O
of	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
and	O
the	O
areas	O
under	O
its	O
control	O
not	O
be	O
utilized	O
for	O
aiding	O
and	O
abetting	O
terrorism	O
directed	O
against	O
India	I-LOC
.	O

It	O
is	O
equally	O
important	O
that	O
the	O
terrorist	O
machinery	O
that	O
draws	O
its	O
sustenance	O
from	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
be	O
shut	O
down	O
.	O

There	O
must	O
be	O
a	O
clear	O
understanding	O
of	O
the	O
fact	O
that	O
Jammu	I-LOC
and	O
Kashmir	I-LOC
is	O
an	O
integral	O
part	O
of	O
India	I-LOC
and	O
that	O
there	O
can	O
never	O
,	O
ever	O
,	O
be	O
a	O
compromise	O
with	O
the	O
unity	O
and	O
territorial	O
integrity	O
of	O
India	I-LOC
.	O

We	O
need	O
to	O
renew	O
our	O
commitment	O
,	O
especially	O
here	O
at	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
to	O
concerted	O
,	O
cohesive	O
and	O
continuing	O
global	O
action	O
against	O
terrorism	O
.	O

There	O
can	O
be	O
no	O
tolerance	O
for	O
States	O
sheltering	O
,	O
arming	O
,	O
training	O
or	O
financing	O
terrorists	O
.	O

Nor	O
can	O
States	I-LOC
absolve	O
themselves	O
of	O
the	O
responsibility	O
to	O
prevent	O
their	O
territories	O
from	O
being	O
used	O
to	O
launch	O
acts	O
of	O
terrorism	O
.	O

￼The	O
increasingly	O
complex	O
challenges	O
to	O
international	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
require	O
a	O
new	O
international	O
consensus	O
to	O
be	O
built	O
,	O
whether	O
it	O
is	O
in	O
the	O
field	O
of	O
cybersecurity	O
,	O
non-proliferation	O
or	O
terrorism	O
.	O

This	O
year	O
,	O
25	O
years	O
after	O
Prime	O
Minister	O
Rajiv	I-PER
Gandhi	I-PER
put	O
forward	O
a	O
comprehensive	O
action	O
plan	O
for	O
a	O
nuclear-	O
weapon-free	O
and	O
non-violent	O
world	O
order	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
strengthen	O
efforts	O
against	O
nuclear	O
proliferation	O
and	O
pursue	O
time-bound	O
,	O
universal	O
,	O
non-discriminatory	O
,	O
phased	O
and	O
verifiable	O
nuclear	O
disarmament	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
also	O
guard	O
against	O
terrorists	O
and	O
non-State	O
actors	O
gaining	O
access	O
to	O
sensitive	O
materials	O
and	O
technologies	O
.	O

Two	O
years	O
from	O
now	O
,	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
will	O
be	O
70	O
years	O
old	O
.	O

Every	O
new	O
State	O
born	O
during	O
that	O
period	O
of	O
70	O
years	O
has	O
taken	O
its	O
place	O
in	O
the	O
Assembly	I-ORG
not	O
just	O
with	O
pride	O
but	O
also	O
with	O
hope	O
.	O

The	O
year	O
2015	O
will	O
be	O
a	O
time	O
to	O
celebrate	O
our	O
successes	O
and	O
ensure	O
that	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
is	O
ready	O
for	O
this	O
century	O
,	O
by	O
completing	O
much-needed	O
reforms	O
of	O
the	O
Organization	I-ORG
and	O
its	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
,	O
developing	O
an	O
ambitious	O
and	O
balanced	O
post-2015	O
development	O
agenda	O
and	O
demonstrating	O
our	O
capacity	O
to	O
cooperate	O
effectively	O
for	O
durable	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
we	O
live	O
in	O
.	O
