Sixty-three	O
years	O
after	O
its	O
formation	O
,	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
remains	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
central	O
international	O
body	O
.	O

Only	O
here	O
do	O
all	O
countries	O
come	O
together	O
to	O
devise	O
solutions	O
and	O
to	O
forge	O
collective	O
action	O
on	O
global	O
challenges	O
.	O

And	O
these	O
are	O
particularly	O
challenging	O
times	O
.	O

As	O
the	O
Secretary-General	O
and	O
many	O
others	O
have	O
noted	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
facing	O
a	O
global	O
financial	O
crisis	O
,	O
a	O
global	O
energy	O
crisis	O
and	O
a	O
global	O
food	O
crisis	O
.	O

More	O
than	O
ever	O
before	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
an	O
interconnected	O
and	O
interdependent	O
world	O
community	O
.	O

The	O
Charter	O
goals	O
of	O
peace	O
and	O
prosperity	O
require	O
the	O
full	O
support	O
of	O
all	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Members	O
.	O

New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
was	O
a	O
founding	O
member	O
in	O
1945	O
,	O
and	O
our	O
commitment	O
to	O
this	O
body	O
is	O
as	O
strong	O
now	O
as	O
it	O
was	O
then	O
.	O

At	O
such	O
a	O
difficult	O
time	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
we	O
need	O
leadership	O
,	O
courage	O
and	O
a	O
recommitment	O
of	O
our	O
resources	O
to	O
tackle	O
the	O
issues	O
before	O
us	O
.	O

When	O
the	O
food	O
crisis	O
was	O
first	O
in	O
the	O
headlines	O
,	O
the	O
Secretary-General	O
's	O
High-Level	O
Task	O
Force	O
provided	O
a	O
mechanism	O
for	O
us	O
all	O
to	O
respond	O
.	O

Having	O
contributed	O
nearly	O
$NZ	O
10	O
million	O
to	O
date	O
,	O
New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
is	O
among	O
those	O
assisting	O
with	O
urgent	O
food	O
security	O
needs	O
and	O
medium-term	O
policy	O
responses	O
.	O

A	O
successful	O
conclusion	O
of	O
the	O
Doha	I-LOC
Development	I-MISC
Round	O
would	O
alleviate	O
much	O
of	O
the	O
pressure	O
on	O
the	O
demand-supply	O
imbalance	O
.	O

On	O
the	O
development	O
theme	O
of	O
this	O
sixty-third	O
session	O
,	O
New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
fully	O
associates	O
with	O
the	O
Millennium	O
Development	I-MISC
Goal	O
(MDG)	O
Global	O
Call	O
to	O
Action	O
Campaign	O
.	O

Support	O
is	O
urgently	O
needed	O
to	O
revitalize	O
collective	O
efforts	O
,	O
including	O
developing	O
and	O
strengthening	O
partnerships	O
between	O
traditional	O
and	O
new	O
donors	O
,	O
the	O
private	O
sector	O
and	O
civil	O
society	O
,	O
and	O
through	O
South-South	O
cooperation	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
set	O
to	O
play	O
our	O
part	O
.	O

New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
is	O
significantly	O
stepping	O
up	O
official	O
development	O
assistance	O
(ODA)	O
from	O
0	O
.	O
27	O
per	O
cent	O
of	O
gross	O
national	O
income	O
in	O
2007	O
to	O
0	O
.	O
35	O
per	O
cent	O
by	O
2010-2011	O
.	O

That	O
62	O
per	O
cent	O
increase	O
will	O
take	O
New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
aid	O
to	O
over	O
$NZ	O
600	O
million	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
acutely	O
aware	O
that	O
the	O
Pacific	O
is	O
the	O
second	O
region	O
after	O
sub-	O
Saharan	O
Africa	O
that	O
is	O
least	O
likely	O
to	O
meet	O
the	O
MDG	O
targets	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
therefore	O
looking	O
to	O
direct	O
our	O
increased	O
ODA	O
there	O
,	O
through	O
a	O
Pacific	O
strategy	O
,	O
which	O
focuses	O
poverty	O
reduction	O
efforts	O
around	O
four	O
key	O
pillars:	O
strengthening	O
governance	O
,	O
achieving	O
broader-based	O
growth	O
and	O
sustainable	O
livelihoods	O
,	O
improving	O
health	O
and	O
education	O
,	O
and	O
reducing	O
vulnerabilities	O
,	O
including	O
to	O
climate	O
change	O
.	O

In	O
these	O
challenging	O
times	O
,	O
we	O
look	O
to	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
to	O
deliver	O
effectively	O
for	O
development	O
,	O
for	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
and	O
on	O
human	O
rights	O
.	O

Our	O
Organization	O
must	O
continue	O
to	O
evolve	O
along	O
with	O
the	O
changing	O
demands	O
on	O
it	O
.	O

Momentum	O
needs	O
to	O
be	O
maintained	O
in	O
the	O
modernization	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

I	O
would	O
now	O
like	O
to	O
turn	O
to	O
the	O
challenges	O
of	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
,	O
from	O
which	O
our	O
own	O
region	O
is	O
not	O
immune	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
Pacific	O
Islands	O
Forum	O
held	O
in	O
Niue	I-LOC
last	O
month	O
,	O
New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
and	O
other	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
Pacific	O
Forum	O
community	O
expressed	O
profound	O
disappointment	O
at	O
Fiji	I-LOC
's	O
lack	O
of	O
progress	O
towards	O
restoring	O
democratic	O
government	O
.	O

The	O
Forum	O
communiqué	O
urged	O
the	O
interim	O
regime	O
in	O
Fiji	I-LOC
to	O
fulfil	O
its	O
promise	O
to	O
hold	O
elections	O
in	O
accordance	O
with	O
Fiji	I-LOC
's	O
existing	O
constitution	O
by	O
March	I-LOC
next	O
year	O
.	O

Leaders	O
also	O
acknowledged	O
that	O
there	O
were	O
long-term	O
issues	O
to	O
be	O
resolved	O
in	O
Fiji	I-LOC
and	O
supported	O
a	O
Commonwealth-led	O
independent	O
and	O
inclusive	O
political	O
dialogue	O
process	O
to	O
address	O
them	O
.	O

That	O
will	O
not	O
only	O
create	O
a	O
more	O
conducive	O
environment	O
for	O
elections	O
,	O
but	O
also	O
enable	O
a	O
newly	O
elected	O
Government	O
to	O
engage	O
with	O
key	O
stakeholders	O
to	O
promote	O
national	O
reconciliation	O
.	O

New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
urges	O
all	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Members	O
to	O
support	O
the	O
steps	O
taken	O
by	O
the	O
Pacific	O
Islands	O
Forum	O
to	O
encourage	O
Fiji	I-LOC
to	O
return	O
to	O
democratic	O
and	O
constitutional	O
government	O
as	O
soon	O
as	O
possible	O
.	O

Our	O
region	O
is	O
also	O
home	O
to	O
Timor-Leste	O
,	O
a	O
partner	O
and	O
friend	O
of	O
New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
.	O

We	O
are	O
pleased	O
to	O
see	O
encouraging	O
progress	O
since	O
last	O
year	O
's	O
elections	O
,	O
especially	O
the	O
building	O
of	O
institutions	O
and	O
improving	O
governance	O
.	O

That	O
was	O
achieved	O
despite	O
assassination	O
attempts	O
on	O
Timor-	O
Leste	O
's	O
leadership	O
.	O

The	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Integrated	O
Mission	I-LOC
in	O
Timor-Leste	O
(UNMIT)	O
and	O
the	O
International	O
Stabilization	O
Force	O
continue	O
to	O
play	O
a	O
valuable	O
role	O
in	O
helping	O
to	O
maintain	O
security	O
.	O

New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
strongly	O
supports	O
the	O
UNMIT	O
mandate	O
and	O
its	O
extension	O
beyond	O
February	O
2009	O
.	O

Planning	O
for	O
security	O
in	O
the	O
longer	O
term	O
,	O
to	O
ensure	O
appropriately	O
sized	O
and	O
resourced	O
institutions	O
with	O
clearly	O
delineated	O
roles	O
and	O
responsibilities	O
,	O
is	O
also	O
a	O
key	O
issue	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
stand	O
ready	O
to	O
help	O
.	O

Also	O
within	O
our	O
region	O
,	O
the	O
political	O
,	O
economic	O
and	O
human	O
rights	O
situation	O
in	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
remains	O
troubling	O
.	O

We	O
urge	O
the	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
authorities	O
to	O
achieve	O
national	O
reconciliation	O
through	O
open	O
and	O
constructive	O
dialogue	O
and	O
to	O
respect	O
universal	O
human	O
rights	O
in	O
the	O
country	O
,	O
consistent	O
with	O
international	O
obligations	O
.	O

We	O
support	O
the	O
efforts	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
to	O
sustain	O
a	O
dialogue	O
with	O
the	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
Government	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
build	O
foundations	O
for	O
the	O
future	O
.	O

On	O
the	O
African	O
continent	O
,	O
the	O
humanitarian	O
disaster	O
caused	O
by	O
the	O
conflict	O
in	O
Darfur	O
is	O
unacceptable	O
.	O

The	O
targeting	O
of	O
civilians	O
by	O
State	O
and	O
non-State	O
parties	O
,	O
is	O
a	O
flagrant	O
breach	O
of	O
international	O
human	O
rights	O
law	O
.	O

The	O
widespread	O
absence	O
of	O
justice	O
and	O
accountability	O
for	O
such	O
human	O
rights	O
violations	O
and	O
the	O
impunity	O
that	O
this	O
promotes	O
represent	O
major	O
obstacles	O
to	O
improving	O
the	O
human	O
rights	O
situation	O
in	O
Darfur	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
case	O
of	O
Zimbabwe	I-LOC
,	O
the	O
recent	O
announcement	O
of	O
a	O
power-sharing	O
agreement	O
offers	O
hope	O
that	O
the	O
long	O
period	O
of	O
violent	O
repression	O
and	O
human	O
rights	O
abuses	O
by	O
the	O
previous	O
Government	O
can	O
be	O
brought	O
to	O
a	O
close	O
.	O

The	O
international	O
community	O
will	O
be	O
watching	O
closely	O
to	O
see	O
that	O
all	O
parties	O
fulfil	O
the	O
commitments	O
that	O
they	O
have	O
made	O
to	O
bring	O
about	O
peace	O
,	O
respect	O
for	O
political	O
freedom	O
and	O
human	O
rights	O
and	O
a	O
Government	O
which	O
reflects	O
the	O
will	O
of	O
the	O
people	O
.	O

Let	O
me	O
turn	O
now	O
to	O
the	O
Middle	O
East	O
.	O

New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
continues	O
to	O
be	O
strongly	O
supportive	O
of	O
all	O
attempts	O
to	O
find	O
a	O
lasting	O
solution	O
to	O
the	O
Arab-	O
Israeli	O
conflict	O
.	O

We	O
share	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
's	O
vision	O
for	O
a	O
viable	O
and	O
territorially	O
contiguous	O
Palestinian	O
State	O
,	O
existing	O
side	O
by	O
side	O
in	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
with	O
the	O
State	O
of	O
Israel	I-LOC
.	O

In	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
,	O
despite	O
political	O
progress	O
,	O
the	O
overall	O
situation	O
is	O
fragile	O
.	O

The	O
international	O
community	O
needs	O
to	O
devote	O
more	O
resources	O
to	O
ending	O
the	O
conflict	O
and	O
to	O
assisting	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
in	O
their	O
efforts	O
to	O
stabilize	O
and	O
rebuild	O
their	O
country	O
.	O

Closer	O
to	O
home	O
,	O
New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
welcomes	O
the	O
recent	O
improvement	O
in	O
cross-	O
Strait	O
relations	O
.	O

Cross-Strait	O
stability	O
is	O
vital	O
to	O
the	O
security	O
of	O
the	O
greater	O
Asia-Pacific	O
region	O
.	O

We	O
encourage	O
China	I-LOC
and	O
Taiwan	I-LOC
to	O
maintain	O
the	O
dialogue	O
which	O
has	O
been	O
established	O
.	O

New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
remains	O
a	O
strong	O
supporter	O
of	O
efforts	O
to	O
protect	O
and	O
maintain	O
the	O
international	O
rule	O
of	O
law	O
.	O

When	O
the	O
ICC	O
was	O
first	O
established	O
,	O
it	O
was	O
widely	O
considered	O
to	O
herald	O
the	O
beginning	O
of	O
a	O
new	O
era	O
in	O
international	O
criminal	O
justice	O
.	O

The	O
Court	O
has	O
now	O
reached	O
a	O
crucial	O
stage	O
in	O
its	O
development	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
has	O
become	O
clear	O
that	O
the	O
establishment	O
of	O
a	O
global	O
justice	O
system	O
brings	O
with	O
it	O
many	O
challenges	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
of	O
the	O
utmost	O
importance	O
that	O
States	I-LOC
rise	O
to	O
those	O
challenges	O
.	O

To	O
fail	O
to	O
do	O
so	O
would	O
be	O
a	O
betrayal	O
of	O
the	O
victims	O
of	O
egregious	O
crimes	O
.	O

New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
urges	O
States	I-LOC
to	O
make	O
every	O
effort	O
to	O
ensure	O
the	O
independence	O
and	O
success	O
of	O
the	O
Court	O
.	O

The	O
Court	O
needs	O
our	O
full	O
support	O
and	O
cooperation	O
to	O
ensure	O
that	O
individuals	O
responsible	O
for	O
the	O
most	O
serious	O
violations	O
of	O
international	O
law	O
are	O
brought	O
to	O
justice	O
without	O
delay	O
.	O

In	O
this	O
sixtieth	O
anniversary	O
year	O
of	O
the	O
Universal	O
Declaration	I-MISC
of	O
Human	O
Rights	O
,	O
we	O
acknowledge	O
the	O
many	O
international	O
human	O
rights	O
conventions	O
that	O
have	O
arisen	O
out	O
of	O
that	O
unique	O
statement	O
of	O
overriding	O
principles	O
.	O

New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
played	O
an	O
active	O
part	O
in	O
the	O
design	O
of	O
the	O
new	O
Human	O
Rights	O
Council	I-ORG
,	O
and	O
we	O
are	O
seeking	O
election	O
to	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
next	O
year	O
,	O
so	O
as	O
to	O
be	O
more	O
closely	O
involved	O
in	O
its	O
work	O
.	O

We	O
look	O
forward	O
to	O
the	O
first	O
conference	O
of	O
States	I-LOC
parties	O
,	O
and	O
to	O
the	O
opportunity	O
the	O
Convention	O
offers	O
to	O
make	O
a	O
real	O
improvement	O
in	O
the	O
lives	O
and	O
human	O
rights	O
of	O
disabled	O
people	O
everywhere	O
.	O

Finally	O
,	O
let	O
me	O
reiterate	O
the	O
importance	O
that	O
New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
attaches	O
to	O
the	O
concept	O
of	O
the	O
responsibility	O
to	O
protect	O
.	O

The	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
through	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
,	O
should	O
be	O
prepared	O
to	O
protect	O
people	O
against	O
ethnic	O
cleansing	O
,	O
genocide	O
,	O
war	O
crimes	O
and	O
crimes	O
against	O
humanity	O
when	O
national	O
authorities	O
fail	O
to	O
do	O
so	O
.	O

There	O
is	O
a	O
clear	O
need	O
to	O
enhance	O
early	O
warning	O
systems	O
to	O
enable	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
to	O
act	O
in	O
a	O
timely	O
manner	O
.	O

We	O
look	O
forward	O
to	O
the	O
report	O
of	O
the	O
Secretary-General	O
on	O
the	O
responsibility	O
to	O
protect	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
stand	O
ready	O
to	O
help	O
to	O
take	O
that	O
important	O
initiative	O
forward	O
.	O

As	O
we	O
look	O
forward	O
to	O
the	O
year	O
ahead	O
,	O
New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
pledges	O
to	O
work	O
actively	O
with	O
others	O
in	O
our	O
collective	O
stewardship	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

We	O
shall	O
play	O
our	O
part	O
in	O
the	O
continuing	O
,	O
patient	O
process	O
of	O
renewing	O
our	O
Organization	O
and	O
of	O
making	O
it	O
more	O
resilient	O
and	O
responsive	O
.	O
