We	O
are	O
convinced	O
that	O
her	O
vast	O
experience	O
in	O
international	O
relations	O
and	O
able	O
leadership	O
will	O
lead	O
this	O
session	O
to	O
a	O
successful	O
conclusion	O
.	O

I	O
would	O
also	O
like	O
to	O
pay	O
tribute	O
to	O
her	O
predecessor	O
,	O
Mr.	O
Jan	O
Eliasson	O
,	O
who	O
led	O
the	O
last	O
session	O
of	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
most	O
ably	O
and	O
successfully	O
.	O

His	O
tireless	O
and	O
dedicated	O
service	O
to	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
will	O
be	O
indelibly	O
etched	O
in	O
our	O
collective	O
memory	O
.	O

The	O
reform	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
to	O
meet	O
the	O
new	O
challenges	O
of	O
our	O
times	O
is	O
an	O
ongoing	O
process	O
that	O
needs	O
to	O
be	O
assessed	O
continuously	O
.	O

While	O
we	O
have	O
achieved	O
tangible	O
progress	O
in	O
some	O
areas	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
the	O
establishment	O
of	O
the	O
Human	O
Rights	O
Council	I-ORG
and	O
the	O
Peacebuilding	O
Commission	O
,	O
progress	O
has	O
yet	O
to	O
be	O
made	O
in	O
other	O
areas	O
.	O

The	O
success	O
of	O
the	O
reform	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
must	O
be	O
judged	O
in	O
terms	O
of	O
its	O
effective	O
response	O
to	O
the	O
contemporary	O
needs	O
of	O
Member	O
States	I-LOC
,	O
in	O
particular	O
those	O
of	O
the	O
developing	O
countries	O
,	O
which	O
form	O
the	O
majority	O
of	O
the	O
membership	O
.	O

While	O
many	O
States	I-LOC
,	O
including	O
the	O
developing	O
countries	O
,	O
struggle	O
to	O
protect	O
and	O
advance	O
the	O
principles	O
and	O
practices	O
of	O
multilateralism	O
,	O
the	O
tendency	O
towards	O
unilateralism	O
remains	O
strong	O
.	O

That	O
unhealthy	O
tendency	O
can	O
in	O
no	O
way	O
gain	O
ascendancy	O
if	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
is	O
to	O
remain	O
viable	O
.	O

Attempts	O
by	O
some	O
strong	O
and	O
powerful	O
States	I-LOC
to	O
impose	O
their	O
will	O
on	O
developing	O
countries	O
in	O
pursuit	O
of	O
their	O
political	O
agenda	O
create	O
an	O
environment	O
of	O
hostility	O
in	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
.	O

To	O
our	O
dismay	O
and	O
frustration	O
,	O
there	O
has	O
been	O
glaring	O
abuse	O
of	O
the	O
mandate	O
entrusted	O
to	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
by	O
Member	O
States	I-LOC
by	O
unjustly	O
placing	O
the	O
situation	O
of	O
my	O
country	O
on	O
the	O
agenda	O
of	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
and	O
by	O
alleging	O
that	O
it	O
poses	O
a	O
threat	O
to	O
regional	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
.	O

Nothing	O
could	O
be	O
further	O
from	O
the	O
truth	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
has	O
done	O
nothing	O
that	O
can	O
undermine	O
the	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
of	O
any	O
country	O
,	O
let	O
alone	O
regional	O
or	O
international	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
has	O
close	O
and	O
cordial	O
relations	O
with	O
all	O
its	O
five	O
neighbours	O
and	O
other	O
countries	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
.	O

The	O
founders	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
did	O
not	O
intend	O
the	O
world	O
body	O
to	O
become	O
a	O
forum	O
in	O
which	O
some	O
Members	O
with	O
political	O
and	O
economic	O
clout	O
could	O
gang	O
up	O
against	O
a	O
Member	O
State	O
and	O
label	O
it	O
as	O
what	O
it	O
is	O
not	O
.	O

We	O
therefore	O
urge	O
all	O
Member	O
States	I-LOC
to	O
resist	O
attempts	O
by	O
those	O
powerful	O
States	I-LOC
to	O
influence	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
to	O
take	O
action	O
against	O
a	O
Member	O
State	O
that	O
in	O
no	O
way	O
poses	O
any	O
threat	O
to	O
international	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
.	O

Regarding	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
reform	O
,	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
is	O
in	O
favour	O
of	O
the	O
expansion	O
of	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
in	O
both	O
the	O
permanent	O
and	O
non-permanent	O
categories	O
.	O

The	O
expanded	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
must	O
also	O
reflect	O
today	O
's	O
political	O
and	O
economic	O
realities	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
the	O
fact	O
that	O
we	O
have	O
not	O
made	O
substantial	O
progress	O
on	O
the	O
expansion	O
of	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
demonstrates	O
the	O
sensitive	O
and	O
complex	O
nature	O
of	O
the	O
issue	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
extremely	O
important	O
that	O
this	O
issue	O
not	O
become	O
divisive	O
among	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
membership	O
.	O

Dialogue	O
and	O
consultations	O
must	O
continue	O
to	O
seek	O
a	O
solution	O
acceptable	O
to	O
the	O
overwhelming	O
majority	O
of	O
the	O
membership	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
encouraging	O
that	O
the	O
first	O
session	O
of	O
the	O
Human	O
Rights	O
Council	I-ORG
was	O
successfully	O
held	O
in	O
Geneva	I-LOC
in	O
June	O
and	O
that	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
is	O
now	O
working	O
in	O
full	O
swing	O
to	O
quickly	O
become	O
an	O
effectively	O
functioning	O
human	O
rights	O
body	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
's	O
active	O
participation	O
at	O
the	O
highest	O
level	O
in	O
that	O
session	O
is	O
a	O
reflection	O
of	O
our	O
commitment	O
to	O
further	O
strengthening	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
human	O
rights	O
machinery	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
important	O
that	O
the	O
principle	O
of	O
impartiality	O
,	O
objectivity	O
and	O
non-selectivity	O
be	O
scrupulously	O
observed	O
in	O
the	O
work	O
of	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
.	O

Although	O
we	O
want	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
to	O
become	O
an	O
effective	O
tool	O
in	O
the	O
strengthening	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
human	O
rights	O
machinery	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
not	O
giving	O
it	O
carte	O
blanche	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
incumbent	O
not	O
only	O
on	O
the	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
,	O
but	O
also	O
on	O
all	O
of	O
us	O
,	O
to	O
ensure	O
that	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
does	O
not	O
deviate	O
from	O
the	O
direction	O
in	O
which	O
we	O
expect	O
it	O
to	O
head	O
.	O

Terrorism	O
continues	O
to	O
defy	O
the	O
attempts	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
to	O
eliminate	O
it	O
,	O
raising	O
its	O
ugly	O
head	O
again	O
in	O
Mumbai	I-LOC
and	O
elsewhere	O
very	O
recently	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
of	O
the	O
view	O
that	O
it	O
is	O
only	O
through	O
the	O
involvement	O
of	O
every	O
community	O
of	O
people	O
that	O
we	O
can	O
be	O
forewarned	O
in	O
time	O
of	O
the	O
impending	O
onslaught	O
of	O
terrorist	O
acts	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
fully	O
supports	O
the	O
international	O
efforts	O
to	O
eliminate	O
terrorism	O
.	O

A	O
daunting	O
challenge	O
facing	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
is	O
the	O
horrendous	O
crime	O
of	O
human	O
trafficking	O
,	O
which	O
the	O
Secretary-General	O
aptly	O
refers	O
to	O
as	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
reprehensible	O
violations	O
of	O
human	O
rights	O
.	O

Despite	O
the	O
efforts	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
to	O
tackle	O
that	O
issue	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
decade	O
,	O
it	O
continues	O
to	O
grow	O
,	O
with	O
serious	O
national	O
and	O
international	O
implications	O
for	O
the	O
Governments	O
concerned	O
.	O

Human	O
trafficking	O
is	O
a	O
serious	O
international	O
issue	O
and	O
we	O
believe	O
that	O
it	O
requires	O
a	O
coordinated	O
and	O
cooperative	O
response	O
by	O
the	O
entire	O
international	O
community	O
to	O
address	O
the	O
issue	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
is	O
a	O
State	O
party	O
to	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Convention	O
against	O
Transnational	O
Organized	O
Crime	O
and	O
its	O
supplementary	O
Protocols	O
to	O
Prevent	O
,	O
Suppress	O
and	O
Punish	O
Trafficking	O
in	O
Persons	O
,	O
especially	O
Women	O
and	O
Children	O
and	O
against	O
the	O
Smuggling	O
of	O
Migrants	O
by	O
Land	O
,	O
Sea	O
and	O
Air	O
.	O

I	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
stress	O
that	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
regards	O
combating	O
trafficking	O
in	O
persons	O
as	O
a	O
national	O
task	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
making	O
relentless	O
efforts	O
in	O
that	O
regard	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
has	O
designated	O
HIV/AIDS	O
,	O
malaria	O
and	O
tuberculosis	O
as	O
diseases	O
of	O
national	O
concern	O
.	O

In	O
1989	O
,	O
we	O
set	O
up	O
a	O
high-level	O
multisectoral	O
national	O
AIDS	O
committee	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
been	O
cooperating	O
with	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
and	O
,	O
in	O
2001	O
,	O
our	O
national	O
AIDS	O
programme	O
and	O
the	O
Joint	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Programme	I-MISC
on	O
HIV/AIDS	O
(UNAIDS)	O
drew	O
up	O
a	O
joint	O
programme	O
of	O
action	O
covering	O
education	O
,	O
prevention	O
,	O
cure	O
and	O
rehabilitation	O
to	O
effectively	O
address	O
the	O
challenge	O
.	O

As	O
a	O
result	O
,	O
we	O
have	O
been	O
able	O
not	O
only	O
to	O
level	O
the	O
HIV/AIDS	O
infection	O
rate	O
,	O
but	O
to	O
reduce	O
it	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
also	O
serving	O
on	O
the	O
UNAIDS	O
Programme	I-MISC
Coordinating	O
Board	O
,	O
enabling	O
us	O
to	O
address	O
the	O
issue	O
at	O
both	O
the	O
national	O
and	O
international	O
levels	O
.	O

Narcotic	O
drugs	O
continue	O
to	O
be	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
threats	O
facing	O
us	O
today	O
.	O

As	O
the	O
Government	O
of	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
regards	O
the	O
eradication	O
of	O
narcotic	O
drugs	O
as	O
a	O
national	O
responsibility	O
,	O
it	O
has	O
striven	O
relentlessly	O
to	O
eradicate	O
such	O
drugs	O
by	O
2014	O
.	O

Our	O
determined	O
efforts	O
on	O
all	O
fronts	O
have	O
resulted	O
in	O
a	O
substantial	O
decrease	O
in	O
opium	O
production	O
.	O

I	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
reiterate	O
here	O
that	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
will	O
step	O
up	O
its	O
efforts	O
,	O
in	O
close	O
cooperation	O
with	O
friendly	O
countries	O
and	O
international	O
organizations	O
,	O
until	O
we	O
achieve	O
our	O
goal	O
.	O

Cooperation	O
with	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
is	O
a	O
cornerstone	O
of	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
's	O
foreign	O
policy	O
.	O

Our	O
track	O
record	O
has	O
proven	O
that	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
has	O
invariably	O
extended	O
its	O
cooperation	O
to	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
has	O
been	O
implementing	O
a	O
national	O
development	O
plan	O
with	O
the	O
aim	O
of	O
accelerating	O
growth	O
,	O
achieving	O
equitable	O
and	O
balanced	O
development	O
,	O
and	O
reducing	O
the	O
socio-economic	O
development	O
gap	O
between	O
rural	O
and	O
urban	O
areas	O
of	O
the	O
country	O
.	O

The	O
national	O
development	O
plan	O
addresses	O
the	O
major	O
aspects	O
of	O
the	O
Millennium	O
Development	I-MISC
Goals	I-MISC
(MDGs)	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
made	O
significant	O
progress	O
towards	O
achieving	O
the	O
MDGs	O
by	O
2015	O
,	O
particularly	O
in	O
such	O
areas	O
as	O
health	O
,	O
education	O
,	O
sustainable	O
access	O
to	O
safe	O
drinking	O
water	O
,	O
and	O
access	O
to	O
improved	O
sanitation	O
.	O

In	O
implementing	O
the	O
MDGs	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
primarily	O
relying	O
on	O
our	O
national	O
resources	O
.	O

In	O
that	O
regard	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
also	O
receiving	O
valuable	O
assistance	O
and	O
cooperation	O
from	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
agencies	O
concerned	O
.	O

Finally	O
,	O
I	O
wish	O
to	O
apprise	O
the	O
Assembly	I-ORG
of	O
the	O
political	O
developments	O
in	O
my	O
country	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
been	O
steadfastly	O
implementing	O
the	O
seven-step	O
road	O
map	O
for	O
transition	O
to	O
democracy	O
,	O
announced	O
in	O
August	O
2003	O
.	O

The	O
National	O
Convention	O
,	O
which	O
was	O
adjourned	O
on	O
31	O
January	O
2006	O
,	O
will	O
resume	O
its	O
session	O
on	O
10	O
October	O
and	O
continue	O
to	O
discuss	O
the	O
basic	O
principles	O
for	O
the	O
drafting	O
of	O
an	O
enduring	O
constitution	O
.	O

I	O
wish	O
to	O
stress	O
that	O
the	O
process	O
of	O
transforming	O
the	O
country	O
into	O
a	O
democratic	O
State	O
will	O
move	O
ahead	O
systematically	O
in	O
accordance	O
with	O
the	O
road	O
map	O
.	O

Before	O
concluding	O
,	O
I	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
reaffirm	O
our	O
commitment	O
to	O
working	O
together	O
in	O
upholding	O
the	O
principles	O
enunciated	O
in	O
the	O
Charter	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
and	O
in	O
strengthening	O
the	O
role	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
to	O
respond	O
to	O
the	O
challenges	O
of	O
the	O
twenty-first	O
century	O
.	O
