I	O
begin	O
by	O
joining	O
others	O
who	O
have	O
congratulated	O
you	O
,	O
Mr.	O
President	O
,	O
on	O
your	O
election	O
.	O

I	O
also	O
assure	O
you	O
of	O
the	O
New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
delegation	O
's	O
full	O
cooperation	O
as	O
you	O
carry	O
out	O
your	O
important	O
duties	O
.	O

I	O
also	O
welcome	O
the	O
admission	O
last	O
week	O
of	O
our	O
neighbour	O
and	O
friend	O
Tuvalu	I-LOC
into	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

The	O
admission	O
of	O
four	O
new	O
Pacific	O
nations	O
in	O
the	O
space	O
of	O
a	O
year	O
contributes	O
to	O
the	O
truly	O
universal	O
character	O
of	O
the	O
Organization	O
.	O

This	O
general	O
debate	O
is	O
taking	O
place	O
at	O
the	O
start	O
of	O
a	O
new	O
century	O
and	O
a	O
new	O
millennium	O
.	O

Secretary-General	O
Kofi	O
Annan	O
has	O
called	O
upon	O
the	O
Member	O
States	I-LOC
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
to	O
harness	O
the	O
symbolic	O
power	O
of	O
the	O
millennium	O
to	O
meet	O
the	O
real	O
and	O
urgent	O
needs	O
of	O
people	O
in	O
every	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
an	O
appropriate	O
time	O
to	O
recommit	O
ourselves	O
to	O
the	O
beliefs	O
,	O
the	O
values	O
and	O
the	O
principles	O
that	O
led	O
to	O
the	O
birth	O
of	O
the	O
Organization	O
55	O
years	O
ago	O
.	O

Like	O
many	O
other	O
Members	O
of	O
the	O
Organization	O
,	O
New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
is	O
a	O
small	O
country	O
that	O
tries	O
to	O
take	O
a	O
principled	O
and	O
independent	O
view	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

In	O
1945	O
,	O
in	O
San	I-LOC
Francisco	O
,	O
we	O
played	O
an	O
active	O
part	O
through	O
the	O
Labour	O
Prime	O
Minister	O
of	O
the	O
day	O
,	O
Peter	O
Fraser	O
,	O
in	O
framing	O
the	O
Charter	O
in	O
which	O
heads	O
of	O
State	O
and	O
Government	O
reaffirmed	O
their	O
faith	O
here	O
last	O
week	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
currently	O
making	O
our	O
largest-ever	O
contribution	O
to	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
peacekeeping	O
operation	O
in	O
East	O
Timor	O
.	O

This	O
commitment	O
underlines	O
our	O
full	O
support	O
for	O
the	O
central	O
role	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
in	O
building	O
a	O
stable	O
,	O
democratic	O
and	O
economically	O
viable	O
East	O
Timor	O
in	O
partnership	O
with	O
its	O
people	O
.	O

So	O
do	O
the	O
non-military	O
personnel	O
and	O
development	O
assistance	O
we	O
have	O
provided	O
to	O
help	O
the	O
East	O
Timorese	O
create	O
essential	O
services	O
.	O

Just	O
over	O
a	O
year	O
ago	O
,	O
the	O
East	O
Timorese	O
people	O
voted	O
overwhelmingly	O
for	O
an	O
independent	O
future	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
had	O
the	O
privilege	O
of	O
being	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Mission	I-LOC
in	O
East	O
Timor	O
(UNAMET)	O
group	O
that	O
oversaw	O
that	O
electoral	O
process	O
.	O

We	O
recall	O
the	O
horrors	O
which	O
followed	O
as	O
pro-integration	O
militias	O
laid	O
waste	O
to	O
the	O
territory	O
,	O
slaughtered	O
innocent	O
people	O
and	O
forced	O
thousands	O
of	O
East	O
Timorese	O
into	O
West	O
Timor	O
.	O

Relative	O
calm	O
and	O
stability	O
has	O
been	O
restored	O
in	O
most	O
of	O
East	O
Timor	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
remember	O
here	O
today	O
the	O
sacrifices	O
made	O
by	O
peacekeepers	O
from	O
Australia	I-LOC
,	O
Bangladesh	I-LOC
,	O
Nepal	I-LOC
and	O
my	O
own	O
country	O
who	O
in	O
recent	O
months	O
laid	O
down	O
their	O
lives	O
to	O
help	O
achieve	O
this	O
.	O

But	O
the	O
militias	O
continue	O
to	O
hold	O
sway	O
in	O
the	O
border	O
areas	O
among	O
the	O
refugees	O
in	O
West	O
Timor	O
.	O

Unless	O
brought	O
under	O
control	O
,	O
these	O
militias	O
will	O
destabilize	O
both	O
West	O
and	O
East	O
Timor	O
.	O

New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
was	O
able	O
to	O
respond	O
quickly	O
,	O
along	O
with	O
Australia	I-LOC
,	O
to	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
call	O
for	O
help	O
in	O
evacuating	O
their	O
colleagues	O
and	O
non-governmental	O
organization	O
personnel	O
from	O
Atambua	I-LOC
.	O

We	O
committed	O
helicopters	O
with	O
security	O
and	O
medical	O
elements	O
from	O
our	O
forces	O
serving	O
on	O
the	O
border	O
with	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Transitional	O
Administration	O
in	O
East	O
Timor	O
(UNTAET)	O
.	O

This	O
airborne	O
evacuation	O
,	O
which	O
had	O
the	O
cooperation	O
of	O
Indonesian	O
forces	O
,	O
was	O
successful	O
.	O

But	O
the	O
pain	O
and	O
the	O
outrage	O
we	O
feel	O
at	O
the	O
murder	O
of	O
three	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
humanitarian	O
workers	O
remains	O
undiminished	O
.	O

It	O
also	O
called	O
for	O
those	O
who	O
have	O
carried	O
out	O
attacks	O
on	O
international	O
personnel	O
to	O
be	O
brought	O
to	O
justice	O
.	O

These	O
are	O
binding	O
obligations	O
.	O

The	O
world	O
awaits	O
action	O
to	O
implement	O
them	O
without	O
further	O
delay	O
.	O

Besides	O
East	O
Timor	O
,	O
New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
is	O
at	O
present	O
contributing	O
to	O
12	O
other	O
peacekeeping	O
operations	O
,	O
including	O
in	O
Kosovo	I-LOC
,	O
on	O
the	O
borders	O
of	O
Syria	I-LOC
,	O
Israel	I-LOC
and	O
Lebanon	I-LOC
,	O
in	O
the	O
Prevlaka	O
peninsula	O
and	O
in	O
Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
.	O

Being	O
conscious	O
of	O
the	O
many	O
challenges	O
faced	O
by	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
in	O
meeting	O
its	O
peacekeeping	O
responsibilities	O
,	O
we	O
greatly	O
welcome	O
the	O
Brahimi	O
report	O
.	O

We	O
trust	O
that	O
the	O
report	O
's	O
important	O
recommendations	O
will	O
receive	O
serious	O
and	O
expeditious	O
consideration	O
during	O
this	O
Millennium	O
Assembly	I-ORG
session	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
view	O
to	O
their	O
early	O
implementation	O
.	O

As	O
the	O
Brahimi	O
report	O
points	O
out	O
,	O
weak	O
mandates	O
and	O
poor	O
resourcing	O
underlie	O
most	O
of	O
those	O
operations	O
which	O
did	O
not	O
succeed	O
in	O
their	O
objectives	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
concerned	O
too	O
at	O
the	O
tendency	O
to	O
rely	O
overly	O
on	O

"	O
coalitions	O
of	O
the	O
willing	O
"	O

to	O
carry	O
out	O
operations	O
that	O
should	O
be	O
undertaken	O
by	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

The	O
failure	O
of	O
some	O
Member	O
States	I-LOC
to	O
pay	O
their	O
assessed	O
contributions	O
on	O
time	O
,	O
in	O
full	O
and	O
without	O
conditions	O
imposes	O
an	O
impossible	O
burden	O
on	O
the	O
Organization	O
and	O
on	O
troop	O
contributors	O
.	O

We	O
agree	O
that	O
the	O
scale	O
of	O
assessments	O
for	O
peacekeeping	O
needs	O
revision	O
to	O
make	O
it	O
more	O
equitable	O
and	O
transparent	O
.	O

Any	O
revision	O
must	O
be	O
established	O
in	O
accordance	O
with	O
the	O
longstanding	O
principle	O
of	O
apportioning	O
expenses	O
according	O
to	O
Member	O
States'	O
capacity	O
to	O
pay	O
.	O

Heads	O
of	O
State	O
or	O
Government	O
agreed	O
at	O
the	O
Millennium	O
Summit	I-LOC
to	O
intensify	O
their	O
efforts	O
to	O
achieve	O
a	O
comprehensive	O
reform	O
of	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
in	O
all	O
its	O
aspects	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
past	O
seven	O
years	O
of	O
debate	O
on	O
this	O
matter	O
,	O
it	O
has	O
been	O
shown	O
just	O
how	O
difficult	O
an	O
issue	O
it	O
is	O
,	O
especially	O
in	O
regard	O
to	O
how	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
might	O
be	O
enlarged	O
.	O

There	O
is	O
no	O
agreement	O
on	O
this	O
aspect	O
at	O
this	O
time	O
.	O

And	O
yet	O
I	O
am	O
sure	O
that	O
most	O
Member	O
States	I-LOC
would	O
agree	O
that	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
must	O
be	O
made	O
more	O
representative	O
of	O
today	O
's	O
membership	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
more	O
transparent	O
in	O
its	O
working	O
methods	O
and	O
more	O
democratic	O
in	O
its	O
decision-making	O
.	O

If	O
there	O
is	O
to	O
be	O
progress	O
towards	O
an	O
overall	O
package	O
deal	O
on	O
reform	O
,	O
then	O
compromises	O
will	O
have	O
to	O
be	O
made	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
heart	O
of	O
any	O
reform	O
,	O
in	O
New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
's	O
view	O
,	O
must	O
be	O
the	O
curtailment	O
of	O
the	O
veto	O
,	O
if	O
indeed	O
it	O
cannot	O
be	O
eliminated	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
argued	O
this	O
case	O
since	O
1945	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
believe	O
that	O
it	O
is	O
even	O
more	O
relevant	O
today	O
.	O

A	O
device	O
which	O
50	O
years	O
ago	O
might	O
have	O
had	O
the	O
utility	O
of	O
preventing	O
the	O
permanent	O
members	O
from	O
using	O
the	O
Organization	O
to	O
make	O
war	O
on	O
one	O
another	O
has	O
in	O
recent	O
times	O
served	O
to	O
frustrate	O
the	O
will	O
of	O
the	O
wider	O
membership	O
.	O

I	O
believe	O
there	O
is	O
very	O
broad	O
agreement	O
in	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
on	O
the	O
need	O
to	O
deal	O
with	O
the	O
veto	O
urgently	O
,	O
so	O
that	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
can	O
be	O
more	O
effective	O
in	O
carrying	O
out	O
its	O
important	O
responsibilities	O
.	O

I	O
would	O
not	O
want	O
to	O
suggest	O
that	O
there	O
has	O
been	O
no	O
progress	O
at	O
all	O
on	O
Council	I-ORG
reform	O
.	O

There	O
have	O
,	O
in	O
fact	O
,	O
been	O
some	O
major	O
steps	O
forward	O
in	O
opening	O
up	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
's	O
meetings	O
and	O
briefings	O
to	O
participation	O
by	O
non-	O
members	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
grateful	O
for	O
that	O
.	O

I	O
would	O
also	O
like	O
to	O
reaffirm	O
New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
's	O
strong	O
support	O
for	O
the	O
Open-ended	O
Working	O
Group	O
on	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
reform	O
,	O
whose	O
deliberations	O
have	O
contributed	O
to	O
this	O
progress	O
.	O

In	O
our	O
view	O
,	O
the	O
Working	O
Group	O
continues	O
to	O
be	O
the	O
appropriate	O
forum	O
in	O
which	O
to	O
pursue	O
efforts	O
aimed	O
at	O
reforming	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
,	O
because	O
it	O
is	O
essential	O
for	O
the	O
health	O
of	O
the	O
Organization	O
that	O
any	O
reform	O
package	O
enjoy	O
the	O
widest	O
support	O
and	O
buy-in	O
.	O

Council	I-ORG
reform	O
is	O
too	O
important	O
a	O
matter	O
for	O
back-room	O
deals	O
.	O

The	O
Millennium	O
Declaration	I-MISC
contains	O
some	O
important	O
guidance	O
on	O
human	O
rights	O
,	O
democracy	O
and	O
good	O
governance	O
.	O

For	O
example	O
,	O
all	O
countries	O
are	O
enjoined	O
to	O
strengthen	O
their	O
capacity	O
to	O
implement	O
the	O
principles	O
and	O
practices	O
of	O
democracy	O
and	O
respect	O
for	O
human	O
rights	O
,	O
including	O
minority	O
rights	O
.	O

This	O
could	O
not	O
be	O
more	O
timely	O
for	O
my	O
own	O
region	O
,	O
the	O
South	O
Pacific	O
,	O
where	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
year	O
we	O
have	O
seen	O
the	O
collapse	O
of	O
democracy	O
and	O
governance	O
in	O
some	O
countries	O
in	O
the	O
face	O
of	O
disputes	O
over	O
land	O
and	O
economic	O
disparities	O
and	O
as	O
a	O
result	O
of	O
ethnic	O
tensions	O
.	O

There	O
are	O
no	O
easy	O
solutions	O
to	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
problems	O
the	O
region	O
faces	O
,	O
but	O
one	O
thing	O
is	O
clear	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
is	O
that	O
the	O
answer	O
to	O
these	O
problems	O
is	O
not	O
to	O
adopt	O
political	O
systems	O
that	O
discriminate	O
against	O
particular	O
ethnic	O
groups	O
,	O
as	O
some	O
in	O
Fiji	I-LOC
this	O
year	O
have	O
sought	O
to	O
do	O
.	O

To	O
do	O
so	O
simply	O
breeds	O
a	O
deeper	O
sense	O
of	O
frustration	O
and	O
exclusion	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
a	O
recipe	O
for	O
further	O
instability	O
.	O

Small	O
States	I-LOC
,	O
especially	O
small	O
developing	O
countries	O
like	O
our	O
neighbours	O
in	O
the	O
Pacific	O
,	O
face	O
particular	O
challenges	O
from	O
globalization	O
.	O

They	O
are	O
uniquely	O
vulnerable	O
to	O
external	O
impacts	O
.	O

We	O
need	O
to	O
find	O
fresh	O
and	O
more	O
effective	O
means	O
to	O
development	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
essential	O
to	O
help	O
countries	O
build	O
for	O
themselves	O
inclusive	O
and	O
democratic	O
forms	O
of	O
government	O
that	O
in	O
turn	O
take	O
account	O
of	O
cultural	O
values	O
.	O

Underpinning	O
this	O
must	O
be	O
robust	O
and	O
accountable	O
institutions	O
,	O
respect	O
for	O
the	O
rule	O
of	O
law	O
,	O
independence	O
of	O
the	O
judiciary	O
,	O
an	O
effective	O
press	O
,	O
strong	O
civil	O
society	O
and	O
,	O
above	O
all	O
,	O
greater	O
public	O
education	O
to	O
foster	O
a	O
more	O
widespread	O
understanding	O
of	O
democratic	O
values	O
and	O
processes	O
.	O

The	O
Millennium	O
Summit	I-LOC
provided	O
heads	O
of	O
State	O
or	O
Government	O
the	O
opportunity	O
to	O
take	O
action	O
on	O
a	O
range	O
of	O
treaties	O
which	O
are	O
fundamental	O
to	O
the	O
development	O
of	O
international	O
human	O
rights	O
law	O
and	O
international	O
humanitarian	O
law	O
.	O

The	O
practices	O
of	O
child	O
prostitution	O
,	O
child	O
pornography	O
and	O
the	O
appalling	O
exploitation	O
of	O
children	O
to	O
fight	O
wars	O
are	O
a	O
disgrace	O
and	O
a	O
crime	O
against	O
humanity	O
which	O
must	O
be	O
expunged	O
.	O

We	O
encourage	O
others	O
also	O
to	O
sign	O
and	O
ratify	O
these	O
agreements	O
.	O

I	O
should	O
also	O
add	O
that	O
we	O
greatly	O
welcome	O
the	O
recent	O
decision	O
by	O
the	O
Economic	O
and	O
Social	O
Council	I-ORG
to	O
establish	O
a	O
Permanent	O
Forum	O
on	O
Indigenous	O
Issues	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
Millennium	O
Summit	I-LOC
,	O
world	O
leaders	O
agreed	O
to	O
strive	O
for	O
the	O
elimination	O
of	O
weapons	O
of	O
mass	O
destruction	O
,	O
particularly	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
a	O
matter	O
of	O
real	O
urgency	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
promote	O
the	O
implementation	O
of	O
the	O
new	O
commitments	O
.	O

New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
,	O
with	O
its	O
new	O
agenda	O
partners	O
,	O
will	O
submit	O
a	O
draft	O
resolution	O
during	O
this	O
session	O
of	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
.	O

New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
will	O
also	O
,	O
in	O
partnership	O
with	O
Brazil	I-LOC
,	O
promote	O
a	O
southern	O
hemisphere	O
free	O
of	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
.	O

In	O
addition	O
,	O
we	O
will	O
,	O
along	O
with	O
Australia	I-LOC
,	O
Mexico	I-LOC
and	O
Japan	I-LOC
,	O
urge	O
all	O
countries	O
that	O
have	O
yet	O
to	O
do	O
so	O
to	O
sign	O
and	O
ratify	O
the	O
Comprehensive	O
Nuclear-Test-Ban	O
Treaty	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
also	O
support	O
further	O
preparations	O
for	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Conference	O
on	O
the	O
Illicit	O
Trade	O
in	O
Small	O
Arms	O
and	O
Light	O
Weapons	O
in	O
All	O
Its	O
Aspects	O
and	O
join	O
calls	O
for	O
adherence	O
to	O
the	O
Ottawa	I-LOC
Convention	O
on	O
the	O
Prohibition	O
of	O
the	O
Use	O
,	O
Stockpiling	O
,	O
Production	O
and	O
Transfer	O
of	O
Anti-personnel	O
Mines	O
and	O
on	O
Their	O
Destruction	O
.	O

New	I-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
urges	O
caution	O
regarding	O
decisions	O
on	O
missile	O
developments	O
that	O
could	O
impact	O
negatively	O
on	O
nuclear	O
disarmament	O
,	O
lead	O
to	O
a	O
new	O
nuclear	O
arms	O
race	O
or	O
be	O
inconsistent	O
with	O
the	O
commitment	O
to	O
the	O
total	O
elimination	O
of	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
no	O
time	O
for	O
complacency	O
.	O

The	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
disarmament	O
and	O
arms-control	O
machinery	O
must	O
engage	O
again	O
in	O
negotiations	O
and	O
other	O
work	O
on	O
the	O
new	O
programme	O
of	O
action	O
agreed	O
at	O
the	O
NPT	O
Conference	O
.	O

Leaders	O
also	O
declared	O
their	O
resolve	O
to	O
minimize	O
the	O
adverse	O
effects	O
of	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
economic	O
sanctions	O
on	O
innocent	O
populations	O
.	O

Sanctions	O
are	O
an	O
important	O
tool	O
at	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
's	O
disposal	O
to	O
encourage	O
compliance	O
with	O
its	O
resolutions	O
,	O
but	O
they	O
must	O
be	O
appropriately	O
targeted	O
for	O
maximum	O
effect	O
.	O

They	O
should	O
not	O
impose	O
blanket	O
measures	O
which	O
harm	O
innocent	O
populations	O
and	O
even	O
strengthen	O
the	O
grip	O
of	O
despotic	O
regimes	O
.	O

We	O
support	O
efforts	O
within	O
the	O
Organization	O
to	O
develop	O
proposals	O
for	O
smarter	O
,	O
more	O
effective	O
sanctions	O
which	O
apply	O
pressure	O
where	O
it	O
we	O
will	O
have	O
maximum	O
impact	O
.	O

The	O
Millennium	O
Declaration	I-MISC
also	O
speaks	O
of	O
the	O
need	O
to	O
protect	O
our	O
common	O
environment	O
.	O

My	O
Prime	O
Minister	O
announced	O
during	O
the	O
Summit	I-LOC
our	O
intention	O
to	O
become	O
party	O
to	O
the	O
Kyoto	I-LOC
Protocol	O
to	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Framework	O
Convention	O
on	O
Climate	O
Change	O
by	O
mid-2002	O
.	O

I	O
also	O
wish	O
to	O
recall	O
a	O
particular	O
achievement	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
year	O
in	O
the	O
holding	O
of	O
the	O
inaugural	O
session	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Open-ended	O
Informal	O
Consultative	O
Process	O
on	O
Ocean	O
Affairs	O
and	O
the	O
law	O
of	O
the	O
sea	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
a	O
significant	O
step	O
forward	O
in	O
providing	O
an	O
appropriate	O
forum	O
for	O
discussion	O
of	O
cross-cutting	O
oceans	O
issues	O
.	O

The	O
success	O
of	O
this	O
process	O
should	O
be	O
judged	O
by	O
the	O
extent	O
to	O
which	O
there	O
is	O
enhanced	O
global	O
understanding	O
of	O
oceans	O
issues	O
and	O
an	O
increased	O
willingness	O
to	O
cooperate	O
and	O
coordinate	O
cross-sectorally	O
to	O
address	O
them	O
.	O

Finally	O
,	O
the	O
Millennium	O
Declaration	I-MISC
sets	O
some	O
key	O
goals	O
for	O
development	O
and	O
poverty	O
eradication	O
and	O
urges	O
meeting	O
the	O
special	O
needs	O
of	O
Africa	O
.	O

We	O
believe	O
that	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
has	O
a	O
key	O
role	O
to	O
play	O
in	O
the	O
coordination	O
of	O
official	O
development	O
assistance	O
delivery	O
.	O

The	O
preparations	O
for	O
the	O
event	O
on	O
financing	O
for	O
development	O
are	O
an	O
excellent	O
demonstration	O
of	O
leadership	O
by	O
the	O
Organization	O
and	O
a	O
significant	O
step	O
forward	O
in	O
furthering	O
cooperation	O
with	O
the	O
Bretton	O
Woods	O
institutions	O
.	O

The	O
crushing	O
and	O
seemingly	O
never-ending	O
debt	O
burden	O
,	O
especially	O
on	O
the	O
countries	O
of	O
Africa	O
,	O
must	O
be	O
urgently	O
reduced	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
also	O
address	O
more	O
effectively	O
the	O
scourge	O
of	O
HIV/AIDS	O
.	O

Leaders	O
at	O
last	O
week	O
's	O
Summit	I-LOC
provided	O
this	O
Millennium	O
Assembly	I-ORG
with	O
a	O
clear	O
direction	O
and	O
a	O
strong	O
mandate	O
.	O

Our	O
countries	O
have	O
delegated	O
us	O
the	O
responsibility	O
to	O
realize	O
that	O
vision	O
of	O
a	O
better	O
world	O
and	O
we	O
must	O
ensure	O
through	O
our	O
efforts	O
and	O
determination	O
that	O
we	O
do	O
not	O
fail	O
them	O
.	O
