I	O
am	O
confident	O
that	O
with	O
his	O
wide	O
knowledge	O
,	O
experience	O
and	O
diplomatic	O
skills	O
,	O
we	O
will	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
achieve	O
fruitful	O
results	O
in	O
our	O
deliberations	O
in	O
addressing	O
important	O
and	O
critical	O
issues	O
on	O
the	O
international	O
agenda	O
.	O

I	O
would	O
also	O
like	O
to	O
convey	O
our	O
appreciation	O
to	O
Mr.	O
Joseph	I-PER
Deiss	I-PER
for	O
his	O
able	O
leadership	O
and	O
contributions	O
to	O
the	O
sixty-fifth	O
session	O
of	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
.	O

May	O
I	O
also	O
take	O
this	O
opportunity	O
to	O
once	O
again	O
extend	O
our	O
congratulations	O
to	O
the	O
Secretary-General	O
,	O
Mr.	O
Ban	I-PER
Ki-moon	I-PER
,	O
for	O
his	O
reappointment	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
wish	O
to	O
express	O
our	O
sincere	O
appreciation	O
to	O
him	O
for	O
his	O
dedication	O
and	O
untiring	O
efforts	O
for	O
the	O
cause	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

Since	O
I	O
am	O
addressing	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
after	O
the	O
emergence	O
of	O
the	O
constitutional	O
Government	O
and	O
as	O
the	O
Minister	O
for	O
Foreign	O
Affairs	O
of	O
the	O
Republic	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
the	I-LOC
Union	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
Myanmar	I-LOC
,	O
I	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
apprise	O
the	O
Assembly	I-ORG
of	O
recent	O
developments	O
and	O
significant	O
changes	O
taking	O
place	O
in	O
my	O
country	O
.	O

The	O
Republic	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
the	I-LOC
Union	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
Myanmar	I-LOC
has	O
emerged	O
as	O
a	O
new	O
democratic	O
nation	O
in	O
accordance	O
with	O
the	O
Constitution	O
approved	O
by	O
the	O
overwhelming	O
majority	O
of	O
the	O
people	O
.	O

Multiparty	O
democratic	O
general	O
elections	O
were	O
held	O
in	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
in	O
November	O
2010	O
in	O
line	O
with	O
the	O
seven-step	O
roadmap	O
.	O

Thirty-seven	O
political	O
parties	O
,	O
including	O
19	O
parties	O
from	O
different	O
national	O
ethnic	O
groups	O
,	O
contested	O
in	O
the	O
elections	O
.	O

Today	O
,	O
elected	O
representatives	O
are	O
exercising	O
their	O
democratic	O
rights	O
in	O
the	O
legislative	O
bodies	O
.	O

The	O
President	O
,	O
in	O
his	O
inaugural	O
speech	O
to	O
the	O
first	O
regular	O
session	O
of	O
the	O
Pyidaungsu	I-MISC
Hluttaw	I-MISC
on	O
30	O
March	I-LOC
2011	O
,	O
stated	O
that	O
all	O
elected	O
Hluttaw	I-MISC
members	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
President	O
,	O
are	O
duty-bound	O
to	O
honour	O
and	O
safeguard	O
the	O
Constitution	O
of	O
the	O
Republic	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
the	I-LOC
Union	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
Myanmar	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
new	O
Government	O
pledged	O
that	O
all	O
citizens	O
shall	O
enjoy	O
equal	O
rights	O
under	O
the	O
law	O
and	O
is	O
determined	O
to	O
strengthen	O
the	O
judiciary	O
.	O

The	O
Government	O
also	O
assured	O
the	O
nation	O
that	O
it	O
will	O
amend	O
and	O
revoke	O
existing	O
laws	O
and	O
adopt	O
new	O
laws	O
as	O
may	O
be	O
deemed	O
necessary	O
to	O
implement	O
the	O
provisions	O
of	O
the	O
fundamental	O
rights	O
of	O
the	O
citizens	O
.	O

With	O
a	O
view	O
to	O
maintaining	O
and	O
promoting	O
friendly	O
relations	O
with	O
all	O
countries	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
,	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
is	O
reaching	O
out	O
to	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
past	O
five	O
months	O
,	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
has	O
received	O
the	O
visits	O
of	O
State	O
leaders	O
and	O
high-level	O
delegations	O
from	O
our	O
neighbouring	O
countries	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
from	O
other	O
regions	O
and	O
international	O
organizations	O
.	O

In	O
return	O
,	O
President	O
Thein	I-PER
Sein	I-PER
paid	O
official	O
visits	O
to	O
the	O
Republic	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
Indonesia	I-LOC
and	O
the	O
People	I-LOC
's	I-LOC
Republic	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
China	I-LOC
.	O

One	O
of	O
those	O
measures	O
is	O
the	O
stepping	O
up	O
of	O
its	O
efforts	O
to	O
reduce	O
poverty	O
.	O

In	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
,	O
about	O
70	O
per	O
cent	O
of	O
the	O
population	O
resides	O
in	O
rural	O
areas	O
and	O
engages	O
in	O
agricultural	O
and	O
livestock	O
farming	O
.	O

Those	O
policies	O
will	O
lead	O
to	O
sustained	O
,	O
inclusive	O
and	O
equitable	O
economic	O
growth	O
,	O
which	O
will	O
in	O
turn	O
increase	O
employment	O
opportunities	O
,	O
promote	O
agriculture	O
development	O
and	O
reduce	O
poverty	O
.	O

Towards	O
that	O
end	O
,	O
the	O
new	O
Government	O
has	O
adopted	O
the	O
National	I-MISC
Rural	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
and	I-MISC
Poverty	I-MISC
Reduction	I-MISC
Plan	I-MISC
to	O
alleviate	O
poverty	O
and	O
to	O
improve	O
the	O
livelihood	O
of	O
people	O
residing	O
in	O
rural	O
areas	O
.	O

A	O
central	O
committee	O
and	O
various	O
work	O
committees	O
have	O
been	O
formed	O
to	O
supplement	O
the	O
eight	O
tasks	O
laid	O
down	O
under	O
the	O
National	I-MISC
Plan	I-MISC
.	O

Furthermore	O
,	O
the	O
new	O
Government	O
has	O
increased	O
pension	O
allowances	O
for	O
retired	O
service	O
personnel	O
commensurate	O
with	O
the	O
changing	O
economic	O
and	O
social	O
conditions	O
of	O
the	O
country	O
.	O

With	O
a	O
view	O
to	O
encouraging	O
foreign	O
trade	O
,	O
the	O
Government	O
reduced	O
the	O
export	O
tax	O
from	O
8	O
per	O
cent	O
to	O
2	O
per	O
cent	O
and	O
granted	O
export	O
tax	O
exemptions	O
for	O
all	O
agricultural	O
and	O
timber	O
products	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
regrettable	O
that	O
the	O
Government	O
's	O
efforts	O
to	O
improve	O
the	O
livelihood	O
of	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
are	O
being	O
hampered	O
by	O
economic	O
sanctions	O
.	O

I	O
would	O
therefore	O
like	O
to	O
call	O
upon	O
countries	O
that	O
have	O
imposed	O
unilateral	O
sanctions	O
on	O
my	O
country	O
to	O
lift	O
those	O
restrictions	O
.	O

It	O
will	O
also	O
contribute	O
to	O
our	O
efforts	O
to	O
achieve	O
our	O
Millennium	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
Goal	I-MISC
(	O
MDG	I-MISC
)	O
targets	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
attaches	O
great	O
importance	O
to	O
the	O
promotion	O
and	O
protection	O
of	O
human	O
rights	O
.	O

The	O
fundamental	O
rights	O
of	O
the	O
country	O
's	O
citizens	O
are	O
guaranteed	O
by	O
relevant	O
provisions	O
of	O
the	O
State	O
Constitution	O
.	O

With	O
a	O
view	O
to	O
promoting	O
and	O
safeguarding	O
the	O
fundamental	O
rights	O
of	O
its	O
citizens	O
as	O
set	O
forth	O
in	O
the	O
Constitution	O
,	O
the	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
National	I-ORG
Human	I-ORG
Rights	I-ORG
Commission	I-ORG
was	O
formed	O
on	O
5	O
September	O
2011	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
's	O
cooperation	O
with	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
has	O
been	O
clearly	O
demonstrated	O
by	O
the	O
Government	O
's	O
acceptance	O
of	O
the	O
fourth	O
visit	O
of	O
Mr.	O
Tomás	I-PER
Ojea	I-PER
Quintana	I-PER
,	O
the	O
Special	O
Rapporteur	O
on	O
the	O
situation	O
of	O
human	O
rights	O
in	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
in	O
August	O
2011	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Quintana	I-PER
recognized	O
and	O
welcomed	O
the	O
steps	O
taken	O
by	O
the	O
Government	O
to	O
improve	O
the	O
human	O
rights	O
situation	O
in	O
the	O
country	O
.	O

He	O
also	O
welcomed	O
the	O
Government	O
's	O
stated	O
commitments	O
to	O
reform	O
and	O
the	O
priorities	O
set	O
forth	O
by	O
the	O
President	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
has	O
been	O
cooperating	O
closely	O
with	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Human	I-ORG
Rights	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
's	O
Universal	I-MISC
Periodic	I-MISC
Review	I-MISC
(	O
UPR	I-MISC
)	O
report	O
was	O
submitted	O
and	O
reviewed	O
by	O
the	O
UPR	O
Working	O
Group	O
last	O
January	O
and	O
adopted	O
at	O
the	O
seventeenth	O
session	O
of	O
the	O
Human	I-ORG
Rights	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
last	O
June	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
has	O
agreed	O
to	O
accept	O
52	O
.	O
4	O
per	O
cent	O
of	O
the	O
total	O
recommendations	O
.	O

We	O
strongly	O
believe	O
that	O
the	O
UPR	I-ORG
process	O
is	O
the	O
most	O
dependable	O
and	O
non-controversial	O
monitoring	O
mechanism	O
for	O
addressing	O
and	O
rectifying	O
the	O
human	O
rights	O
situations	O
of	O
all	O
countries	O
.	O

As	O
for	O
national	O
reconciliation	O
,	O
the	O
Government	O
offered	O
an	O
olive	O
branch	O
to	O
all	O
the	O
ethnic	O
armed	O
groups	O
in	O
the	O
country	O
through	O
Announcement	O
No	O
.	O
1/2011	O
on	O
18	O
August	O
,	O
and	O
some	O
of	O
those	O
groups	O
have	O
accepted	O
the	O
Government	O
's	O
offer	O
.	O

The	O
Government	O
also	O
granted	O
an	O
amnesty	O
on	O
16	O
May	O
2011	O
,	O
with	O
20	O
,000	O
inmates	O
having	O
been	O
released	O
by	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
July	O
.	O

I	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
take	O
this	O
opportunity	O
to	O
inform	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
that	O
the	O
President	O
,	O
in	O
exercising	O
the	O
mandate	O
vested	O
in	O
him	O
by	O
the	O
Constitution	O
,	O
will	O
grant	O
a	O
further	O
amnesty	O
at	O
an	O
appropriate	O
time	O
in	O
the	O
near	O
future	O
.	O

The	O
President	O
invited	O
people	O
to	O
work	O
together	O
for	O
the	O
interest	O
of	O
the	O
nation	O
despite	O
differences	O
.	O

Accordingly	O
,	O
he	O
received	O
Daw	O
Aung	I-PER
San	I-PER
Suu	I-PER
Kyi	I-PER
on	O
19	O
August	O
2011	O
,	O
and	O
,	O
putting	O
aside	O
differing	O
views	O
,	O
they	O
had	O
candid	O
and	O
cordial	O
discussions	O
with	O
a	O
view	O
to	O
finding	O
common	O
ground	O
and	O
exploring	O
a	O
potential	O
cooperation	O
in	O
the	O
interest	O
of	O
the	O
nation	O
and	O
its	O
people	O
.	O

The	O
foregoing	O
are	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
significant	O
items	O
of	O
progress	O
we	O
have	O
achieved	O
in	O
our	O
democratization	O
process	O
.	O

As	O
an	O
agro-based	O
country	O
,	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
is	O
following	O
with	O
keen	O
interest	O
the	O
issues	O
involving	O
the	O
effects	O
of	O
climate	O
change	O
.	O

Since	O
agriculture	O
is	O
highly	O
dependent	O
on	O
the	O
climate	O
,	O
the	O
implications	O
of	O
the	O
climatic	O
situation	O
on	O
agriculture	O
cannot	O
be	O
ignored	O
.	O

Lately	O
,	O
floods	O
and	O
droughts	O
have	O
devastated	O
crops	O
and	O
agricultural	O
production	O
in	O
our	O
region	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
evident	O
that	O
developing	O
countries	O
are	O
the	O
most	O
vulnerable	O
and	O
will	O
therefore	O
be	O
the	O
first	O
to	O
suffer	O
from	O
global	O
warming	O
and	O
climate	O
change	O
.	O

Although	O
the	O
road	O
to	O
Durban	I-LOC
will	O
be	O
a	O
difficult	O
one	O
,	O
my	O
delegation	O
shares	O
the	O
view	O
that	O
our	O
discussions	O
on	O
the	O
issue	O
should	O
be	O
placed	O
within	O
the	O
context	O
of	O
promoting	O
sustainable	O
development	O
.	O

In	O
that	O
regard	O
,	O
we	O
would	O
also	O
like	O
to	O
stress	O
that	O
all	O
three	O
pillars	O
,	O
namely	O
,	O
economic	O
development	O
,	O
social	O
development	O
and	O
environmental	O
protection	O
,	O
need	O
to	O
be	O
promoted	O
in	O
an	O
integrated	O
,	O
coordinated	O
and	O
balanced	O
manner	O
.	O

In	O
today	O
's	O
world	O
,	O
terrorism	O
and	O
transnational	O
organized	O
crime	O
are	O
increasingly	O
threatening	O
human	O
society	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
is	O
also	O
among	O
those	O
countries	O
that	O
have	O
been	O
victim	O
of	O
the	O
scourge	O
of	O
terrorism	O
.	O

In	O
that	O
regard	O
,	O
we	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
express	O
our	O
deepest	O
condolences	O
to	O
the	O
bereaved	O
families	O
of	O
victims	O
of	O
terrorism	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

We	O
welcome	O
the	O
Secretary-	O
General	O
's	O
commitment	O
to	O
conducting	O
a	O
global	O
threat	O
review	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
re-	O
assess	O
security	O
threats	O
in	O
the	O
wake	O
of	O
the	O
deadly	O
attack	O
in	O
Abuja	I-LOC
,	O
Nigeria	I-LOC
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
stands	O
ready	O
to	O
cooperate	O
at	O
the	O
regional	O
and	O
international	O
levels	O
to	O
prevent	O
and	O
combat	O
terrorism	O
and	O
transnational	O
organized	O
crimes	O
.	O

Without	O
a	O
stable	O
and	O
peaceful	O
environment	O
,	O
sustainable	O
development	O
would	O
not	O
be	O
possible	O
for	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
a	O
country	O
or	O
in	O
a	O
region	O
and	O
beyond	O
.	O

The	O
Millennium	I-MISC
Declaration	I-MISC
set	O
2015	O
as	O
the	O
target	O
date	O
for	O
achieving	O
the	O
Millennium	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
Goals	I-MISC
,	O
which	O
were	O
formulated	O
to	O
address	O
the	O
welfare	O
and	O
needs	O
of	O
people	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

Despite	O
some	O
progress	O
,	O
development	O
efforts	O
have	O
been	O
hindered	O
by	O
various	O
factors	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
slow	O
economic	O
growth	O
,	O
diminishing	O
resources	O
,	O
increasing	O
food	O
prices	O
and	O
ongoing	O
concern	O
over	O
food	O
security	O
,	O
increasingly	O
frequent	O
natural	O
disasters	O
and	O
the	O
challenges	O
posed	O
by	O
climate	O
change	O
.	O

Each	O
country	O
has	O
the	O
primary	O
responsibility	O
to	O
generate	O
its	O
ways	O
and	O
means	O
for	O
achieving	O
social	O
and	O
economic	O
development	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
national	O
efforts	O
to	O
that	O
end	O
need	O
to	O
be	O
supported	O
by	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
.	O

For	O
our	O
part	O
,	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
is	O
determined	O
to	O
promote	O
better	O
living	O
standards	O
and	O
the	O
equitable	O
development	O
of	O
its	O
people	O
.	O

According	O
to	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Development	I-MISC
Programme	I-MISC
,	O
the	O
poverty	O
rate	O
in	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
has	O
decreased	O
from	O
32	O
per	O
cent	O
to	O
26	O
per	O
cent	O
in	O
recent	O
years	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
we	O
have	O
to	O
redouble	O
our	O
efforts	O
to	O
achieve	O
MDG	O
1	O
by	O
the	O
year	O
2015	O
.	O

As	O
a	O
signatory	O
to	O
the	O
Treaty	O
,	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
remains	O
committed	O
to	O
the	O
three	O
pillars	O
of	O
the	O
treaty	O
.	O

As	O
a	O
strong	O
advocate	O
of	O
nuclear	O
disarmament	O
,	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
has	O
been	O
tabling	O
a	O
draft	O
resolution	O
on	O
nuclear	O
disarmament	O
every	O
year	O
since	O
1995	O
,	O
one	O
which	O
enjoys	O
wide	O
support	O
from	O
Member	O
States	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
firmly	O
opposes	O
the	O
proliferation	O
and	O
production	O
of	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
and	O
strongly	O
supports	O
any	O
efforts	O
leading	O
to	O
the	O
realization	O
of	O
a	O
world	O
free	O
of	O
the	O
threat	O
of	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
and	O
their	O
by-	O
products	O
.	O

Recently	O
,	O
the	O
world	O
around	O
us	O
has	O
changed	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
seen	O
changes	O
in	O
Governments	O
and	O
political	O
landscapes	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
has	O
transformed	O
and	O
is	O
moving	O
towards	O
becoming	O
a	O
democratic	O
nation	O
in	O
a	O
smooth	O
and	O
peaceful	O
manner	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
now	O
embarked	O
on	O
a	O
series	O
of	O
reforms	O
in	O
various	O
sectors	O
to	O
bring	O
about	O
democratization	O
and	O
economic	O
development	O
and	O
improve	O
the	O
lives	O
of	O
our	O
people	O
.	O

The	O
steps	O
taken	O
by	O
the	O
Government	O
of	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
are	O
concrete	O
,	O
visible	O
and	O
irreversible	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
ensure	O
that	O
the	O
reform	O
process	O
is	O
incremental	O
,	O
systematic	O
and	O
dynamic	O
.	O

Myanmar	I-LOC
is	O
strongly	O
determined	O
to	O
continue	O
implementing	O
the	O
democratization	O
process	O
despite	O
all	O
of	O
the	O
current	O
challenges	O
.	O

At	O
this	O
critical	O
juncture	O
,	O
the	O
encouragement	O
,	O
understanding	O
and	O
support	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
are	O
crucial	O
to	O
Myanmar	I-LOC
's	O
transition	O
to	O
democracy	O
.	O
