I	O
am	O
indeed	O
very	O
happy	O
to	O
see	O
a	O
sister	O
from	O
fraternal	O
Bahrain	I-LOC
presiding	O
over	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
at	O
this	O
important	O
session	O
.	O

Your	O
election	O
,	O
Madam	O
,	O
symbolizes	O
the	O
increasingly	O
significant	O
role	O
that	O
women	O
are	O
playing	O
in	O
the	O
Muslim	O
world	O
.	O

You	O
will	O
have	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
's	O
full	O
support	O
in	O
carrying	O
out	O
your	O
challenging	O
responsibilities	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
that	O
I	O
have	O
addressed	O
this	O
body	O
since	O
the	O
devastating	O
earthquake	O
that	O
occurred	O
in	O
the	O
northern	O
regions	O
of	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
last	O
October	O
.	O

I	O
therefore	O
take	O
this	O
opportunity	O
to	O
express	O
our	O
deepest	O
gratitude	O
for	O
the	O
relief	O
and	O
financial	O
assistance	O
that	O
we	O
received	O
from	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

We	O
were	O
deeply	O
moved	O
by	O
the	O
global	O
solidarity	O
displayed	O
in	O
the	O
hour	O
of	O
our	O
distress	O
and	O
need	O
.	O

Multilateral	O
cooperation	O
is	O
the	O
key	O
to	O
addressing	O
the	O
existing	O
and	O
emerging	O
challenges	O
of	O
the	O
twenty-first	O
century:	O
political	O
disputes	O
,	O
terrorism	O
,	O
proliferation	O
,	O
poverty	O
,	O
hunger	O
,	O
disease	O
,	O
economic	O
disparities	O
,	O
migration	O
,	O
unemployment	O
,	O
environmental	O
degradation	O
and	O
natural	O
disasters	O
.	O

We	O
appreciate	O
the	O
Secretary-General	O
's	O
initiatives	O
to	O
equip	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
to	O
respond	O
to	O
those	O
challenges	O
.	O

But	O
we	O
are	O
yet	O
a	O
distance	O
from	O
the	O
vision	O
endorsed	O
at	O
the	O
2005	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Summit	I-LOC
.	O

Over	O
the	O
past	O
six	O
years	O
,	O
despite	O
daunting	O
external	O
and	O
internal	O
challenges	O
,	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
has	O
been	O
transformed	O
into	O
a	O
dynamic	O
nation	O
,	O
moving	O
rapidly	O
towards	O
the	O
vision	O
of	O
our	O
founder	O
,	O
namely	O
,	O
a	O
modern	O
,	O
progressive	O
,	O
Islamic	O
and	O
democratic	O
republic	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
reformed	O
our	O
institutions	O
of	O
governance	O
and	O
our	O
economy	O
.	O

Democratic	O
governance	O
has	O
been	O
introduced	O
at	O
the	O
grass-roots	O
level	O
.	O

Women	O
are	O
being	O
politically	O
and	O
economically	O
empowered	O
and	O
protected	O
against	O
discrimination	O
.	O

Minorities	O
have	O
been	O
politically	O
mainstreamed	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
also	O
unshackled	O
the	O
media	O
.	O

Having	O
successfully	O
put	O
our	O
economy	O
on	O
an	O
upsurge	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
now	O
embarked	O
on	O
second-generation	O
reforms	O
to	O
spread	O
the	O
benefits	O
of	O
growth	O
to	O
all	O
our	O
people	O
.	O

One	O
of	O
our	O
strategic	O
aims	O
is	O
to	O
utilize	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
's	O
unique	O
geostrategic	O
position	O
to	O
build	O
trade	O
,	O
energy	O
and	O
communication	O
corridors	O
linking	O
South	O
Asia	I-LOC
,	O
West	O
Asia	I-LOC
,	O
Central	I-LOC
Asia	I-LOC
and	O
China	I-LOC
.	O

Regional	O
integration	O
will	O
accelerate	O
economic	O
growth	O
and	O
prosperity	O
in	O
our	O
part	O
of	O
Asia	I-LOC
and	O
even	O
beyond	O
.	O

Of	I-LOC
course	O
,	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
still	O
faces	O
daunting	O
challenges	O
from	O
within	O
and	O
without	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
facing	O
them	O
boldly	O
to	O
build	O
an	O
environment	O
of	O
peace	O
and	O
stability	O
in	O
our	O
region	O
.	O

Pakistan	I-LOC
desires	O
a	O
peaceful	O
environment	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
been	O
engaged	O
in	O
a	O
peace	O
process	O
with	O
India	I-LOC
aimed	O
at	O
building	O
confidence	O
and	O
resolving	O
issues	O
—	O
including	O
the	O
Jammu	I-LOC
and	O
Kashmir	O
dispute	O
—	O
that	O
have	O
been	O
the	O
source	O
of	O
tension	O
and	O
conflict	O
between	O
the	O
two	O
countries	O
in	O
the	O
past	O
.	O

The	O
improved	O
relations	O
and	O
the	O
conducive	O
international	O
environment	O
have	O
brought	O
an	O
acceptable	O
solution	O
to	O
this	O
long-standing	O
dispute	O
within	O
reach	O
.	O

I	O
am	O
confident	O
that	O
my	O
positive	O
meeting	O
with	O
Prime	O
Minister	O
Manmohan	O
Singh	O
in	O
Havana	I-LOC
will	O
help	O
to	O
carry	O
the	O
peace	O
process	O
forward	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
vital	O
for	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
both	O
countries	O
and	O
for	O
peace	O
in	O
South	O
Asia	I-LOC
and	O
beyond	O
.	O

A	O
stable	O
security	O
environment	O
is	O
also	O
important	O
for	O
peace	O
in	O
our	O
region	O
.	O

Pakistan	I-LOC
has	O
proposed	O
the	O
creation	O
of	O
a	O
strategic	O
restraint	O
regime	O
in	O
South	O
Asia	I-LOC
,	O
encompassing	O
minimum	O
nuclear	O
deterrence	O
and	O
a	O
balance	O
of	O
conventional	O
forces	O
.	O

We	O
do	O
not	O
want	O
to	O
enter	O
into	O
an	O
arms	O
race	O
.	O

But	O
we	O
will	O
do	O
whatever	O
is	O
necessary	O
to	O
preserve	O
the	O
credibility	O
of	O
our	O
minimum	O
defensive	O
deterrence	O
level	O
.	O

Pakistan	I-LOC
has	O
a	O
legitimate	O
requirement	O
for	O
nuclear	O
power	O
generation	O
to	O
meet	O
the	O
energy	O
needs	O
of	O
our	O
expanding	O
economy	O
and	O
our	O
expanding	O
industry	O
.	O

As	O
a	O
responsible	O
nuclear	O
State	O
,	O
we	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
seek	O
nuclear	O
technology	O
for	O
power	O
generation	O
under	O
International	O
Atomic	O
Energy	O
Agency	O
safeguards	O
.	O

We	O
cannot	O
accept	O
discrimination	O
in	O
the	O
nuclear	O
field	O
.	O

Peace	O
and	O
stability	O
in	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
is	O
in	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
's	O
vital	O
interest	O
.	O

It	O
will	O
assure	O
tranquillity	O
on	O
our	O
western	O
frontiers	O
.	O

It	O
will	O
also	O
enable	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
to	O
realize	O
its	O
ambition	O
of	O
linking	O
Central	I-LOC
Asia	I-LOC
and	O
South	O
Asia	I-LOC
through	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
and	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
.	O

Afghanistan	I-LOC
confronts	O
complex	O
security	O
,	O
political	O
and	O
economic	O
challenges	O
,	O
including	O
a	O
resurgent	O
Taliban	O
that	O
also	O
threatens	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
's	O
efforts	O
to	O
combat	O
extremism	O
and	O
terrorism	O
.	O

The	O
common	O
challenge	O
imposes	O
a	O
joint	O
responsibility	O
on	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
,	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
and	O
the	O
coalition	O
forces	O
.	O

Problems	O
in	O
the	O
border	O
regions	O
of	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
and	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
are	O
compounded	O
by	O
the	O
continuing	O
presence	O
in	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
of	O
over	O
3	O
million	O
Afghan	O
refugees	O
,	O
some	O
of	O
them	O
sympathetic	O
to	O
the	O
Taliban	O
.	O

The	O
incentives	O
offered	O
by	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
to	O
the	O
refugees	O
for	O
their	O
voluntary	O
return	O
are	O
minimal	O
.	O

A	O
serious	O
international	O
commitment	O
is	O
required	O
to	O
facilitate	O
their	O
repatriation	O
to	O
their	O
country	O
.	O

The	O
unfortunate	O
history	O
of	O
our	O
region	O
has	O
placed	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
in	O
the	O
frontline	O
of	O
the	O
global	O
campaign	O
against	O
terrorism	O
.	O

Our	O
cooperation	O
has	O
pre-empted	O
several	O
terrorist	O
plots	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
the	O
one	O
uncovered	O
recently	O
to	O
blow	O
up	O
airliners	O
flying	O
from	O
London	I-LOC
.	O

Over	O
the	O
past	O
five	O
years	O
,	O
Al-Qaida	O
has	O
been	O
significantly	O
degraded	O
as	O
an	O
organization	O
in	O
our	O
region	O
.	O

While	O
we	O
confront	O
terrorism	O
our	O
strategy	O
must	O
seek	O
to	O
eliminate	O
this	O
phenomenon	O
comprehensively	O
.	O

We	O
cannot	O
do	O
so	O
unless	O
we	O
understand	O
and	O
address	O
the	O
root	O
causes	O
of	O
terrorism	O
today	O
.	O

How	O
are	O
terrorists	O
able	O
to	O
find	O
willing	O
recruits	O
,	O
even	O
among	O
educated	O
young	O
people	O
,	O
in	O
advanced	O
and	O
democratic	O
societies	O
?	O

The	O
reasons	O
are	O
clear	O
.	O

Across	O
the	O
Muslim	O
world	O
,	O
old	O
conflicts	O
and	O
new	O
campaigns	O
of	O
military	O
intervention	O
have	O
spawned	O
a	O
deep	O
sense	O
of	O
desperation	O
and	O
injustice	O
.	O

Each	O
new	O
battleground	O
involving	O
an	O
Islamic	O
State	O
has	O
served	O
as	O
a	O
new	O
breeding	O
ground	O
for	O
extremists	O
and	O
terrorists	O
.	O

Indiscriminate	O
bombings	O
,	O
civilian	O
casualties	O
,	O
torture	O
,	O
human	O
rights	O
abuses	O
,	O
racial	O
slurs	O
and	O
discrimination	O
only	O
add	O
to	O
the	O
challenge	O
of	O
defeating	O
terrorism	O
.	O

In	O
my	O
view	O
,	O
a	O
two-pronged	O
strategy	O
,	O
which	O
I	O
call	O
enlightened	O
moderation	O
,	O
is	O
required	O
to	O
address	O
the	O
situation	O
.	O

That	O
strategy	O
envisages	O
that	O
,	O
apart	O
from	O
combating	O
terrorism	O
frontally	O
,	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
must	O
undertake	O
resolute	O
efforts	O
to	O
resolve	O
the	O
conflicts	O
afflicting	O
the	O
Islamic	O
world	O
.	O

We	O
also	O
need	O
to	O
bridge	O
,	O
through	O
dialogue	O
and	O
understanding	O
,	O
the	O
growing	O
divide	O
between	O
the	O
Islamic	O
and	O
Western	O
worlds	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
most	O
disappointing	O
to	O
see	O
personalities	O
of	O
high	O
standing	O
oblivious	O
to	O
Muslim	O
sensitivities	O
at	O
these	O
critical	O
moments	O
.	O

The	O
greatest	O
challenge	O
to	O
global	O
security	O
,	O
to	O
the	O
campaign	O
against	O
terrorism	O
,	O
to	O
the	O
promotion	O
of	O
harmony	O
among	O
civilizations	O
and	O
to	O
the	O
credibility	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
is	O
the	O
cauldron	O
of	O
conflict	O
that	O
is	O
the	O
Middle	O
East	O
—	O
exemplified	O
by	O
the	O
latest	O
Israeli	O
aggression	O
against	O
Lebanon	I-LOC
.	O

We	O
hope	O
that	O
the	O
resolution	O
painstakingly	O
brokered	O
in	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
will	O
lead	O
to	O
a	O
rapid	O
and	O
complete	O
Israeli	O
withdrawal	O
and	O
the	O
restoration	O
of	O
Lebanon	I-LOC
's	O
sovereignty	O
over	O
its	O
entire	O
territory	O
.	O

The	O
attack	O
on	O
Lebanon	I-LOC
has	O
far-reaching	O
implications	O
for	O
the	O
Middle	O
East	O
.	O

The	O
ability	O
and	O
relevance	O
of	O
moderate	O
forces	O
to	O
bring	O
about	O
a	O
just	O
peace	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
has	O
been	O
put	O
to	O
a	O
very	O
severe	O
test	O
.	O

The	O
world	O
must	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
still	O
support	O
them	O
to	O
address	O
the	O
festering	O
problems	O
of	O
the	O
region	O
comprehensively	O
and	O
fairly	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
time	O
to	O
end	O
Israel	I-LOC
's	O
conflicts	O
with	O
all	O
its	O
neighbours	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
time	O
,	O
first	O
and	O
foremost	O
,	O
to	O
end	O
the	O
tragedy	O
of	O
Palestine	I-LOC
.	O

There	O
is	O
no	O
doubt	O
in	O
our	O
mind	O
—	O
there	O
should	O
be	O
no	O
doubt	O
in	O
anyone	O
's	O
mind	O
—	O
that	O
that	O
lies	O
at	O
the	O
core	O
not	O
only	O
of	O
tackling	O
the	O
problems	O
of	O
Iraq	I-LOC
and	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
,	O
but	O
also	O
of	O
dealing	O
with	O
the	O
menaces	O
of	O
terrorism	O
and	O
extremism	O
at	O
their	O
roots	O
.	O

The	O
confrontation	O
over	O
Iran	I-LOC
's	O
nuclear	O
programme	O
threatens	O
further	O
instability	O
in	O
this	O
already	O
inflamed	O
region	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
encouraged	O
by	O
the	O

"	O
Iran	I-LOC
and	O
5	O
+	O
1	O
"	O

negotiations	O
and	O
believe	O
that	O
this	O
issue	O
can	O
be	O
resolved	O
peacefully	O
in	O
a	O
manner	O
that	O
accommodates	O
the	O
legitimate	O
rights	O
and	O
interests	O
of	O
all	O
parties	O
involved	O
.	O

Resort	O
to	O
coercion	O
and	O
worse	O
,	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
force	O
,	O
could	O
lead	O
to	O
grave	O
consequences	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
and	O
globally	O
.	O

The	O
dynamic	O
economic	O
performance	O
of	O
several	O
developing	O
countries	O
,	O
especially	O
in	O
Asia	I-LOC
,	O
has	O
transformed	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
geo-economic	O
map	O
.	O

Yet	O
,	O
most	O
developing	O
countries	O
find	O
that	O
international	O
trade	O
and	O
financial	O
structures	O
are	O
weighted	O
against	O
them	O
.	O

With	O
the	O
Doha	I-LOC
Round	O
in	O
the	O
doldrums	O
,	O
new	O
modalities	O
must	O
be	O
found	O
so	O
as	O
to	O
utilize	O
the	O
full	O
potential	O
of	O
trade	O
for	O
development	O
.	O

Similarly	O
,	O
the	O
international	O
financial	O
system	O
should	O
ensure	O
a	O
more	O
equitable	O
share	O
of	O
international	O
liquidity	O
and	O
investment	O
for	O
developing	O
countries	O
.	O

Unless	O
the	O
activities	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
accommodate	O
the	O
concerns	O
and	O
priorities	O
of	O
its	O
general	O
membership	O
,	O
the	O
Organization	O
risks	O
losing	O
its	O
global	O
moral	O
authority	O
.	O

The	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
should	O
reassert	O
its	O
Charter	O
responsibilities	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
should	O
be	O
reformed	O
to	O
make	O
the	O
activities	O
of	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
more	O
democratic	O
,	O
transparent	O
,	O
inclusive	O
and	O
accountable	O
to	O
the	O
general	O
membership	O
.	O

The	O
reform	O
of	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
is	O
of	O
vital	O
interest	O
to	O
every	O
Member	O
State	O
and	O
must	O
therefore	O
be	O
adopted	O
by	O
consensus	O
or	O
by	O
the	O
widest	O
possible	O
agreement	O
.	O

This	O
important	O
session	O
of	O
the	O
Assembly	I-ORG
will	O
elect	O
the	O
next	O
Secretary-	O
General	I-ORG
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

Pakistan	I-LOC
hopes	O
that	O
consensus	O
will	O
soon	O
develop	O
in	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
and	O
the	O
Assembly	I-ORG
on	O
a	O
qualified	O
candidate	O
from	O
Asia	I-LOC
.	O

