I	O
would	O
like	O
first	O
to	O
congratulate	O
you	O
,	O
Mr.	O
President	O
,	O
on	O
your	O
election	O
to	O
your	O
prestigious	O
office	O
.	O

Your	O
vast	O
political	O
experience	O
and	O
diplomatic	O
skills	O
will	O
undoubtedly	O
guide	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
towards	O
success	O
in	O
dealing	O
with	O
its	O
important	O
agenda	O
.	O

Her	O
stature	O
and	O
accomplishments	O
symbolize	O
the	O
prominent	O
role	O
that	O
women	O
are	O
playing	O
in	O
the	O
Muslim	I-MISC
world	O
.	O

Let	O
me	O
also	O
express	O
our	O
high	O
appreciation	O
to	O
Mr.	O
Ban	I-PER
Ki-moon	I-PER
for	O
the	O
distinctive	O
and	O
assiduous	O
manner	O
in	O
which	O
,	O
as	O
our	O
new	O
Secretary-General	O
,	O
he	O
has	O
engaged	O
himself	O
to	O
address	O
crises	O
and	O
humanitarian	O
situations	O
.	O

We	O
support	O
the	O
Secretary-General	O
's	O
commitment	O
to	O
improving	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
so	O
that	O
it	O
can	O
respond	O
to	O
contemporary	O
challenges	O
and	O
opportunities	O
.	O

The	O
end	O
of	O
the	O
cold	O
war	O
at	O
the	O
dawn	O
of	O
the	O
twenty-first	O
century	O
gave	O
rise	O
to	O
hopes	O
for	O
a	O
better	O
future	O
.	O

A	O
decade	O
later	O
,	O
the	O
world	O
is	O
in	O
the	O
grip	O
of	O
deepening	O
uncertainty	O
and	O
rising	O
turbulence	O
.	O

There	O
are	O
new	O
threats	O
of	O
terrorism	O
,	O
violence	O
and	O
widening	O
divisions	O
among	O
cultures	O
and	O
societies	O
,	O
driven	O
by	O
suspicion	O
and	O
prejudice	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
heart	O
of	O
that	O
growing	O
malaise	O
is	O
not	O
a	O
clash	O
of	O
values	O
or	O
civilizations	O
;	O
it	O
is	O
the	O
failure	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
to	O
address	O
festering	O
disputes	O
and	O
our	O
collective	O
inability	O
to	O
universalize	O
the	O
opportunities	O
and	O
benefits	O
offered	O
by	O
the	O
phenomenal	O
advances	O
of	O
technology	O
and	O
globalization	O
for	O
the	O
betterment	O
of	O
all	O
peoples	O
.	O

Conflicts	O
continue	O
in	O
Palestine	I-LOC
,	O
Iraq	I-LOC
and	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
.	O

In	O
South	I-LOC
Asia	I-LOC
,	O
the	O
Kashmir	I-LOC
dispute	O
is	O
yet	O
to	O
be	O
resolved	O
.	O

Old	O
disputes	O
are	O
compounded	O
by	O
new	O
confrontations	O
.	O

Also	O
,	O
serious	O
challenges	O
are	O
emerging	O
in	O
the	O
shape	O
of	O
climate	O
change	O
,	O
energy	O
security	O
,	O
and	O
financial	O
and	O
trade	O
imbalances	O
.	O

In	O
this	O
complex	O
world	O
,	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
provides	O
a	O
critical	O
and	O
indispensable	O
role	O
.	O

The	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
is	O
at	O
the	O
apex	O
of	O
expanding	O
international	O
interaction	O
and	O
remains	O
the	O
only	O
acknowledged	O
instrument	O
for	O
regulating	O
global	O
affairs	O
on	O
the	O
basis	O
of	O
agreed	O
principles	O
and	O
norms	O
.	O

Terrorism	O
is	O
a	O
grave	O
and	O
pervasive	O
threat	O
.	O

Terrorism	O
destabilizes	O
societies	O
.	O

It	O
must	O
not	O
be	O
associated	O
with	O
any	O
faith	O
or	O
culture	O
.	O

It	O
must	O
be	O
countered	O
and	O
rejected	O
,	O
addressing	O
both	O
its	O
manifestations	O
and	O
its	O
root	O
causes	O
.	O

Equally	O
disturbing	O
are	O
trends	O
to	O
malign	O
other	O
cultures	O
and	O
faiths	O
and	O
reinforce	O
divisions	O
,	O
especially	O
between	O
the	O
West	O
and	O
the	O
Islamic	I-MISC
world	O
.	O

Tolerating	O
Islamophobia	I-MISC
in	O
the	O
guise	O
of	O
freedom	O
of	O
expression	O
is	O
dangerous	O
.	O

More	O
than	O
ever	O
before	O
,	O
in	O
this	O
globalized	O
world	O
we	O
need	O
understanding	O
,	O
harmony	O
and	O
the	O
building	O
of	O
bridges	O
among	O
all	O
cultures	O
and	O
peoples	O
through	O
such	O
initiatives	O
as	O
the	O
Alliance	I-MISC
of	I-MISC
Civilizations	I-MISC
,	O
interfaith	O
dialogue	O
and	O
enlightened	O
moderation	O
.	O

Conflict	O
and	O
violence	O
in	O
the	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
are	O
fundamentally	O
linked	O
to	O
the	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
issue	O
that	O
has	O
agitated	O
two	O
generations	O
of	O
Palestinians	I-MISC
and	O
Muslims	I-MISC
around	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

Essentially	O
,	O
Palestine	I-LOC
is	O
an	O
issue	O
of	O
freedom	O
.	O

Security	O
cannot	O
be	O
ensured	O
by	O
denying	O
the	O
Palestinians	I-MISC
their	O
freedom	O
.	O

Salvation	O
lies	O
in	O
what	O
the	O
Arab	I-MISC
nations	O
proposed	O
in	O
Beirut	I-LOC
five	O
years	O
ago	O
.	O

Pakistan	I-LOC
supports	O
that	O
position	O
.	O

The	O
world	O
has	O
a	O
historical	O
responsibility	O
to	O
end	O
the	O
tragedy	O
of	O
the	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
people	O
by	O
enabling	O
them	O
to	O
establish	O
their	O
own	O
State	O
in	O
Palestine	I-LOC
,	O
consistent	O
with	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
resolutions	O
242	O
(	O
1967	O
)	O
and	O
338	O
(	0
1973	0
)	O
and	O
the	O
Arab	I-MISC
peace	O
plan	O
.	O

Israel	I-LOC
must	O
also	O
withdraw	O
from	O
the	O
other	O
occupied	O
Arab	I-MISC
territories	O
and	O
fully	O
respect	O
the	O
territorial	O
and	O
sovereign	O
integrity	O
of	O
Lebanon	I-LOC
.	O

Efforts	O
that	O
deflect	O
from	O
those	O
basic	O
imperatives	O
will	O
only	O
prolong	O
agony	O
and	O
turmoil	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
.	O

Pakistan	I-LOC
is	O
deeply	O
concerned	O
over	O
the	O
grave	O
situation	O
in	O
Iraq	I-LOC
.	O

We	O
deplore	O
the	O
internecine	O
bloodshed	O
.	O

Peace	O
in	O
Iraq	I-LOC
can	O
emerge	O
only	O
through	O
dialogue	O
,	O
mutual	O
cooperation	O
and	O
tolerance	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
vital	O
both	O
for	O
the	O
Iraqi	I-MISC
people	O
and	O
for	O
the	O
region	O
to	O
ensure	O
the	O
preservation	O
of	O
the	O
unity	O
and	O
territorial	O
integrity	O
of	O
Iraq	I-LOC
and	O
full	O
respect	O
for	O
its	O
sovereignty	O
.	O

Pakistan	I-LOC
is	O
also	O
disturbed	O
by	O
the	O
ominous	O
confrontation	O
over	O
Iran	I-LOC
's	O
nuclear	O
issue	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
insisted	O
on	O
recourse	O
to	O
diplomacy	O
because	O
resort	O
to	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
force	O
could	O
lead	O
to	O
incalculable	O
consequences	O
for	O
that	O
already	O
inflamed	O
and	O
highly	O
sensitive	O
region	O
.	O

In	O
our	O
region	O
,	O
violence	O
and	O
the	O
rise	O
of	O
terrorism	O
and	O
extremism	O
are	O
due	O
to	O
the	O
developments	O
of	O
the	O
nearly	O
three	O
decades	O
when	O
neighbouring	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
became	O
the	O
last	O
front	O
of	O
the	O
cold	O
war	O
.	O

Ironically	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
1980s	O
the	O
struggle	O
in	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
helped	O
the	O
consolidation	O
of	O
freedom	O
movements	O
that	O
culminated	O
in	O
the	O
surge	O
of	O
freedom	O
signified	O
by	O
the	O
fall	O
of	O
the	O
Berlin	I-LOC
wall	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
1990s	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
suffered	O
international	O
neglect	O
and	O
indifference	O
until	O
the	O
shock	O
and	O
horror	O
of	O
9/11	O
refocused	O
international	O
attention	O
on	O
that	O
war-ravaged	O
country	O
.	O

The	O
unfortunate	O
happenings	O
in	O
our	O
neighbourhood	O
impacted	O
on	O
our	O
own	O
society	O
,	O
giving	O
rise	O
to	O
terrorism	O
and	O
extremism	O
,	O
especially	O
in	O
the	O
tribal	O
regions	O
bordering	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
.	O

We	O
are	O
fighting	O
Al-Qaida	I-ORG
and	O
other	O
terrorist	O
elements	O
with	O
resolve	O
and	O
determination	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
deployed	O
nearly	O
100,000	O
troops	O
for	O
that	O
purpose	O
.	O

A	O
large	O
number	O
of	O
our	O
troops	O
have	O
sacrificed	O
their	O
lives	O
.	O

As	O
part	O
of	O
a	O
comprehensive	O
strategy	O
,	O
we	O
have	O
introduced	O
reforms	O
to	O
counter	O
extremism	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
cooperating	O
internationally	O
and	O
reject	O
irresponsible	O
comments	O
and	O
insinuations	O
,	O
especially	O
in	O
certain	O
sections	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
media	O
,	O
casting	O
aspersions	O
on	O
our	O
intentions	O
and	O
efforts	O
.	O

It	O
must	O
be	O
appreciated	O
that	O
the	O
challenge	O
is	O
enormous	O
and	O
requires	O
a	O
sustained	O
and	O
protracted	O
endeavour	O
both	O
locally	O
and	O
at	O
the	O
international	O
level	O
.	O

Pakistan	I-LOC
desires	O
a	O
peaceful	O
environment	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
.	O

No	O
country	O
stands	O
to	O
gain	O
as	O
much	O
as	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
from	O
peace	O
and	O
stability	O
in	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
recently	O
convened	O
Grand	I-ORG
Jirga	I-ORG
in	O
Kabul	I-LOC
offers	O
hope	O
.	O

A	O
great	O
deal	O
will	O
depend	O
on	O
the	O
effectiveness	O
of	O
the	O
follow-up	O
mechanisms	O
,	O
especially	O
the	O
50-member	O
joint	O
council	O
that	O
is	O
mandated	O
to	O
reach	O
out	O
to	O
the	O
opposition	O
to	O
promote	O
peace	O
in	O
the	O
area	O
.	O

The	O
international	O
community	O
also	O
has	O
an	O
important	O
responsibility	O
to	O
help	O
Afghanistan	I-LOC
with	O
a	O
Marshall	I-MISC
Plan-like	I-MISC
programme	O
for	O
reconstruction	O
.	O

Pakistan	I-LOC
is	O
engaged	O
in	O
a	O
peace	O
process	O
with	O
India	I-LOC
that	O
has	O
led	O
to	O
significant	O
improvement	O
in	O
bilateral	O
relations	O
.	O

The	O
two	O
countries	O
must	O
now	O
seize	O
the	O
opportunity	O
provided	O
by	O
the	O
propitious	O
international	O
and	O
regional	O
environment	O
to	O
address	O
problems	O
,	O
especially	O
the	O
Jammu	I-LOC
and	O
Kashmir	I-LOC
dispute	O
that	O
has	O
been	O
at	O
the	O
heart	O
of	O
conflict	O
and	O
tension	O
in	O
South	I-LOC
Asia	I-LOC
.	O

Both	O
sides	O
will	O
have	O
to	O
demonstrate	O
political	O
will	O
,	O
courage	O
and	O
flexibility	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
pursuing	O
a	O
solution	O
that	O
would	O
be	O
acceptable	O
to	O
India	I-LOC
,	O
to	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
and	O
,	O
above	O
all	O
,	O
to	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
Jammu	I-LOC
and	O
Kashmir	I-LOC
.	O

President	O
Pervez	I-PER
Musharraf	I-PER
has	O
offered	O
important	O
ideas	O
that	O
have	O
resonated	O
with	O
the	O
Kashmiri	I-MISC
people	O
,	O
who	O
must	O
be	O
involved	O
in	O
the	O
process	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
essential	O
to	O
create	O
an	O
environment	O
free	O
of	O
human	O
rights	O
violations	O
in	O
Kashmir	I-LOC
if	O
there	O
is	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
sustainable	O
peaceful	O
solution	O
.	O

A	O
peaceful	O
settlement	O
responding	O
to	O
the	O
aspirations	O
of	O
the	O
Kashmiri	I-MISC
people	O
will	O
usher	O
in	O
a	O
new	O
era	O
of	O
mutual	O
trust	O
and	O
cooperation	O
in	O
South	I-LOC
Asia	I-LOC
.	O

In	O
our	O
region	O
,	O
the	O
incipient	O
United	I-LOC
States	I-LOC
-	0
India	I-LOC
nuclear	O
deal	O
injects	O
a	O
new	O
element	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
concerns	O
over	O
strategic	O
stability	O
,	O
which	O
we	O
will	O
maintain	O
despite	O
our	O
firm	O
opposition	O
to	O
an	O
arms	O
race	O
in	O
South	I-LOC
Asia	I-LOC
.	O

Moreover	O
,	O
we	O
also	O
have	O
a	O
strong	O
interest	O
in	O
developing	O
civil	O
nuclear	O
power	O
generation	O
under	O
international	O
safeguards	O
.	O

Our	O
nuclear	O
and	O
strategic	O
assets	O
are	O
solely	O
for	O
defensive	O
purpose	O
.	O

We	O
started	O
pursuing	O
the	O
nuclear	O
option	O
only	O
after	O
1974	O
,	O
when	O
the	O
strategic	O
balance	O
was	O
disrupted	O
by	O
the	O
first	O
Indian	I-MISC
nuclear	O
test	O
.	O

Our	O
initiatives	O
to	O
keep	O
South	I-LOC
Asia	I-LOC
free	O
of	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
received	O
scant	O
response	O
internationally	O
.	O

In	O
1998	O
,	O
we	O
were	O
again	O
faced	O
with	O
a	O
dilemma	O
and	O
had	O
to	O
respond	O
to	O
the	O
Indian	I-MISC
tests	O
to	O
establish	O
deterrence	O
.	O

Our	O
failure	O
to	O
do	O
so	O
would	O
have	O
created	O
a	O
dangerous	O
ambiguity	O
about	O
our	O
capability	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
risk	O
of	O
miscalculation	O
.	O

I	O
wish	O
to	O
reaffirm	O
that	O
our	O
strategic	O
capability	O
is	O
solely	O
for	O
deterrence	O
and	O
defence	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
opposed	O
to	O
an	O
arms	O
race	O
and	O
want	O
to	O
maintain	O
minimum	O
credible	O
deterrence	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
not	O
be	O
the	O
first	O
to	O
test	O
in	O
our	O
region	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
never	O
use	O
our	O
nuclear	O
capability	O
against	O
non-nuclear	O
weapon	O
States	O
.	O

We	O
remain	O
fully	O
committed	O
to	O
the	O
objective	O
of	O
general	O
and	O
complete	O
disarmament	O
and	O
nuclear	O
non-proliferation	O
.	O

We	O
want	O
to	O
be	O
treated	O
as	O
a	O
partner	O
rather	O
than	O
as	O
a	O
target	O
of	O
the	O
global	O
nuclear	O
non-proliferation	O
regime	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
committed	O
to	O
developing	O
nuclear	O
power	O
generation	O
under	O
international	O
safeguards	O
to	O
meet	O
our	O
growing	O
energy	O
needs	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
evident	O
that	O
global	O
consensus	O
on	O
disarmament	O
and	O
non-	O
proliferation	O
has	O
been	O
seriously	O
eroded	O
.	O

There	O
are	O
several	O
reasons	O
for	O
that	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
disavowal	O
of	O
nuclear	O
disarmament	O
by	O
the	O
nuclear-weapon	O
States	O
signatories	O
to	O
the	O
Treaty	I-MISC
on	I-MISC
the	I-MISC
Non-Proliferation	I-MISC
of	I-MISC
Nuclear	I-MISC
Weapons	I-MISC
(	O
NPT	I-MISC
)	O
;	O
the	O
emergence	O
of	O
de	O
facto	O
nuclear-weapon	O
States	O
not	O
parties	O
to	O
the	O
NPT	I-MISC
;	O
the	O
failure	O
to	O
address	O
the	O
security	O
concerns	O
of	O
non-nuclear-weapon	O
States	O
;	O
and	O
discrimination	O
in	O
the	O
conduct	O
of	O
peaceful	O
nuclear	O
cooperation	O
.	O

There	O
is	O
an	O
obvious	O
need	O
for	O
a	O
new	O
and	O
universal	O
consensus	O
on	O
non-proliferation	O
,	O
disarmament	O
and	O
peaceful	O
nuclear	O
cooperation	O
that	O
eliminates	O
dangers	O
and	O
risks	O
and	O
establishes	O
cooperation	O
on	O
an	O
equitable	O
basis	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
coming	O
months	O
,	O
the	O
Nuclear	I-MISC
Suppliers	I-MISC
Group	I-MISC
States	I-MISC
have	O
a	O
heavy	O
responsibility	O
,	O
as	O
any	O
endorsement	O
of	O
a	O
selective	O
or	O
discriminatory	O
approach	O
could	O
fatefully	O
damage	O
the	O
existing	O
consensus	O
on	O
disarmament	O
and	O
non-proliferation	O
.	O

The	O
world	O
is	O
slowly	O
recognizing	O
the	O
existential	O
threat	O
posed	O
by	O
climate	O
change	O
.	O

The	O
special	O
event	O
held	O
on	O
24	O
September	O
has	O
been	O
useful	O
in	O
crystallizing	O
the	O
issues	O
that	O
must	O
be	O
addressed	O
.	O

Environment	O
is	O
a	O
responsibility	O
and	O
an	O
opportunity	O
.	O

The	O
responsibility	O
is	O
to	O
heal	O
the	O
Earth	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
scarred	O
and	O
degraded	O
.	O

The	O
challenge	O
goes	O
far	O
beyond	O
Kyoto	I-LOC
.	O

Collectively	O
,	O
we	O
need	O
to	O
restrain	O
our	O
avaricious	O
and	O
extravagant	O
living	O
.	O

Opportunity	I-LOC
lies	O
in	O
developing	O
the	O
environment	O
as	O
an	O
employment	O
sector	O
to	O
absorb	O
a	O
part	O
of	O
world	O
human	O
resources	O
in	O
meaningful	O
activity	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
realize	O
that	O
with	O
technological	O
advances	O
it	O
will	O
no	O
longer	O
be	O
feasible	O
to	O
rationally	O
utilize	O
the	O
entire	O
global	O
work	O
force	O
in	O
the	O
production	O
,	O
manufacturing	O
and	O
service	O
sectors	O
.	O

Against	O
the	O
backdrop	O
of	O
the	O
new	O
challenges	O
,	O
large	O
parts	O
of	O
humanity	O
continue	O
to	O
suffer	O
from	O
hunger	O
,	O
poverty	O
and	O
disease	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
tragic	O
in	O
these	O
modern	O
times	O
,	O
where	O
the	O
miracle	O
of	O
technology	O
has	O
empowered	O
the	O
world	O
to	O
effectively	O
overcome	O
the	O
vestiges	O
of	O
our	O
primitive	O
existence	O
.	O

The	O
Group	O
of	O
77	O
has	O
therefore	O
insisted	O
on	O
a	O
broad	O
endeavour	O
for	O
sustainable	O
development	O
based	O
on	O
economic	O
growth	O
,	O
social	O
development	O
and	O
environmental	O
protection	O
.	O

Pakistan	I-LOC
,	O
as	O
the	O
current	O
Chair	O
of	O
the	O
Group	I-MISC
of	I-MISC
77	I-MISC
and	O
China	I-LOC
,	O
has	O
suggested	O
steps	O
to	O
enable	O
developing	O
countries	O
to	O
coordinate	O
and	O
enlarge	O
their	O
national	O
development	O
cooperation	O
effort	O
.	O

In	O
accordance	O
with	O
the	O
mandate	O
adopted	O
at	O
the	O
Second	I-MISC
South	I-MISC
Summit	I-MISC
,	O
we	O
will	O
convene	O
a	O
panel	O
of	O
eminent	O
experts	O
of	O
the	O
South	O
to	O
further	O
develop	O
common	O
positions	O
for	O
developing	O
countries	O
in	O
critical	O
areas	O
like	O
trade	O
finance	O
,	O
technology	O
,	O
energy	O
and	O
climate	O
change	O
.	O

Pakistan	I-LOC
agrees	O
that	O
the	O
management	O
and	O
Secretariat	I-ORG
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
should	O
be	O
reformed	O
and	O
modernized	O
,	O
especially	O
to	O
improve	O
the	O
coherence	O
and	O
effectiveness	O
of	O
the	O
system	O
.	O

Prime	O
Minister	O
Shaukat	I-PER
Aziz	I-PER
is	O
the	O
Co-Chair	O
of	O
the	O
Secretary-General	O
's	O
High-level	O
Panel	O
on	O
System-wide	O
Coherence	O
.	O

The	O
reform	O
process	O
must	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
remain	O
sensitive	O
to	O
the	O
fundamental	O
principle	O
of	O
the	O
sovereign	O
equality	O
of	O
States	O
in	O
the	O
decision-	O
making	O
process	O
.	O

That	O
applies	O
especially	O
to	O
the	O
issue	O
of	O
the	O
expansion	O
of	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
.	O

Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
reform	O
must	O
enlarge	O
the	O
representation	O
of	O
all	O
Member	O
States	O
rather	O
than	O
expand	O
the	O
circle	O
of	O
the	O
privileged	O
.	O

The	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
functions	O
must	O
also	O
be	O
developed	O
in	O
a	O
manner	O
so	O
that	O
these	O
do	O
not	O
eclipse	O
the	O
Charter	I-MISC
responsibilities	O
of	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
or	O
those	O
of	O
the	O
other	O
principal	O
organs	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

In	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
,	O
our	O
aspirations	O
are	O
the	O
same	O
as	O
elsewhere:	O
to	O
accelerate	O
our	O
socio-economic	O
development	O
,	O
to	O
build	O
a	O
knowledge-based	O
society	O
and	O
to	O
contribute	O
to	O
peace	O
and	O
development	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
consistent	O
with	O
the	O
deeply	O
held	O
values	O
of	O
our	O
faith	O
and	O
our	O
vision	O
for	O
a	O
modern	O
progressive	O
Islamic	I-MISC
state	O
.	O

That	O
has	O
been	O
the	O
orientation	O
of	O
the	O
Government	O
of	O
President	O
Musharraf	I-PER
for	O
setting	O
priorities	O
and	O
introducing	O
reform	O
programmes	O
.	O

There	O
have	O
been	O
significant	O
accomplishments	O
in	O
strengthening	O
institutions	O
,	O
promoting	O
democratic	O
polity	O
and	O
building	O
a	O
sound	O
economy	O
.	O

To	O
give	O
a	O
few	O
examples	O
,	O
today	O
we	O
have	O
robust	O
grass-roots	O
level	O
democratic	O
institutions	O
with	O
mandatory	O
one-third	O
representation	O
by	O
women	O
.	O

Our	O
minorities	O
have	O
been	O
integrated	O
into	O
the	O
political	O
mainstream	O
.	O

Our	O
media	O
is	O
free	O
,	O
vibrant	O
and	O
assertive	O
.	O

Our	O
economy	O
has	O
seen	O
stable	O
growth	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
eight	O
years	O
,	O
and	O
in	O
that	O
period	O
,	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
's	O
national	O
output	O
and	O
per	O
capita	O
income	O
has	O
doubled	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
now	O
preparing	O
for	O
elections	O
,	O
as	O
our	O
elected	O
national	O
and	O
provincial	O
assemblies	O
will	O
soon	O
complete	O
their	O
full	O
term	O
of	O
office	O
.	O

As	O
we	O
enter	O
this	O
important	O
phase	O
in	O
our	O
political	O
life	O
,	O
we	O
do	O
so	O
with	O
the	O
deep	O
awareness	O
that	O
a	O
strong	O
and	O
stable	O
Pakistan	I-LOC
is	O
pivotal	O
for	O
the	O
peace	O
and	O
progress	O
of	O
our	O
region	O
.	O
