My	O
delegation	O
extends	O
to	O
you	O
,	O
Sir	O
,	O
its	O
warmest	O
congratulations	O
on	O
your	O
election	O
to	O
the	O
presidency	O
of	O
this	O
body	O
at	O
its	O
fifty-sixth	O
session	O
.	O

Given	O
your	O
impressive	O
credentials	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
confident	O
that	O
under	O
your	O
guidance	O
we	O
will	O
conclude	O
our	O
deliberations	O
successfully	O
.	O

I	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
take	O
this	O
opportunity	O
to	O
express	O
our	O
appreciation	O
to	O
His	O
Excellency	O
Mr.	O
Harri	I-PER
Holkeri	I-PER
of	O
Finland	I-LOC
,	O
who	O
admirably	O
conducted	O
the	O
affairs	O
of	O
the	O
epoch-making	O
Millennium	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
last	O
year	O
.	O

Let	O
me	O
also	O
warmly	O
congratulate	O
our	O
indefatigable	O
Secretary-General	O
,	O
Mr.	O
Kofi	I-PER
Annan	I-PER
,	O
on	O
his	O
reappointment	O
to	O
a	O
second	O
term	O
of	O
office	O
and	O
on	O
his	O
award	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
of	O
the	O
2001	O
Nobel	I-MISC
Prize	I-MISC
for	I-MISC
Peace	I-MISC
.	O

As	O
citizens	O
of	O
the	O
West	I-MISC
African	I-MISC
subregion	O
,	O
we	O
in	O
Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
are	O
proud	O
of	O
his	O
stewardship	O
.	O

Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
is	O
indeed	O
indebted	O
to	O
him	O
,	O
the	O
staff	O
of	O
the	O
Secretariat	I-ORG
and	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
family	O
for	O
their	O
invaluable	O
support	O
of	O
our	O
effort	O
to	O
secure	O
peace	O
and	O
stability	O
in	O
my	O
country	O
.	O

Forty	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
on	O
29	O
September	O
to	O
be	O
exact	O
,	O
Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
was	O
admitted	O
as	O
the	O
one	O
hundredth	O
Member	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

We	O
have	O
faithfully	O
adhered	O
to	O
the	O
purposes	O
and	O
principles	O
of	O
the	O
Charter	I-MISC
.	O

We	O
have	O
practised	O
,	O
and	O
continue	O
to	O
practise	O
,	O
tolerance	O
and	O
good-neighbourliness	O
.	O

Our	O
faith	O
in	O
the	O
Organization	O
remains	O
as	O
strong	O
as	O
it	O
was	O
40	O
years	O
ago	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
,	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
and	O
its	O
agencies	O
have	O
done	O
a	O
lot	O
for	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
.	O

As	O
President	O
Kabbah	I-PER
told	O
the	O
Millennium	I-MISC
Summit	I-MISC
last	O
year	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
course	O
of	O
its	O
membership	O
,	O
Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
has	O
tested	O
the	O
capacity	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
to	O
respond	O
to	O
major	O
challenges	O
,	O
especially	O
in	O
the	O
areas	O
of	O
peacekeeping	O
,	O
through	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Mission	I-MISC
in	I-MISC
Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
(	O
UNAMSIL	I-MISC
)	O
,	O
and	O
of	O
humanitarian	O
law	O
,	O
through	O
the	O
proposed	O
special	O
court	O
to	O
try	O
those	O
who	O
bear	O
the	O
greatest	O
responsibility	O
for	O
serious	O
violations	O
of	O
Sierra	I-MISC
Leonean	I-MISC
law	O
,	O
war	O
crimes	O
and	O
crimes	O
against	O
humanity	O
committed	O
in	O
Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
.	O

In	O
conveying	O
our	O
sincere	O
thanks	O
to	O
the	O
Organization	O
and	O
the	O
rest	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
for	O
their	O
support	O
,	O
my	O
delegation	O
expresses	O
the	O
hope	O
that	O
Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
and	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
will	O
continue	O
to	O
work	O
closely	O
for	O
peace	O
,	O
security	O
and	O
sustainable	O
development	O
in	O
the	O
coming	O
years	O
.	O

Sadly	O
,	O
this	O
session	O
of	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
is	O
taking	O
place	O
in	O
the	O
aftermath	O
of	O
the	O
despicable	O
acts	O
of	O
terrorism	O
inflicted	O
on	O
our	O
host	O
country	O
on	O
11	O
September	O
2001	O
—	O
acts	O
that	O
claimed	O
the	O
lives	O
of	O
thousands	O
of	O
Americans	I-MISC
and	O
of	O
the	O
nationals	O
of	O
86	O
other	O
countries	O
.	O

As	O
we	O
share	O
their	O
grief	O
and	O
renew	O
our	O
heartfelt	O
condolences	O
to	O
the	O
families	O
of	O
the	O
victims	O
and	O
the	O
Government	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
States	I-LOC
,	O
we	O
Sierra	I-MISC
Leoneans	I-MISC
are	O
reminded	O
of	O
that	O
ominous	O
day	O
in	O
January	O
1999	O
when	O
over	O
5,000	O
innocent	O
civilians	O
were	O
brutally	O
killed	O
during	O
the	O
rebel	O
onslaught	O
on	O
our	O
capital	O
city	O
.	O

Hundreds	O
of	O
others	O
,	O
including	O
children	O
and	O
young	O
girls	O
,	O
were	O
abducted	O
or	O
raped	O
or	O
had	O
limbs	O
deliberately	O
amputated	O
.	O

Terrorism	O
in	O
all	O
its	O
forms	O
and	O
manifestations	O
is	O
deplorable	O
and	O
must	O
be	O
eradicated	O
.	O

My	O
delegation	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
assure	O
this	O
Assembly	I-ORG
that	O
we	O
shall	O
do	O
everything	O
within	O
our	O
power	O
and	O
available	O
resources	O
to	O
support	O
the	O
current	O
multilateral	O
counter-terrorism	O
effort	O
under	O
the	O
aegis	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

The	O
new	O
emerging	O
coalition	O
to	O
counteract	O
the	O
scourge	O
of	O
terrorism	O
is	O
absolutely	O
necessary	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
the	O
Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
delegation	O
strongly	O
believes	O
that	O
we	O
should	O
also	O
strengthen	O
existing	O
coalitions	O
or	O
build	O
new	O
ones	O
against	O
those	O
forces	O
that	O
continue	O
to	O
kill	O
millions	O
of	O
children	O
and	O
adults	O
throughout	O
the	O
world	O
every	O
single	O
day	O
.	O

We	O
know	O
these	O
forces	O
.	O

We	O
know	O
their	O
vicious	O
and	O
destructive	O
powers	O
.	O

Hunger	O
,	O
poverty	O
,	O
malnutrition	O
,	O
malaria	O
,	O
HIV/AIDS	I-MISC
,	O
brutality	O
and	O
intolerance	O
—	O
these	O
are	O
but	O
a	O
few	O
of	O
them	O
.	O

Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
calls	O
upon	O
this	O
Assembly	I-ORG
and	O
the	O
entire	O
international	O
community	O
to	O
use	O
the	O
current	O
international	O
solidarity	O
against	O
terrorism	O
to	O
translate	O
the	O
Agenda	I-MISC
for	I-MISC
Peace	I-MISC
,	O
the	O
Agenda	I-MISC
for	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
,	O
the	O
Millennium	I-MISC
Declaration	I-MISC
,	O
the	O
Declaration	I-MISC
and	O
Plan	I-MISC
of	I-MISC
Action	I-MISC
of	O
the	O
World	I-MISC
Summit	I-MISC
for	I-MISC
Children	I-MISC
and	O
similar	O
strategies	O
and	O
goals	O
into	O
a	O
series	O
of	O
new	O
coalitions	O
:	O
a	O
new	O
coalition	O
against	O
childhood	O
diseases	O
;	O
a	O
new	O
coalition	O
against	O
poverty	O
and	O
human	O
underdevelopment	O
;	O
a	O
new	O
coalition	O
against	O
the	O
scourge	O
of	O
HIV/AIDS	I-MISC
and	O
malaria	O
;	O
and	O
a	O
brand	O
new	O
coalition	O
against	O
the	O
accumulation	O
of	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
and	O
other	O
weapons	O
of	O
mass	O
destruction	O
.	O

There	O
has	O
been	O
a	O
marked	O
improvement	O
in	O
the	O
situation	O
in	O
Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
serious	O
humanitarian	O
crisis	O
still	O
prevails	O
,	O
but	O
is	O
gradually	O
subsiding	O
.	O

Thousands	O
of	O
ex-combatants	O
have	O
been	O
disarmed	O
and	O
demobilized	O
.	O

Government	O
authority	O
and	O
civil	O
administrative	O
services	O
are	O
gradually	O
being	O
established	O
in	O
areas	O
previously	O
occupied	O
by	O
rebels	O
.	O

Our	O
restructured	O
army	O
is	O
now	O
truly	O
professional	O
,	O
thanks	O
to	O
the	O
intensive	O
training	O
programme	O
directed	O
by	O
the	O
Government	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-LOC
Kingdom	I-LOC
.	O

By	O
all	O
accounts	O
,	O
we	O
can	O
say	O
that	O
the	O
overall	O
security	O
and	O
safety	O
situation	O
is	O
one	O
of	O
great	O
expectation	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
coming	O
months	O
,	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
will	O
once	O
again	O
start	O
to	O
enjoy	O
to	O
the	O
fullest	O
extent	O
their	O
basic	O
right	O
to	O
life	O
—	O
a	O
life	O
free	O
from	O
brutal	O
armed	O
rebellion	O
such	O
as	O
that	O
provoked	O
and	O
abetted	O
by	O
external	O
forces	O
and	O
fuelled	O
by	O
blood	O
diamonds	O
for	O
10	O
long	O
years	O
.	O

In	O
this	O
connection	O
,	O
my	O
delegation	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
express	O
our	O
sincere	O
gratitude	O
to	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
and	O
its	O
agencies	O
,	O
the	O
Economic	I-ORG
Community	I-ORG
of	I-ORG
West	I-ORG
African	I-ORG
States	I-ORG
(	O
ECOWAS	I-ORG
)	O
,	O
UNAMSIL	I-ORG
troop-contributing	O
countries	O
,	O
the	O
United	I-LOC
Kingdom	I-LOC
and	O
other	O
friendly	O
nations	O
for	O
their	O
individual	O
and	O
collective	O
contributions	O
to	O
the	O
peace	O
process	O
in	O
Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
.	O

Allow	O
me	O
from	O
this	O
rostrum	O
to	O
express	O
the	O
condolences	O
of	O
the	O
Government	O
and	O
people	O
of	O
Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
for	O
those	O
brave	O
and	O
dedicated	O
ambassadors	O
of	O
peace	O
from	O
the	O
United	I-LOC
Kingdom	I-LOC
,	O
Zambia	I-LOC
,	O
the	O
Ukraine	I-LOC
and	O
Bulgaria	I-LOC
who	O
lost	O
their	O
lives	O
in	O
the	O
recent	O
helicopter	O
accidents	O
in	O
my	O
country	O
.	O

Despite	O
our	O
optimism	O
for	O
peace	O
and	O
stability	O
in	O
Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
,	O
past	O
experience	O
of	O
adventurous	O
attempts	O
by	O
the	O
rebels	O
to	O
renege	O
on	O
their	O
obligations	O
under	O
peace	O
agreements	O
have	O
taught	O
us	O
a	O
lesson:	O
We	O
have	O
to	O
remain	O
constantly	O
vigilant	O
.	O

The	O
safety	O
and	O
security	O
of	O
the	O
people	O
will	O
remain	O
high	O
on	O
our	O
national	O
agenda	O
,	O
as	O
will	O
the	O
process	O
of	O
consolidating	O
the	O
peace	O
through	O
sustainable	O
development	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
why	O
we	O
would	O
like	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
especially	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
,	O
to	O
continue	O
to	O
generate	O
the	O
necessary	O
international	O
support	O
for	O
our	O
post-conflict	O
and	O
peace-	O
building	O
effort	O
.	O

In	O
this	O
connection	O
,	O
we	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
draw	O
the	O
attention	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
and	O
those	O
who	O
assist	O
us	O
in	O
the	O
implementation	O
of	O
our	O
disarmament	O
,	O
demobilization	O
and	O
reintegration	O
programme	O
to	O
the	O
fact	O
that	O
the	O
disarmament	O
and	O
demobilization	O
of	O
ex-combatants	O
will	O
soon	O
come	O
to	O
a	O
successful	O
end	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
the	O
process	O
of	O
reintegration	O
remains	O
crucial	O
.	O

As	O
President	O
Kabbah	O
pointed	O
out	O
recently	O
,	O
we	O
also	O
have	O
tens	O
of	O
thousands	O
of	O
young	O
people	O
who	O
have	O
never	O
seen	O
,	O
touched	O
or	O
used	O
an	O
AK-47	O
rifle	O
or	O
a	O
rocket-propelled	O
grenade	O
.	O

They	O
,	O
too	O
,	O
are	O
waiting	O
to	O
be	O
integrated	O
into	O
the	O
mainstream	O
of	O
our	O
economic	O
and	O
social	O
sectors	O
.	O

On	O
behalf	O
of	O
my	O
Government	O
,	O
I	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
appeal	O
to	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
,	O
as	O
a	O
matter	O
of	O
urgency	O
,	O
to	O
help	O
us	O
remove	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
root	O
causes	O
of	O
conflict	O
by	O
increasing	O
support	O
for	O
our	O
reintegration	O
and	O
integration	O
programmes	O
for	O
the	O
benefit	O
of	O
youths	O
.	O

We	O
should	O
no	O
longer	O
allow	O
the	O
legitimate	O
social	O
and	O
economic	O
needs	O
or	O
grievances	O
of	O
these	O
young	O
people	O
to	O
be	O
exploited	O
by	O
ruthless	O
warlords	O
whose	O
sole	O
objective	O
is	O
to	O
drain	O
our	O
precious	O
mineral	O
resources	O
for	O
their	O
own	O
selfish	O
ends	O
.	O

First	O
,	O
there	O
has	O
been	O
a	O
substantial	O
increase	O
in	O
revenue	O
from	O
legitimate	O
diamonds	O
since	O
the	O
system	O
was	O
established	O
just	O
over	O
a	O
year	O
ago	O
.	O

Secondly	O
,	O
it	O
has	O
also	O
helped	O
to	O
reduce	O
the	O
incidence	O
of	O
an	O
old	O
problem	O
that	O
preceded	O
the	O
phenomenon	O
of	O
conflict	O
or	O
blood	O
diamonds	O
—	O
namely	O
,	O
smuggling	O
.	O

My	O
Government	O
is	O
in	O
the	O
process	O
of	O
updating	O
the	O
status	O
of	O
the	O
certification	O
system	O
in	O
its	O
third	O
report	O
to	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
through	O
the	O
Committee	O
that	O
is	O
monitoring	O
the	O
implementation	O
of	O
resolution	O
1306	O
(	O
2000	O
)	O
.	O

The	O
sacrifices	O
we	O
have	O
made	O
for	O
peace	O
in	O
Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
are	O
not	O
for	O
Sierra	I-MISC
Leoneans	I-MISC
alone	O
;	O
they	O
are	O
also	O
in	O
the	O
interest	O
of	O
peace	O
and	O
stability	O
in	O
the	O
Mano	I-LOC
River	I-LOC
Union	I-MISC
triangle	O
in	O
particular	O
and	O
the	O
West	I-MISC
African	I-MISC
subregion	O
as	O
a	O
whole	O
.	O

The	O
recent	O
rapprochement	O
at	O
the	O
ministerial	O
level	O
,	O
followed	O
by	O
meetings	O
of	O
the	O
Joint	I-ORG
Security	I-ORG
Committee	I-ORG
and	O
the	O
initiative	O
launched	O
by	O
the	O
Mano	I-LOC
River	I-LOC
Union	I-MISC
Women	I-MISC
Peace	I-MISC
Network	I-MISC
in	O
the	O
three	O
countries	O
—	O
Guinea	I-LOC
,	O
Liberia	I-LOC
and	O
Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
—	O
augur	O
well	O
for	O
the	O
proposed	O
Mano	I-LOC
River	I-LOC
Union	I-MISC
summit	O
meeting	O
.	O

Meanwhile	O
,	O
I	O
can	O
assure	O
the	O
Assembly	I-ORG
that	O
President	O
Kabbah	I-PER
remains	O
committed	O
to	O
his	O
determination	O
to	O
help	O
restore	O
adherence	O
to	O
the	O
principle	O
of	O
good-neighbourliness	O
in	O
the	O
Union	I-MISC
.	O

This	O
should	O
lead	O
to	O
a	O
revitalization	O
of	O
economic	O
cooperation	O
programmes	O
among	O
the	O
three	O
countries	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
admit	O
that	O
conflict	O
and	O
tension	O
in	O
the	O
Union	I-MISC
have	O
had	O
a	O
negative	O
impact	O
on	O
the	O
ability	O
of	O
ECOWAS	I-ORG
to	O
concentrate	O
on	O
the	O
principal	O
objective	O
for	O
which	O
it	O
was	O
created	O
,	O
namely	O
,	O
economic	O
cooperation	O
and	O
development	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
aware	O
that	O
primary	O
responsibility	O
for	O
alleviating	O
poverty	O
,	O
stimulating	O
economic	O
growth	O
and	O
reducing	O
conflicts	O
and	O
their	O
often	O
disastrous	O
consequences	O
lies	O
in	O
the	O
hands	O
of	O
the	O
developing	O
countries	O
themselves	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
the	O
international	O
consensus	O
is	O
that	O
sustainable	O
development	O
also	O
requires	O
greater	O
cooperation	O
between	O
developing	O
and	O
developed	O
countries	O
in	O
such	O
areas	O
as	O
trade	O
,	O
debt	O
relief	O
and	O
external	O
financing	O
.	O

There	O
are	O
many	O
pressing	O
and	O
unresolved	O
problems	O
on	O
the	O
international	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
agenda	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

One	O
of	O
them	O
is	O
the	O
situation	O
in	O
Palestine	I-LOC
.	O

It	O
remains	O
the	O
core	O
issue	O
in	O
the	O
search	O
for	O
peace	O
in	O
the	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
.	O

In	O
our	O
view	O
,	O
it	O
also	O
breeds	O
tension	O
,	O
and	O
directly	O
fans	O
the	O
flames	O
of	O
war	O
in	O
other	O
parts	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
current	O
state	O
of	O
affairs	O
it	O
is	O
no	O
longer	O
enough	O
to	O
speak	O
about	O
the	O
right	O
of	O
the	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
people	O
to	O
self-determination	O
.	O

They	O
have	O
a	O
right	O
to	O
an	O
independent	O
State	O
of	O
their	O
own	O
.	O

In	O
terms	O
of	O
international	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
,	O
we	O
cannot	O
afford	O
any	O
further	O
delay	O
.	O

Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
is	O
obviously	O
not	O
a	O
nuclear	O
Power	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
as	O
a	O
member	O
of	O
the	O
human	O
family	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
concerned	O
about	O
the	O
threat	O
or	O
use	O
of	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
.	O

Indeed	O
,	O
we	O
believe	O
that	O
these	O
weapons	O
pose	O
the	O
greatest	O
threat	O
to	O
human	O
survival	O
.	O

Therefore	O
,	O
we	O
shall	O
continue	O
to	O
support	O
universal	O
adherence	O
to	O
regional	O
and	O
international	O
disarmament	O
and	O
non-proliferation	O
instruments	O
.	O

For	O
instance	O
,	O
Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
recently	O
ratified	O
the	O
Comprehensive	I-MISC
Nuclear-Test-Ban	I-MISC
Treaty	I-MISC
,	O
which	O
we	O
strongly	O
believe	O
is	O
central	O
to	O
the	O
question	O
of	O
the	O
vertical	O
,	O
or	O
qualitative	O
,	O
proliferation	O
of	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
also	O
seriously	O
concerned	O
about	O
the	O
proliferation	O
of	O
conventional	O
arms	O
,	O
including	O
those	O
that	O
have	O
brought	O
untold	O
suffering	O
to	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
Sierra	I-LOC
Leone	I-LOC
during	O
the	O
past	O
10	O
years	O
.	O

Last	O
July	O
,	O
at	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Conference	I-MISC
on	I-MISC
the	I-MISC
Illicit	I-MISC
Trade	I-MISC
in	I-MISC
Small	I-MISC
Arms	I-MISC
and	I-MISC
Light	I-MISC
Weapons	I-MISC
in	I-MISC
All	I-MISC
Its	I-MISC
Aspects	I-MISC
,	O
we	O
pleaded	O
in	O
vain	O
for	O
action	O
to	O
prevent	O
the	O
transfer	O
of	O
these	O
weapons	O
to	O
non-State	O
entities	O
such	O
as	O
terrorists	O
and	O
rebels	O
who	O
commit	O
atrocities	O
against	O
innocent	O
civilians	O
.	O

The	O
recent	O
terrorist	O
attacks	O
and	O
the	O
awareness	O
that	O
biological	O
weapons	O
in	O
the	O
hands	O
of	O
such	O
non-State	O
entities	O
pose	O
a	O
threat	O
to	O
us	O
all	O
should	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
view	O
of	O
my	O
delegation	O
,	O
prod	O
those	O
Member	O
States	O
that	O
were	O
unable	O
to	O
support	O
our	O
plea	O
last	O
July	O
to	O
seriously	O
reconsider	O
their	O
position	O
on	O
this	O
important	O
issue	O
of	O
arms	O
transfers	O
to	O
non-State	O
entities	O
.	O

We	O
also	O
need	O
their	O
full	O
support	O
in	O
the	O
implementation	O
of	O
the	O
Programme	O
of	O
Action	O
adopted	O
at	O
that	O
important	O
Conference	O
.	O

In	O
conclusion	O
,	O
my	O
delegation	O
is	O
convinced	O
that	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
has	O
at	O
its	O
disposal	O
the	O
instruments	O
,	O
institutions	O
,	O
strategies	O
,	O
targets	O
and	O
road	O
maps	O
for	O
counteracting	O
and	O
eradicating	O
terrorism	O
,	O
HIV/AIDS	I-MISC
,	O
malaria	O
,	O
hunger	O
,	O
malnutrition	O
and	O
other	O
deadly	O
forces	O
,	O
through	O
closer	O
multilateral	O
cooperation	O
.	O

Let	O
the	O
fifty-sixth	O
session	O
of	O
this	O
Assembly	I-ORG
,	O
which	O
was	O
interrupted	O
by	O
the	O
common	O
enemy	O
of	O
terrorism	O
,	O
go	O
down	O
in	O
history	O
as	O
the	O
new	O
multilateral	O
cooperation	O
session	O
,	O
one	O
that	O
should	O
inspire	O
all	O
nations	O
,	O
large	O
and	O
small	O
,	O
nuclear	O
and	O
non-nuclear	O
,	O
to	O
deal	O
resolutely	O
with	O
the	O
other	O
common	O
enemies	O
of	O
the	O
human	O
race	O
.	O
