International	O
relations	O
are	O
becoming	O
increasingly	O
complex	O
and	O
multidimensional	O
,	O
while	O
developments	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
are	O
even	O
more	O
rapid	O
and	O
less	O
predictable	O
.	O

Under	O
these	O
circumstances	O
as	O
never	O
before	O
,	O
there	O
is	O
an	O
urgent	O
need	O
to	O
agree	O
upon	O
collective	O
responses	O
to	O
the	O
key	O
issues	O
of	O
today	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
solely	O
within	O
the	O
power	O
of	O
such	O
a	O
truly	O
universal	O
Organization	O
as	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
to	O
do	O
so	O
.	O

Moreover	O
,	O
such	O
solidarity-based	O
efforts	O
will	O
be	O
productive	O
only	O
if	O
they	O
reflect	O
the	O
entire	O
spectrum	O
of	O
views	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
on	O
global	O
challenges	O
and	O
threats	O
,	O
a	O
broad	O
range	O
of	O
historical	O
experiences	O
and	O
the	O
full	O
cultural	O
and	O
civilizational	O
diversity	O
of	O
the	O
modern	O
world	O
.	O

For	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
Members	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
family	O
,	O
that	O
approach	O
is	O
axiomatic	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
there	O
is	O
also	O
another	O
tendency	O
whereby	O
collective	O
actions	O
are	O
understood	O
primarily	O
as	O
agreement	O
with	O
the	O
viewpoint	O
of	O
one	O
group	O
of	O
countries	O
.	O

Such	O
views	O
manifest	O
themselves	O
in	O
various	O
areas:	O
international	O
security	O
,	O
the	O
settlement	O
of	O
conflict	O
situations	O
,	O
the	O
functioning	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
economy	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
choice	O
of	O
development	O
models	O
and	O
core	O
values	O
.	O

Many	O
problems	O
affecting	O
today	O
's	O
world	O
are	O
reflected	O
in	O
the	O
tragic	O
situation	O
in	O
Syria	I-LOC
and	O
in	O
the	O
uncertainty	O
surrounding	O
the	O
development	O
of	O
events	O
in	O
the	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
and	O
North	I-LOC
Africa	I-LOC
overall	O
.	O

From	O
the	O
very	O
onset	O
of	O
the	O
turmoil	O
in	O
that	O
region	O
,	O
Russia	I-LOC
has	O
consistently	O
called	O
for	O
the	O
development	O
by	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
of	O
a	O
common	O
approach	O
combining	O
support	O
for	O
the	O
Arab	I-MISC
peoples	O
on	O
their	O
path	O
to	O
transformation	O
with	O
an	O
understanding	O
of	O
the	O
fact	O
that	O
,	O
objectively	O
,	O
those	O
processes	O
will	O
be	O
lengthy	O
and	O
sometimes	O
painful	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
it	O
will	O
be	O
quite	O
important	O
not	O
to	O
undermine	O
them	O
through	O
gross	O
outside	O
interference	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
emphasized	O
the	O
need	O
to	O
act	O
in	O
a	O
balanced	O
way	O
and	O
to	O
take	O
account	O
of	O
the	O
fact	O
that	O
current	O
complex	O
developments	O
are	O
associated	O
with	O
,	O
among	O
other	O
things	O
,	O
a	O
tireless	O
quest	O
for	O
compromises	O
among	O
the	O
various	O
ethnic	O
and	O
religious	O
groups	O
that	O
make	O
up	O
the	O
mosaic	O
of	O
Arab	O
societies	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
consistently	O
supported	O
the	O
choice	O
of	O
the	O
evolutionary	O
way	O
of	O
development	O
and	O
the	O
peaceful	O
settlement	O
of	O
crises	O
through	O
national	O
dialogue	O
and	O
reconciliation	O
.	O

Another	O
perspective	O
has	O
been	O
reflected	O
in	O
the	O
attempts	O
made	O
to	O
determine	O
who	O
is	O
and	O
is	O
not	O
legitimate	O
among	O
the	O
leaders	O
of	O
the	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
and	O
North	I-LOC
Africa	I-LOC
region	O
,	O
to	O
impose	O
a	O
view	O
as	O
to	O
which	O
side	O
should	O
be	O
supported	O
in	O
domestic	O
national	O
conflicts	O
,	O
and	O
to	O
dictate	O
external	O
,	O
ready-made	O
prescriptions	O
for	O
democratic	O
transformation	O
.	O

Attempts	O
to	O
portray	O
,	O
in	O
a	O
simplified	O
way	O
,	O
the	O
developments	O
in	O
the	O
Arab	I-MISC
world	O
as	O
the	O
struggle	O
of	O
democracy	O
against	O
tyranny	O
or	O
of	O
good	O
against	O
evil	O
have	O
long	O
obscured	O
the	O
problems	O
associated	O
with	O
the	O
rising	O
wave	O
of	O
extremism	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
spilling	O
over	O
into	O
other	O
regions	O
today	O
.	O

The	O
terrorist	O
attacks	O
in	O
Kenya	I-LOC
have	O
demonstrated	O
the	O
full	O
gravity	O
of	O
that	O
threat	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
common	O
knowledge	O
that	O
jihadist	O
groups	O
that	O
include	O
numerous	O
radical	O
elements	O
from	O
all	O
parts	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
are	O
the	O
most	O
combat-capable	O
units	O
of	O
the	O
opposition	O
.	O

The	O
goals	O
that	O
they	O
are	O
pursuing	O
have	O
nothing	O
to	O
do	O
with	O
democracy	O
but	O
are	O
based	O
on	O
intolerance	O
and	O
aimed	O
at	O
the	O
destruction	O
of	O
secular	O
States	O
and	O
the	O
establishment	O
of	O
caliphates	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
difficult	O
to	O
qualify	O
as	O
far-sighted	O
a	O
policy	O
that	O
entails	O
fighting	O
in	O
Mali	I-LOC
the	O
same	O
extremist	O
groups	O
that	O
are	O
being	O
supported	O
in	O
Syria	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
use	O
of	O
chemical	O
weapons	O
is	O
inadmissible	O
.	O

That	O
does	O
not	O
mean	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
that	O
one	O
can	O
usurp	O
the	O
right	O
to	O
accuse	O
and	O
to	O
render	O
verdicts	O
.	O

All	O
of	O
the	O
incidents	O
associated	O
with	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
chemical	O
weapons	O
in	O
Syria	I-LOC
,	O
by	O
whomsoever	O
committed	O
,	O
must	O
be	O
investigated	O
in	O
a	O
professional	O
and	O
unbiased	O
manner	O
and	O
then	O
considered	O
by	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
exclusively	O
on	O
the	O
basis	O
of	O
facts	O
rather	O
than	O
of	O
allegations	O
or	O
assumptions	O
.	O

In	O
that	O
respect	O
,	O
at	O
the	O
Group	I-ORG
of	I-ORG
20	I-ORG
(	O
G-20	I-ORG
)	O
summit	O
held	O
in	O
June	O
,	O
an	O
agreement	O
was	O
reached	O
by	O
leaders	O
of	O
the	O
eight	O
key	O
States	O
.	O

￼Recently	O
a	O
common	O
argument	O
has	O
been	O
increasingly	O
made	O
to	O
the	O
effect	O
that	O
the	O
threat	O
or	O
use	O
of	O
force	O
,	O
directly	O
prohibited	O
by	O
the	O
Charter	I-MISC
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
is	O
virtually	O
the	O
most	O
effective	O
method	O
of	O
addressing	O
international	O
problems	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
settlement	O
of	O
domestic	O
conflicts	O
.	O

There	O
have	O
been	O
attempts	O
to	O
extrapolate	O
such	O
an	O
approach	O
to	O
the	O
situation	O
in	O
Syria	I-LOC
as	O
well	O
,	O
despite	O
the	O
fact	O
that	O
recent	O
experience	O
with	O
such	O
interventions	O
has	O
proved	O
that	O
they	O
are	O
ineffective	O
,	O
meaningless	O
and	O
destructive	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
an	O
extremely	O
dangerous	O
path	O
leading	O
to	O
the	O
erosion	O
of	O
the	O
foundations	O
of	O
today	O
's	O
world	O
order	O
and	O
the	O
subversion	O
of	O
the	O
weapons	O
of	O
mass	O
destruction	O
non-proliferation	O
regimes	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
alarming	O
to	O
hear	O
statements	O
about	O
the	O
right	O
to	O
use	O
military	O
force	O
to	O
ensure	O
one	O
's	O
own	O
interests	O
in	O
the	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
region	O
under	O
the	O
pretext	O
of	O
a	O
persistent	O
leadership	O
gap	O
in	O
the	O
international	O
arena	O
.	O

Recent	O
history	O
shows	O
that	O
no	O
State	O
,	O
no	O
matter	O
how	O
big	O
or	O
powerful	O
,	O
can	O
cope	O
alone	O
with	O
challenges	O
of	O
the	O
scope	O
faced	O
by	O
humankind	O
today	O
.	O

There	O
is	O
no	O
doubt	O
that	O
leadership	O
is	O
required	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
today	O
it	O
can	O
only	O
be	O
collective	O
leadership	O
based	O
on	O
agreed	O
actions	O
of	O
the	O
leading	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
,	O
with	O
strict	O
respect	O
for	O
the	O
principles	O
and	O
norms	O
of	O
international	O
law	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
the	O
growing	O
understanding	O
of	O
that	O
reality	O
that	O
has	O
opened	O
the	O
way	O
towards	O
achieving	O
Russia-United	I-LOC
States	I-LOC
understandings	O
relating	O
to	O
the	O
placing	O
under	O
international	O
control	O
and	O
subsequent	O
elimination	O
of	O
the	O
Syrian	I-MISC
chemical	O
arsenals	O
.	O

That	O
became	O
possible	O
thanks	O
to	O
the	O
decision	O
by	O
Damascus	I-LOC
to	O
join	O
the	O
Chemical	I-ORG
Weapons	I-ORG
Convention	I-ORG
and	O
fulfil	O
the	O
relevant	O
obligations	O
following	O
the	O
expedited	O
procedure	O
.	O

We	O
expect	O
that	O
the	O
decisions	O
of	O
the	O
Organization	I-ORG
for	I-ORG
the	I-ORG
Prohibition	I-ORG
of	I-ORG
Chemical	I-ORG
Weapons	I-ORG
Executive	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
and	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
will	O
contribute	O
to	O
creating	O
the	O
framework	O
required	O
for	O
the	O
elimination	O
of	O
chemical	O
arsenals	O
in	O
Syria	I-LOC
.	O

We	O
know	O
that	O
there	O
are	O
a	O
number	O
of	O
complicated	O
issues	O
related	O
to	O
ensuring	O
full	O
participation	O
of	O
the	O
countries	O
of	O
the	O
region	O
in	O
such	O
a	O
conference	O
,	O
but	O
they	O
cannot	O
be	O
discussed	O
endlessly	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
exactly	O
when	O
true	O
leadership	O
and	O
resolve	O
must	O
be	O
demonstrated	O
for	O
the	O
common	O
benefit	O
.	O

People	O
are	O
continuing	O
to	O
die	O
and	O
innocent	O
civilians	O
to	O
suffer	O
every	O
day	O
in	O
Syria	I-LOC
.	O

Religious	O
minorities	O
,	O
including	O
Christian	O
communities	O
,	O
are	O
becoming	O
victims	O
of	O
the	O
conflict	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
increasingly	O
acquiring	O
a	O
sectarian	O
character	O
.	O

Virtually	O
the	O
only	O
possibility	O
remaining	O
today	O
to	O
put	O
an	O
end	O
to	O
this	O
turmoil	O
is	O
to	O
break	O
the	O
deadlock	O
regarding	O
the	O
process	O
of	O
a	O
political	O
settlement	O
of	O
the	O
Syrian	I-MISC
crisis	O
.	O

We	O
continue	O
to	O
work	O
tirelessly	O
for	O
the	O
earliest	O
convening	O
of	O
a	O
peace	O
conference	O
to	O
implement	O
the	O
Geneva	I-LOC
communiqué	O
of	O
30	O
July	O
2012	O
(	O
S/2012/522	O
,	O
annex	O
)	O
.	O

We	O
hope	O
that	O
,	O
following	O
the	O
example	O
set	O
by	O
the	O
Government	O
of	O
Syria	I-LOC
,	O
the	O
opposition	O
will	O
also	O
constructively	O
respond	O
to	O
the	O
Russia-United	I-MISC
States	I-LOC
initiative	O
.	O

The	O
Syrian	I-MISC
crisis	O
should	O
not	O
overshadow	O
the	O
need	O
to	O
address	O
the	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
problem	O
.	O

We	O
expect	O
the	O
Israeli	I-MISC
and	O
Palestinian	I-MISC
leaders	O
to	O
shoulder	O
their	O
responsibility	O
for	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
their	O
people	O
at	O
this	O
current	O
critical	O
stage	O
,	O
where	O
the	O
parties	O
have	O
resumed	O
direct	O
talks	O
after	O
a	O
lengthy	O
interruption	O
.	O

While	O
duly	O
recognizing	O
the	O
efforts	O
made	O
by	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
States	I-LOC
in	O
the	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
settlement	O
process	O
,	O
we	O
deem	O
it	O
necessary	O
to	O
intensify	O
the	O
activity	O
of	O
the	O
Quartet	O
,	O
the	O
internationally	O
recognized	O
mechanism	O
for	O
providing	O
assistance	O
to	O
the	O
peace	O
process	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
on	O
the	O
basis	O
of	O
the	O
relevant	O
decisions	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
the	O
Madrid	I-LOC
principles	O
and	O
the	O
Arab	I-MISC
Peace	I-MISC
Initiative	I-MISC
.	O

It	O
is	O
also	O
important	O
to	O
ensure	O
the	O
close	O
involvement	O
of	O
the	O
Arab	I-MISC
countries	O
in	O
the	O
activities	O
of	O
the	O
Quartet	O
.	O

Approaches	O
based	O
on	O
negotiation	O
are	O
also	O
required	O
with	O
respect	O
to	O
other	O
situations	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
Iranian	I-MISC
nuclear	O
programme	O
and	O
the	O
nuclear	O
problem	O
in	O
the	O
Korean	O
peninsula	O
.	O

As	O
President	O
Vladimir	I-PER
Putin	I-PER
noted	O
in	O
his	O
recent	O
article	O
in	O
the	O
11	O
September	O
2013	O
issue	O
of	O
The	I-MISC
New	I-MISC
York	I-MISC
Times	I-MISC
,	O
"	O
We	O
must	O
stop	O
using	O
the	O
language	O
of	O
force	O
and	O
return	O
to	O
the	O
path	O
of	O
civilized	O
diplomatic	O
and	O
political	O
settlement	O
.	O
"	O

This	O
would	O
help	O
to	O
improve	O
the	O
international	O
environment	O
and	O
contribute	O
to	O
stepping	O
up	O
collective	O
efforts	O
to	O
counter	O
global	O
challenges	O
,	O
including	O
terrorism	O
and	O
drug	O
trafficking	O
.	O

Russia	I-LOC
intends	O
to	O
attach	O
priority	O
attention	O
to	O
these	O
challenges	O
during	O
its	O
presidency	O
of	O
the	O
Group	I-ORG
of	I-ORG
Eight	I-ORG
,	O
in	O
2014	O
.	O

Today	O
,	O
when	O
the	O
rigid	O
frame	O
of	O
the	O
bipolar	O
system	O
has	O
been	O
long	O
relegated	O
to	O
the	O
past	O
,	O
a	O
mark	O
of	O
the	O
time	O
is	O
the	O
strengthening	O
of	O
the	O
democratic	O
foundations	O
both	O
within	O
States	O
and	O
in	O
international	O
relations	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
same	O
way	O
,	O
the	O
complex	O
of	O
exclusiveness	O
and	O
supremacy	O
regarding	O
one	O
's	O
own	O
customs	O
in	O
the	O
human	O
rights	O
area	O
should	O
be	O
abandoned	O
and	O
instead	O
the	O
universal	O
criteria	O
enshrined	O
in	O
the	O
Universal	I-MISC
Declaration	I-MISC
of	I-MISC
Human	I-MISC
Rights	I-MISC
should	O
be	O
used	O
as	O
a	O
guideline	O
.	O

Moreover	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
important	O
to	O
respect	O
the	O
traditional	O
values	O
that	O
are	O
common	O
to	O
all	O
the	O
religions	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
obvious	O
that	O
a	O
genuine	O
partnership	O
is	O
hardly	O
achievable	O
without	O
reliance	O
on	O
the	O
foundations	O
of	O
economic	O
cooperation	O
.	O

The	O
prevailing	O
majority	O
of	O
States	O
are	O
interacting	O
within	O
the	O
framework	O
of	O
the	O
World	I-ORG
Trade	I-ORG
Organization	I-ORG
and	O
in	O
that	O
sense	O
they	O
are	O
already	O
operating	O
in	O
a	O
common	O
economic	O
space	O
.	O

This	O
creates	O
the	O
prerequisites	O
for	O
working	O
towards	O
harmonization	O
of	O
integration	O
processes	O
in	O
various	O
regions	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
instead	O
of	O
trying	O
to	O
artificially	O
pit	O
them	O
against	O
each	O
other	O
by	O
creating	O
new	O
division	O
lines	O
.	O

Russia	I-LOC
is	O
proceeding	O
from	O
that	O
exact	O
understanding	O
in	O
its	O
joint	O
work	O
with	O
its	O
partners	O
in	O
the	O
establishment	O
of	O
the	O
Eurasian	I-ORG
Economic	I-ORG
Union	I-ORG
.	O

The	O
main	O
priorities	O
are	O
the	O
eradication	O
of	O
poverty	O
and	O
support	O
for	O
economic	O
growth	O
through	O
the	O
expansion	O
of	O
investment	O
opportunities	O
and	O
the	O
creation	O
of	O
new	O
jobs	O
.	O

Some	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
urgent	O
issues	O
are	O
the	O
strengthening	O
of	O
the	O
energy	O
and	O
transport	O
infrastructures	O
,	O
the	O
fight	O
against	O
infectious	O
diseases	O
and	O
road	O
safety	O
.	O

Cooperation	O
among	O
States	O
should	O
rely	O
on	O
efficient	O
mechanisms	O
and	O
an	O
adequate	O
resource	O
base	O
.	O

In	O
that	O
context	O
,	O
we	O
support	O
the	O
further	O
strengthening	O
of	O
the	O
coordinating	O
role	O
and	O
potential	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Economic	I-ORG
and	I-ORG
Social	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
.	O

During	O
its	O
chairmanship	O
of	O
the	O
Group	I-ORG
of	I-ORG
20	I-ORG
,	O
Russia	I-LOC
has	O
consistently	O
pursued	O
a	O
policy	O
of	O
developing	O
its	O
interaction	O
with	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

We	O
believe	O
that	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
,	O
in	O
cooperation	O
with	O
the	O
G-20	I-ORG
,	O
will	O
develop	O
a	O
realistic	O
programme	O
of	O
long-term	O
cooperation	O
.	O

I	O
firmly	O
believe	O
that	O
,	O
by	O
joining	O
forces	O
on	O
the	O
basis	O
of	O
genuine	O
respect	O
and	O
considering	O
the	O
interests	O
of	O
each	O
and	O
everyone	O
,	O
we	O
will	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
achieve	O
the	O
lofty	O
goals	O
that	O
are	O
enshrined	O
in	O
the	O
Charter	I-MISC
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O
