On	O
the	O
ruins	O
of	O
a	O
world	O
ravaged	O
by	O
the	O
Second	I-MISC
World	I-
War	I-
,	O
51	O
countries	O
decided	O
to	O
give	O
humankind	O
a	O
forum	O
for	O
voicing	O
opinions	O
again	O
and	O
came	O
together	O
to	O
proclaim	O
the	O
values	O
enshrined	O
in	O
the	O
Charter:	I-MISC
dignity	O
,	O
human	O
rights	O
,	O
equality	O
,	O
justice	O
,	O
tolerance	O
and	O
peace	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
fitting	O
that	O
we	O
celebrate	O
the	O
seventieth	O
anniversary	O
of	O
our	O
Organization	O
,	O
which	O
has	O
achieved	O
so	O
much	O
.	O

It	O
would	O
be	O
difficult	O
to	O
imagine	O
a	O
world	O
without	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O
It	O
has	O
contributed	O
to	O
reducing	O
poverty	O
in	O
a	O
great	O
many	O
countries	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
has	O
achieved	O
its	O
primary	O
goal:	O
our	O
generation	O
is	O
the	O
first	O
one	O
not	O
to	O
have	O
lived	O
through	O
a	O
world	O
war	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
if	O
we	O
wish	O
to	O
make	O
an	O
honest	O
assessment	O
we	O
also	O
need	O
to	O
be	O
critical	O
.	O

Today	O
,	O
close	O
to	O
120,000	O
soldiers	O
are	O
currently	O
active	O
in	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
peacekeeping	O
missions	O
.	O

That	O
means	O
that	O
the	O
crises	O
and	O
the	O
wars	O
which	O
ravage	O
the	O
world	O
are	O
still	O
far	O
too	O
many	O
in	O
number	O
.	O

Today	O
we	O
have	O
60	O
million	O
displaced	O
persons	O
worldwide	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
more	O
than	O
at	O
any	O
time	O
since	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
was	O
founded	O
.	O

Not	O
only	O
have	O
we	O
not	O
made	O
sufficient	O
progress	O
when	O
tackling	O
certain	O
problems	O
,	O
but	O
we	O
have	O
created	O
new	O
ones	O
ourselves	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
global	O
warming	O
.	O

Even	O
though	O
we	O
might	O
not	O
like	O
to	O
admit	O
this	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
recognize	O
that	O
our	O
behaviour	O
continues	O
to	O
be	O
marked	O
by	O
major	O
inconsistencies	O
.	O

I	O
should	O
like	O
to	O
offer	O
two	O
examples	O
of	O
that	O
.	O

First	O
,	O
many	O
countries	O
continue	O
to	O
live	O
in	O
abject	O
poverty	O
when	O
they	O
have	O
a	O
wealth	O
of	O
natural	O
resources	O
.	O

Secondly	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
concerned	O
about	O
movements	O
of	O
mass	O
migration	O
,	O
yet	O
,	O
by	O
causing	O
global	O
warming	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
depriving	O
entire	O
populations	O
of	O
the	O
basic	O
conditions	O
they	O
need	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
remain	O
where	O
they	O
are	O
.	O

Let	O
us	O
ask	O
ourselves	O
why	O
so	O
many	O
educated	O
young	O
people	O
wish	O
to	O
leave	O
their	O
own	O
countries	O
.	O

This	O
concerns	O
not	O
only	O
developing	O
countries	O
but	O
also	O
a	O
considerable	O
number	O
of	O
European	I-ORG
States	I-ORG
as	O
well	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
acknowledge	O
that	O
we	O
have	O
not	O
yet	O
succeeded	O
in	O
achieving	O
anything	O
close	O
to	O
a	O
fair	O
global	O
distribution	O
of	O
wealth	O
,	O
nor	O
have	O
we	O
succeeded	O
in	O
establishing	O
the	O
rule	O
of	O
law	O
as	O
the	O
norm	O
.	O

Corruption	O
remains	O
endemic	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
to	O
admit	O
that	O
we	O
have	O
not	O
yet	O
succeeded	O
in	O
combining	O
growth	O
with	O
the	O
protection	O
of	O
our	O
environment	O
.	O

Furthermore	O
,	O
all	O
too	O
often	O
national	O
interests	O
impede	O
the	O
formulation	O
of	O
joint	O
responses	O
.	O

I	O
am	O
thinking	O
here	O
specifically	O
of	O
the	O
refugee	O
crisis	O
in	O
the	O
Middle	I-LOC
East	I-LOC
and	O
in	O
Europe	I-LOC
.	O

Faced	O
with	O
such	O
major	O
flows	O
of	O
migrants	O
,	O
the	O
solutions	O
can	O
only	O
be	O
joint	O
ones	O
.	O

If	O
we	O
each	O
continue	O
to	O
look	O
after	O
our	O
own	O
interests	O
,	O
we	O
will	O
all	O
lose	O
out	O
in	O
the	O
end	O
—	O
the	O
migrants	O
will	O
lose	O
out	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
solidarity	O
between	O
States	O
will	O
fall	O
by	O
the	O
wayside	O
.	O

If	O
we	O
fail	O
to	O
protect	O
human	O
dignity	O
,	O
we	O
do	O
ourselves	O
a	O
disservice	O
,	O
because	O
to	O
betray	O
one	O
's	O
own	O
values	O
is	O
to	O
betray	O
oneself	O
.	O

I	O
say	O
once	O
again	O
,	O
therefore	O
,	O
that	O
the	O
refugee	O
crises	O
require	O
responses	O
based	O
on	O
solidarity	O
.	O

One	O
cannot	O
ask	O
Turkey	I-LOC
,	O
Jordan	I-LOC
or	O
Lebanon	I-LOC
to	O
take	O
in	O
all	O
the	O
refugees	O
fleeing	O
the	O
civil	O
war	O
in	O
Syria	I-LOC
.	O

These	O
countries	O
have	O
already	O
done	O
so	O
much	O
,	O
such	O
admirable	O
work	O
,	O
which	O
has	O
received	O
too	O
little	O
recognition	O
thus	O
far	O
.	O

Similarly	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
not	O
possible	O
to	O
ask	O
a	O
few	O
European	I-MISC
countries	O
to	O
take	O
in	O
all	O
of	O
the	O
refugees	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
all	O
be	O
judged	O
on	O
how	O
we	O
respond	O
to	O
this	O
traumatic	O
humanitarian	O
challenge	O
.	O

Here	O
we	O
face	O
yet	O
another	O
inconsistency	O
.	O

If	O
countries	O
seek	O
answers	O
to	O
such	O
large-scale	O
phenomena	O
as	O
the	O
current	O
migration	O
movements	O
in	O
an	O
individualistic	O
way	O
,	O
without	O
coordinating	O
,	O
everything	O
will	O
be	O
brought	O
to	O
a	O
standstill	O
.	O

Human	O
beings	O
are	O
not	O
free	O
from	O
inconsistencies	O
,	O
none	O
of	O
us	O
are	O
.	O

To	O
some	O
extent	O
at	O
least	O
,	O
that	O
is	O
part	O
of	O
human	O
nature	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
when	O
it	O
comes	O
to	O
the	O
actions	O
of	O
Governments	O
,	O
States	O
and	O
communities	O
of	O
States	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
strive	O
to	O
minimize	O
such	O
inconsistencies	O
.	O

As	O
we	O
all	O
know	O
,	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
address	O
poverty	O
,	O
the	O
challenges	O
of	O
migration	O
,	O
conflicts	O
,	O
terrorism	O
,	O
organized	O
crime	O
and	O
climate	O
change	O
,	O
collective	O
action	O
is	O
vital	O
.	O

￼The	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
is	O
more	O
necessary	O
than	O
ever	O
.	O

What	O
we	O
require	O
is	O
a	O
strong	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
for	O
a	O
better	O
world	O
.	O

To	O
that	O
end	O
,	O
we	O
need	O
to	O
focus	O
on	O
three	O
priorities	O
.	O

The	O
ambitious	O
2030	O
Agenda	O
for	O
Sustainable	I-MISC
Development	I-MISC
(	O
resolution	O
70/1	O
)	O
that	O
we	O
have	O
just	O
adopted	O
is	O
a	O
huge	O
step	O
forward	O
.	O

As	O
for	O
the	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
pillar	O
,	O
it	O
affords	O
us	O
an	O
opportunity	O
to	O
strengthen	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
especially	O
with	O
regard	O
to	O
the	O
protection	O
of	O
the	O
civilian	O
population	O
.	O

Switzerland	I-LOC
is	O
convinced	O
that	O
one	O
cannot	O
resolve	O
a	O
conflict	O
through	O
a	O
purely	O
military	O
approach	O
.	O

The	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
must	O
base	O
each	O
of	O
its	O
actions	O
on	O
a	O
political	O
strategy	O
aimed	O
at	O
finding	O
a	O
lasting	O
solution	O
to	O
the	O
conflict	O
.	O

That	O
self-evident	O
truth	O
was	O
apparent	O
during	O
the	O
various	O
peace	O
and	O
dialogue	O
processes	O
conducted	O
in	O
Geneva	I-LOC
on	O
Syria	I-LOC
,	O
Libya	I-LOC
,	O
Iran	I-LOC
and	O
Yemen	I-LOC
.	O

As	O
for	O
the	O
review	O
of	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
resolution	O
1325	O
(	O
2000	O
)	O
,	O
Switzerland	I-LOC
will	O
continue	O
its	O
effort	O
to	O
promote	O
the	O
participation	O
of	O
women	O
in	O
peace	O
processes	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
also	O
grant	O
women	O
more	O
responsibility	O
when	O
it	O
comes	O
to	O
security-related	O
issues	O
.	O

Their	O
involvement	O
contributes	O
to	O
the	O
duribility	O
of	O
peace	O
agreements	O
by	O
expanding	O
the	O
agenda	O
of	O
negotiations	O
and	O
by	O
improving	O
the	O
population	O
's	O
commitment	O
to	O
such	O
agreements	O
.	O

The	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
will	O
review	O
its	O
global	O
counter-terrorism	O
strategy	O
during	O
the	O
summer	O
of	O
2016	O
.	O

The	O
implementation	O
of	O
this	O
strategy	O
is	O
a	O
priority	O
for	O
Switzerland	I-LOC
,	O
especially	O
the	O
parts	O
relating	O
to	O
terrorism	O
prevention	O
and	O
respect	O
for	O
human	O
rights	O
and	O
international	O
humanitarian	O
law	O
.	O

Finally	O
,	O
Switzerland	I-LOC
is	O
also	O
convinced	O
that	O
a	O
strong	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
is	O
a	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
capable	O
of	O
taking	O
action	O
and	O
decisions	O
when	O
international	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
are	O
under	O
threat	O
.	O

In	O
this	O
connection	O
,	O
we	O
reiterate	O
our	O
long-standing	O
call	O
to	O
the	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
not	O
to	O
block	O
or	O
vote	O
against	O
any	O
resolution	O
aimed	O
at	O
preventing	O
or	O
putting	O
an	O
end	O
to	O
crimes	O
of	O
genocide	O
,	O
crimes	O
against	O
humanity	O
or	O
war	O
crimes	O
.	O

Human	O
rights	O
are	O
the	O
third	O
pillar	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

Here	O
,	O
Switzerland	I-LOC
is	O
proud	O
to	O
be	O
seeking	O
election	O
to	O
the	O
Human	I-ORG
Rights	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
for	O
the	O
2016-2018	O
term	O
.	O

Switzerland	I-LOC
's	O
priorities	O
on	O
human	O
rights	O
are	O
the	O
abolition	O
of	O
the	O
death	O
penalty	O
,	O
the	O
implementation	O
of	O
the	O
prohibition	O
of	O
torture	O
,	O
the	O
promotion	O
of	O
women	O
's	O
and	O
children	O
's	O
rights	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
protection	O
of	O
human	O
rights	O
defenders	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
also	O
essential	O
that	O
the	O
perpetrators	O
of	O
human	O
rights	O
violations	O
be	O
brought	O
to	O
justice	O
.	O

Switzerland	I-LOC
here	O
wishes	O
to	O
recall	O
the	O
important	O
role	O
played	O
by	O
the	O
International	I-ORG
Criminal	I-ORG
Court	I-ORG
in	O
the	O
fight	O
against	O
impunity	O
.	O

As	O
far	O
as	O
the	O
humanitarian	O
system	O
is	O
concerned	O
,	O
it	O
has	O
clearly	O
reached	O
its	O
limits	O
as	O
a	O
result	O
of	O
the	O
growing	O
number	O
,	O
longer	O
duration	O
and	O
increasing	O
complexity	O
of	O
crises	O
.	O

So	O
far	O
this	O
year	O
,	O
82	O
million	O
people	O
have	O
required	O
immediate	O
humanitarian	O
assistance	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
an	O
unprecedented	O
number	O
.	O

The	O
World	I-MISC
Humanitarian	I-MISC
Summit	I-MISC
,	O
which	O
is	O
to	O
be	O
held	O
in	O
Istanbul	I-LOC
in	O
May	O
2016	O
,	O
will	O
afford	O
us	O
an	O
opportunity	O
to	O
improve	O
the	O
efficiency	O
of	O
the	O
humanitarian	O
system	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
enable	O
it	O
to	O
better	O
and	O
more	O
effectively	O
respond	O
to	O
victims'	O
needs	O
.	O

In	O
December	O
,	O
Geneva	I-LOC
will	O
host	O
the	O
thirty-second	O
International	O
Conference	O
of	O
the	O
Red	I-ORG
Cross	I-ORG
and	I-ORG
Red	I-ORG
Crescent	I-ORG
.	O

That	O
will	O
be	O
an	O
important	O
opportunity	O
to	O
make	O
progress	O
towards	O
the	O
creation	O
of	O
an	O
institutional	O
framework	O
in	O
which	O
to	O
discuss	O
how	O
we	O
can	O
improve	O
compliance	O
with	O
international	O
humanitarian	O
law	O
.	O

Let	O
us	O
continue	O
to	O
work	O
together	O
to	O
build	O
a	O
modern	O
and	O
effective	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
by	O
reforming	O
its	O
governance	O
.	O

In	O
this	O
context	O
,	O
Geneva	I-LOC
,	O
as	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
main	O
centres	O
of	O
global	O
governance	O
,	O
has	O
an	O
essential	O
role	O
to	O
play	O
.	O

The	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
can	O
count	O
on	O
the	O
full	O
support	O
of	O
my	O
country	O
,	O
Switzerland	I-LOC
,	O
to	O
strengthen	O
it	O
during	O
the	O
next	O
70	O
years	O
.	O
