Let	O
me	O
begin	O
,	O
Sir	O
,	O
by	O
paying	O
tribute	O
to	O
your	O
predecessor	O
,	O
Jean	O
Ping	O
,	O
for	O
his	O
extraordinary	O
work	O
—	O
above	O
all	O
on	O
the	O
world	O
summit	O
,	O
but	O
also	O
throughout	O
his	O
year	O
as	O
President	O
—	O
and	O
by	O
offering	O
my	O
congratulations	O
to	O
you	O
on	O
beginning	O
your	O
year	O
in	O
office	O
.	O

I	O
should	O
also	O
like	O
to	O
express	O
,	O
on	O
behalf	O
of	O
the	O
European	I-ORG
Union	I-LOC
and	O
all	O
its	O
member	O
States	I-LOC
,	O
our	O
deepest	O
sympathy	O
and	O
solidarity	O
to	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
States	I-LOC
,	O
particularly	O
those	O
in	O
the	O
Gulf	O
states	O
,	O
in	O
their	O
hour	O
of	O
need	O
.	O

In	O
early	O
July	O
,	O
my	O
first	O
duty	O
in	O
the	O
presidency	O
of	O
the	O
European	I-ORG
Union	I-LOC
was	O
to	O
go	O
to	O
Srebrenica	O
to	O
mark	O
the	O
tenth	O
anniversary	O
of	O
the	O
massacre	O
there	O
,	O
the	O
worst	O
in	O
Europe	O
since	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
the	O
Second	O
World	O
War	O
.	O

More	O
than	O
8	O
,000	O
people	O
,	O
mainly	O
Muslim	O
,	O
were	O
taken	O
away	O
and	O
killed	O
as	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
just	O
stood	O
to	O
one	O
side	O
.	O

To	O
be	O
sure	O
,	O
we	O
had	O
shown	O
the	O
right	O
convictions	O
in	O
words	O
,	O
but	O
shamefully	O
,	O
we	O
had	O
failed	O
to	O
act	O
.	O

The	O
lesson	O
of	O
that	O
massacre	O
—	O
and	O
of	O
the	O
even	O
greater	O
horror	O
of	O
Rwanda	I-LOC
a	O
year	O
before	O
—	O
was	O
that	O
we	O
all	O
needed	O
better	O
means	O
to	O
turn	O
our	O
collective	O
will	O
into	O
decisive	O
action	O
.	O

Today	O
,	O
the	O
Union	I-LOC
is	O
on	O
the	O
ground	O
as	O
a	O
military	O
,	O
police	O
or	O
civilian	O
presence	O
in	O
Bosnia	O
,	O
in	O
Aceh	O
,	O
in	O
Iraq	I-LOC
,	O
in	O
the	O
Democratic	O
Republic	O
of	O
the	O
Congo	O
and	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
African	O
Union	I-LOC
,	O
in	O
Darfur	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
summit	O
this	O
week	O
,	O
we	O
agreed	O
on	O
the	O
further	O
steps	O
that	O
we	O
need	O
to	O
take	O
for	O
the	O
Organization	O
to	O
be	O
even	O
more	O
effective	O
.	O

Of	I-LOC
all	O
that	O
was	O
agreed	O
at	O
the	O
summit	O
,	O
I	O
believe	O
it	O
will	O
be	O
the	O
agreement	O
on	O
our	O

"	O
responsibility	O
to	O
protect	O
"	O

that	O
will	O
be	O
seen	O
in	O
the	O
future	O
as	O
having	O
the	O
greatest	O
significance	O
of	O
all	O
.	O

If	O
we	O
follow	O
through	O
on	O
the	O
responsibility	O
to	O
protect	O
,	O
then	O
never	O
again	O
will	O
genocide	O
,	O
ethnic	O
cleansing	O
and	O
crimes	O
against	O
humanity	O
be	O
allowed	O
to	O
take	O
place	O
under	O
our	O
noses	O
with	O
nothing	O
done	O
.	O

The	O
responsibility	O
to	O
protect	O
is	O
,	O
of	O
course	O
,	O
a	O
reflection	O
of	O
our	O
common	O
morality	O
.	O

But	O
it	O
is	O
also	O
a	O
recognition	O
that	O
the	O
world	O
in	O
which	O
we	O
now	O
live	O
is	O
too	O
small	O
for	O
us	O
to	O
be	O
unaffected	O
by	O
,	O
or	O
indifferent	O
to	O
,	O
the	O
innocent	O
victims	O
of	O
murder	O
and	O
oppression	O
.	O

This	O
shrinking	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
has	O
been	O
as	O
sudden	O
as	O
it	O
has	O
been	O
profound	O
.	O

When	O
the	O
Berlin	I-LOC
wall	O
fell	O
,	O
a	O
generation	O
of	O
ideological	O
certainties	O
was	O
swept	O
away	O
.	O

People	O
could	O
suddenly	O
see	O
partners	O
where	O
before	O
they	O
had	O
only	O
glimpsed	O
adversaries	O
.	O

And	O
as	O
that	O
very	O
visible	O
barrier	O
was	O
noisily	O
being	O
breached	O
,	O
a	O
revolution	O
in	O
information	O
technology	O
was	O
quietly	O
erasing	O
the	O
barriers	O
of	O
distance	O
and	O
time	O
.	O

Continents	O
and	O
cultures	O
are	O
now	O
cabled	O
together	O
and	O
bound	O
by	O
trade	O
and	O
services	O
in	O
a	O
way	O
that	O
was	O
unimaginable	O
even	O
a	O
decade	O
ago	O
.	O

In	O
this	O
new	O
world	O
,	O
we	O
can	O
no	O
longer	O
safely	O
tolerate	O
the	O
general	O
threat	O
that	O
can	O
come	O
from	O
a	O
particular	O
human	O
tragedy	O
,	O
wherever	O
it	O
takes	O
place	O
.	O

To	O
a	O
greater	O
extent	O
than	O
ever	O
before	O
,	O
we	O
share	O
the	O
same	O
world:	O
the	O
same	O
threats	O
and	O
responsibilities	O
,	O
the	O
same	O
opportunities	O
and	O
interests	O
.	O

And	O
precisely	O
because	O
the	O
boundaries	O
of	O
our	O
world	O
have	O
contracted	O
,	O
the	O
horizons	O
—	O
the	O
ambitions	O
—	O
of	O
many	O
people	O
around	O
the	O
globe	O
have	O
infinitely	O
expanded	O
.	O

For	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
in	O
our	O
history	O
,	O
mankind	O
has	O
the	O
ability	O
to	O
realize	O
the	O
potential	O
of	O
individuals	O
in	O
societies	O
of	O
all	O
kinds	O
and	O
in	O
every	O
region	O
through	O
an	O
open	O
exchange	O
of	O
goods	O
,	O
investment	O
,	O
technology	O
and	O
,	O
above	O
all	O
,	O
ideas	O
.	O

Not	O
least	O
in	O
all	O
of	O
this	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
the	O
rise	O
of	O
India	I-LOC
and	O
of	O
China	I-LOC
that	O
is	O
reordering	O
the	O
world	O
economy	O
.	O

Hundreds	O
of	O
millions	O
there	O
and	O
elsewhere	O
have	O
been	O
lifted	O
out	O
of	O
poverty	O
.	O

A	O
new	O
global	O
market	O
has	O
been	O
created	O
that	O
ignores	O
the	O
divide	O
—	O
which	O
seemed	O
so	O
fundamental	O
for	O
so	O
many	O
decades	O
—	O
between	O
East	O
and	O
West	O
.	O

Currently	O
,	O
not	O
everyone	O
has	O
the	O
chance	O
to	O
share	O
in	O
all	O
of	O
that	O
.	O

Much	I-LOC
of	O
sub-Saharan	O
Africa	O
remains	O
blighted	O
by	O
poverty	O
,	O
disease	O
and	O
conflict	O
.	O

The	O
European	I-ORG
Union	I-LOC
has	O
now	O
set	O
a	O
clear	O
timetable	O
to	O
achieve	O
the	O
0	O
.	O
7	O
per	O
cent	O
target	O
for	O
aid	O
.	O

Debt	O
relief	O
,	O
trade	O
reform	O
and	O
development	O
aid	O
are	O
all	O
vital	O
,	O
but	O
none	O
of	O
them	O
can	O
work	O
alone	O
.	O

Fundamental	O
to	O
making	O
poverty	O
history	O
are	O
the	O
Governments	O
of	O
the	O
developing	O
world	O
themselves	O
.	O

And	O
where	O
Governments	O
fail	O
,	O
their	O
own	O
peoples	O
are	O
the	O
victims	O
,	O
as	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Special	O
Envoy	O
Anna	I-LOC
Tibaijuka	O
's	O
damning	O
assessment	O
of	O
the	O
situation	O
in	O
Zimbabwe	I-LOC
only	O
too	O
graphically	O
shows	O
.	O

Sub-Saharan	O
Africa	O
is	O
not	O
alone	O
in	O
having	O
yet	O
to	O
achieve	O
its	O
potential	O
.	O

The	O
American	O
author	O
Thomas	O
Friedman	O
,	O
in	O
his	O
recent	O
book	O
The	O
World	O
Is	O
Flat	O
,	O
highlights	O
an	O
extraordinary	O
anomaly:	O
it	O
was	O
the	O
Arab	O
peoples	O
whose	O
forebears	O
devised	O
algebra	O
and	O
the	O
algorithms	O
upon	O
which	O
our	O
entire	O
digital	O
age	O
is	O
based	O
,	O
but	O
those	O
peoples	O
are	O
now	O
right	O
at	O
the	O
rear	O
of	O
today	O
's	O
technological	O
revolution	O
,	O
with	O
,	O
for	O
example	O
,	O
fewer	O
than	O
2	O
per	O
cent	O
of	O
those	O
populations	O
having	O
Internet	O
access	O
.	O

Three	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Development	I-MISC
Programme	I-MISC
Arab	O
Human	O
Development	I-MISC
Reports	O
have	O
now	O
set	O
out	O
clearly	O
how	O
limited	O
economic	O
prospects	O
and	O
stunted	O
political	O
freedoms	O
have	O
led	O
young	O
and	O
talented	O
people	O
towards	O
alienation	O
and	O
disillusionment	O
.	O

The	O
answer	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
does	O
not	O
lie	O
in	O
easy	O
stereotypes	O
about	O
some	O
clash	O
of	O
civilizations	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
only	O
the	O
terrorists	O
and	O
the	O
preachers	O
of	O
hate	O
who	O
want	O
us	O
to	O
believe	O
that	O
Islam	O
and	O
the	O
West	O
are	O
fundamentally	O
different	O
.	O

Theirs	O
is	O
a	O
philosophy	O
of	O
mistrust	O
and	O
despair	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
reject	O
it	O
utterly	O
.	O

Indonesia	I-LOC
and	O
Turkey	I-LOC
—	O
to	O
name	O
just	O
two	O
—	O
are	O
both	O
striking	O
examples	O
of	O
how	O
countries	O
with	O
predominantly	O
Muslim	O
populations	O
can	O
embrace	O
democracy	O
and	O
modernity	O
.	O

We	O
in	O
the	O
European	I-ORG
Union	I-LOC
have	O
seen	O
the	O
vibrant	O
Muslim	O
communities	O
in	O
our	O
own	O
countries	O
,	O
and	O
from	O
that	O
experience	O
have	O
seen	O
how	O
Islamic	O
and	O
Western	O
cultures	O
can	O
be	O
partners	O
in	O
a	O
global	O
society	O
.	O

Everyone	O
knows	O
that	O
the	O
Arab	O
peoples	O
want	O
prosperity	O
,	O
freedom	O
and	O
democracy	O
every	O
bit	O
as	O
much	O
as	O
anyone	O
in	O
Europe	O
or	O
America	I-LOC
.	O

So	O
the	O
fact	O
that	O
the	O
Arab	O
world	O
has	O
the	O
lowest	O
scores	O
in	O
regional	O
measurements	O
of	O
democratic	O
practices	O
,	O
civil	O
freedoms	O
and	O
good	O
governance	O
is	O
not	O
some	O
cultural	O
inevitability	O
,	O
but	O
a	O
temporary	O
failure	O
of	O
human	O
will	O
.	O

In	O
that	O
regard	O
,	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
has	O
a	O
clear	O
responsibility	O
to	O
encourage	O
regionally	O
led	O
political	O
,	O
social	O
and	O
economic	O
reform	O
.	O

The	O
European	I-ORG
Union	I-LOC
strongly	O
supports	O
such	O
reform	O
and	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
do	O
so	O
.	O

Equally	O
,	O
it	O
has	O
been	O
our	O
active	O
foreign	O
policy	O
that	O
has	O
placed	O
us	O
in	O
the	O
lead	O
with	O
regard	O
to	O
Iran	I-LOC
,	O
especially	O
on	O
the	O
nuclear	O
dossier	O
.	O

With	O
our	O
High	O
Representative	O
Javier	O
Solana	I-LOC
and	O
my	O
French	O
and	O
German	O
Foreign	O
Minister	O
colleagues	O
,	O
we	O
have	O
made	O
detailed	O
proposals	O
for	O
the	O
relationship	O
between	O
the	O
European	I-ORG
Union	I-LOC
and	O
Iran	I-LOC
to	O
be	O
based	O
on	O
cooperation	O
and	O
respect	O
for	O
international	O
norms	O
and	O
treaties	O
.	O

Our	O
proposals	O
envisage	O
a	O
high-level	O
,	O
long-term	O
political	O
and	O
security	O
framework	O
between	O
the	O
European	I-ORG
Union	I-LOC
and	O
Iran	I-LOC
,	O
in	O
which	O
we	O
would	O
work	O
together	O
in	O
political	O
,	O
economic	O
,	O
scientific	O
and	O
technological	O
areas	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
civil	O
nuclear	O
field	O
,	O
in	O
return	O
for	O
Iran	I-LOC
providing	O
guarantees	O
about	O
its	O
intentions	O
and	O
capabilities	O
concerning	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
.	O

So	O
,	O
we	O
will	O
listen	O
very	O
carefully	O
to	O
and	O
reflect	O
on	O
this	O
afternoon	O
's	O
speech	O
by	O
the	O
new	O
President	O
of	O
the	O
Islamic	O
Republic	O
of	O
Iran	I-LOC
,	O
Mr.	O
Mahmoud	O
Ahmadinejad	O
.	O

On	O
Iraq	I-LOC
,	O
the	O
European	I-ORG
Union	I-LOC
now	O
has	O
a	O
comprehensive	O
programme	O
of	O
engagement	O
and	O
has	O
put	O
behind	O
it	O
divisions	O
over	O
the	O
military	O
action	O
two	O
and	O
a	O
half	O
years	O
ago	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
supporting	O
the	O
goal	O
of	O
a	O
peaceful	O
,	O
prosperous	O
,	O
democratic	O
and	O
stable	O
nation	O
.	O

We	O
salute	O
Prime	O
Minister	O
Sharon	O
's	O
brave	O
decision	O
to	O
withdraw	O
from	O
the	O
Gaza	I-LOC
Strip	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
salute	O
President	O
Mahmoud	O
Abbas	O
's	O
work	O
to	O
build	O
the	O
first	O
stage	O
of	O
an	O
effective	O
,	O
viable	O
State	O
of	O
Palestine	I-LOC
.	O

In	O
July	O
,	O
the	O
European	I-ORG
Union	I-LOC
again	O
suffered	O
the	O
horror	O
of	O
a	O
major	O
terrorist	O
atrocity	O
.	O

This	O
time	O
the	O
target	O
was	O
my	O
country	O
,	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Kingdom:	O
its	O
capital	O
,	O
London	I-LOC
.	O

But	O
none	O
of	O
us	O
is	O
safe	O
from	O
the	O
threat	O
of	O
terror	O
.	O

International	O
terrorism	O
requires	O
an	O
international	O
response	O
;	O
otherwise	O
,	O
we	O
all	O
pay	O
the	O
price	O
for	O
each	O
other	O
's	O
vulnerabilities	O
.	O

The	O
ratification	O
of	O
a	O
comprehensive	O
treaty	O
on	O
terrorism	O
is	O
,	O
therefore	O
,	O
at	O
the	O
highest	O
priority	O
.	O

But	O
the	O
threat	O
from	O
terrorists	O
and	O
the	O
political	O
instability	O
they	O
bring	O
is	O
made	O
worse	O
by	O
the	O
easy	O
availability	O
of	O
weapons	O
in	O
what	O
has	O
become	O
an	O
anarchic	O
,	O
unregulated	O
international	O
trade	O
.	O

These	O
same	O
weapons	O
fuelled	O
the	O
killings	O
in	O
Rwanda	I-LOC
and	O
in	O
Bosnia	O
a	O
decade	O
ago	O
and	O
are	O
fuelling	O
the	O
conflicts	O
in	O
the	O
Democratic	O
Republic	O
of	O
the	O
Congo	O
and	O
in	O
Darfur	O
today	O
.	O

We	O
already	O
have	O
international	O
instruments	O
to	O
regulate	O
chemical	O
,	O
biological	O
and	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
.	O

We	O
in	O
the	O
European	I-ORG
Union	I-LOC
have	O
a	O
comprehensive	O
arms	O
control	O
regime	O
.	O

But	O
I	O
suggest	O
to	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
that	O
the	O
time	O
has	O
now	O
come	O
for	O
this	O
Organization	O
to	O
embrace	O
the	O
idea	O
of	O
an	O
international	O
arms	O
trade	O
treaty	O
,	O
which	O
would	O
build	O
on	O
and	O
strengthen	O
existing	O
initiatives	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
in	O
the	O
killing	O
fields	O
of	O
Europe	O
,	O
in	O
two	O
successive	O
wars	O
,	O
that	O
the	O
twin	O
ideas	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
and	O
of	O
the	O
European	I-ORG
Union	I-LOC
became	O
imperative	O
.	O

Today	O
,	O
the	O
European	I-ORG
Union	I-LOC
's	O
commitment	O
to	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
is	O
profound	O
;	O
it	O
has	O
never	O
been	O
stronger	O
.	O

And	O
it	O
is	O
reflected	O
in	O
what	O
we	O
give	O
in	O
voluntary	O
donations	O
and	O
to	O
the	O
regular	O
budget	O
and	O
peacekeeping	O
operations	O
.	O

The	O
fundamental	O
purpose	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
remains	O
today	O
what	O
it	O
was	O
at	O
its	O
foundation:	O
to	O
remove	O
the	O
scourge	O
of	O
war	O
,	O
to	O
reaffirm	O
the	O
worth	O
of	O
the	O
human	O
person	O
and	O
to	O
promote	O
social	O
progress	O
and	O
better	O
standards	O
of	O
life	O
.	O

In	O
this	O
changed	O
and	O
changing	O
world	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
the	O
responsibility	O
of	O
us	O
all	O
to	O
ensure	O
that	O
this	O
Organization	O
has	O
the	O
powers	O
and	O
the	O
resources	O
to	O
achieve	O
all	O
these	O
aims	O
.	O
