His	O
extensive	O
experience	O
in	O
both	O
regional	O
and	O
international	O
affairs	O
will	O
undoubtedly	O
enrich	O
the	O
debate	O
and	O
the	O
proceedings	O
during	O
this	O
session	O
.	O

I	O
wish	O
to	O
assure	O
him	O
of	O
the	O
full	O
cooperation	O
of	O
Zimbabwe	I-LOC
as	O
he	O
discharges	O
the	O
onerous	O
duties	O
of	O
that	O
high	O
office	O
.	O

If	O
I	O
may	O
be	O
allowed	O
,	O
I	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
preface	O
my	O
speech	O
with	O
a	O
reference	O
to	O
the	O
most	O
glowing	O
and	O
moving	O
speech	O
that	O
we	O
heard	O
from	O
the	O
President	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
States	I-LOC
yesterday	O
(	O
see	O
A/67/PV.6	0
)	O
,	O
the	O
significance	O
of	O
which	O
was	O
to	O
get	O
us	O
to	O
condemn	O
the	O
tragic	O
death	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
States	I-LOC
Ambassador	O
to	O
Libya	I-LOC
.	O

I	O
am	O
sure	O
that	O
we	O
were	O
all	O
moved	O
and	O
that	O
we	O
all	O
agree	O
that	O
it	O
was	O
,	O
indeed	O
,	O
an	O
appalling	O
event	O
that	O
we	O
all	O
condemn	O
.	O

His	O
death	O
occurred	O
in	O
a	O
context	O
in	O
which	O
NATO	I-ORG
was	O
operating	O
supposedly	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
protect	O
civilians	O
.	O

As	O
we	O
join	O
the	O
United	I-LOC
States	I-LOC
in	O
spirit	O
in	O
condemning	O
the	O
Ambassador	O
's	O
death	O
,	O
will	O
the	O
United	I-LOC
States	I-LOC
also	O
join	O
us	O
in	O
condemning	O
the	O
barbaric	O
death	O
of	O
the	O
Head	O
of	O
State	O
of	O
Libya	I-LOC
,	O
Al-Qadhafi	I-PER
?	O

The	O
mission	O
was	O
strictly	O
to	O
protect	O
civilians	O
,	O
but	O
it	O
became	O
a	O
brutal	O
hunt	O
for	O
Al-Qadhafi	I-PER
and	O
his	O
family	O
.	O

NATO	I-ORG
caught	O
up	O
with	O
them	O
.	O

Al-Qadhafi	I-PER
and	O
some	O
of	O
his	O
children	O
suffered	O
the	O
brutal	O
deaths	O
about	O
which	O
we	O
know	O
.	O

As	O
the	O
United	I-LOC
States	I-LOC
President	O
spoke	O
,	O
I	O
am	O
sure	O
that	O
that	O
he	O
was	O
aware	O
that	O
his	O
country	O
,	O
as	O
a	O
NATO	I-ORG
Power	O
,	O
had	O
,	O
alongside	O
the	O
other	O
NATO	I-ORG
Powers	O
,	O
the	O
authority	O
under	O
Chapter	I-MISC
VII	I-MISC
to	O
operate	O
in	O
Libya	I-LOC
in	O
order	O
to	O
protect	O
civilians	O
.	O

But	O
is	O
that	O
what	O
the	O
operation	O
turned	O
out	O
to	O
be	O
?	O

In	O
a	O
very	O
dishonest	O
manner	O
,	O
we	O
saw	O
the	O
authority	O
entrusted	O
under	O
Chapter	I-MISC
VII	I-MISC
being	O
used	O
as	O
a	O
weapon	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
rout	O
a	O
whole	O
family	O
and	O
to	O
commit	O
the	O
murders	O
that	O
occurred	O
in	O
that	O
country	O
.	O

Bombs	O
were	O
hurled	O
in	O
a	O
callous	O
manner	O
.	O

Quite	O
a	O
number	O
of	O
civilians	O
died	O
.	O

Was	O
that	O
the	O
protection	O
they	O
had	O
sought	O
under	O
Chapter	I-MISC
VII	I-MISC
of	O
the	O
Charter	O
?	O

So	O
the	O
death	O
of	O
Al-Qadhafi	I-PER
must	O
be	O
seen	O
in	O
the	O
same	O
tragic	O
vein	O
as	O
the	O
death	O
of	O
Chris	I-PER
Stevens	I-PER
.	O

We	O
condemn	O
both	O
.	O

Let	O
me	O
begin	O
by	O
reaffirming	O
the	O
rightful	O
and	O
important	O
role	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
in	O
the	O
management	O
of	O
issues	O
affecting	O
international	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
quest	O
for	O
a	O
more	O
just	O
and	O
equitable	O
international	O
order	O
,	O
Zimbabwe	I-LOC
remains	O
strongly	O
opposed	O
to	O
unilateralism	O
and	O
committed	O
to	O
multilateralism	O
.	O

We	O
would	O
therefore	O
like	O
to	O
see	O
a	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
that	O
continues	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
guarantor	O
of	O
world	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
and	O
a	O
bulwark	O
in	O
the	O
fight	O
for	O
justice	O
and	O
equality	O
among	O
nations	O
.	O

It	O
behoves	O
us	O
all	O
,	O
therefore	O
,	O
to	O
take	O
the	O
necessary	O
steps	O
to	O
ensure	O
that	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
is	O
not	O
marginalized	O
on	O
international	O
issues	O
.	O

Equally	O
important	O
,	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
must	O
,	O
in	O
future	O
,	O
never	O
allow	O
itself	O
to	O
be	O
abused	O
,	O
as	O
it	O
was	O
in	O
the	O
case	O
I	O
referred	O
to	O
earlier	O
,	O
when	O
NATO	I-ORG
sought	O
under	O
Chapter	I-MISC
VII	I-MISC
authority	O
to	O
protect	O
civilians	O
,	O
but	O
it	O
did	O
not	O
turn	O
out	O
to	O
be	O
that	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
future	O
,	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
must	O
never	O
allow	O
itself	O
to	O
be	O
abused	O
by	O
any	O
Member	O
State	O
or	O
group	O
of	O
States	O
that	O
seeks	O
to	O
achieve	O
parochial	O
,	O
partisan	O
goals	O
.	O

The	O
Charter	I-MISC
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
clearly	O
stipulates	O
that	O
it	O
is	O
an	O
international	O
body	O
that	O
should	O
work	O
for	O
the	O
good	O
of	O
all	O
the	O
peoples	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
,	O
big	O
and	O
small	O
.	O

We	O
recognize	O
that	O
there	O
are	O
existing	O
and	O
emerging	O
threats	O
and	O
challenges	O
that	O
continue	O
to	O
frustrate	O
our	O
individual	O
and	O
collective	O
efforts	O
to	O
attain	O
greater	O
economic	O
development	O
and	O
social	O
progress	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
peace	O
and	O
security	O
.	O

But	O
the	O
increasing	O
trend	O
among	O
the	O
NATO	I-ORG
member	O
States	O
,	O
inspired	O
by	O
the	O
arrogant	O
belief	O
that	O
they	O
are	O
the	O
most	O
powerful	O
among	O
us	O
—	O
demonstrated	O
in	O
their	O
recent	O
resort	O
to	O
unilateralism	O
and	O
military	O
hegemony	O
in	O
Libya	I-LOC
—	O
is	O
the	O
very	O
antithesis	O
of	O
the	O
basic	O
principles	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

In	O
the	O
case	O
of	O
Libya	I-LOC
,	O
the	O
African	I-ORG
Union	I-ORG
and	O
its	O
peacemaking	O
role	O
was	O
defied	O
,	O
ignored	O
and	O
humiliated	O
.	O

The	O
African	I-ORG
Union	I-ORG
sought	O
dialogue	O
between	O
the	O
Libyan	I-MISC
authorities	O
and	O
the	O
so-called	O
revolutionaries	O
.	O

May	O
we	O
urge	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
to	O
collectively	O
nip	O
this	O
dangerous	O
and	O
unwelcome	O
aggressive	O
development	O
in	O
the	O
bud	O
before	O
it	O
festers	O
.	O

In	O
that	O
regard	O
,	O
the	O
theme	O
that	O
the	O
President	O
has	O
chosen	O
for	O
this	O
session	O
—	O
"	O
Bringing	O
about	O
adjustment	O
or	O
settlement	O
of	O
international	O
disputes	O
or	O
situations	O
by	O
peaceful	O
means	O
"	O
—	O
is	O
very	O
appropriate	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
what	O
we	O
in	O
the	O
African	I-ORG
Union	I-ORG
stress	O
—	O
the	O
settlement	O
of	O
disputes	O
in	O
a	O
peaceful	O
way	O
,	O
through	O
dialogue	O
.	O

The	O
warmongers	O
of	O
our	O
world	O
have	O
done	O
us	O
enough	O
harm	O
.	O

Wherever	O
they	O
have	O
imposed	O
themselves	O
,	O
chaos	O
in	O
place	O
of	O
peace	O
has	O
been	O
the	O
result	O
.	O

One	O
example	O
was	O
the	O
situation	O
created	O
by	O
the	O
Bush-Blair	O
illegal	O
campaign	O
in	O
Iraq	I-LOC
—	O
an	O
illegal	O
campaign	O
undertaken	O
because	O
it	O
was	O
alleged	O
that	O
Saddam	I-PER
Hussein	I-PER
had	O
weapons	O
of	O
mass	O
destruction	O
,	O
when	O
it	O
was	O
well	O
known	O
to	O
those	O
two	O
and	O
their	O
Governments	O
that	O
he	O
did	O
not	O
have	O
such	O
weapons	O
—	O
and	O
,	O
indeed	O
,	O
after	O
invading	O
Iraq	I-LOC
,	O
creating	O
much	O
havoc	O
and	O
getting	O
rid	O
of	O
Saddam	I-PER
Hussein	I-PER
,	O
they	O
admitted	O
that	O
he	O
had	O
no	O
weapons	O
of	O
mass	O
destruction	O
.	O

So	O
why	O
had	O
they	O
attacked	O
Iraq	I-LOC
in	O
the	O
first	O
place	O
?	O

Was	O
it	O
merely	O
because	O
he	O
was	O
a	O
dictator	O
,	O
as	O
they	O
alleged	O
?	O

No	O
,	O
he	O
was	O
the	O
head	O
of	O
a	O
country	O
that	O
sat	O
on	O
tons	O
and	O
tons	O
of	O
oil	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
oil	O
they	O
required	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
saw	O
companies	O
—	O
indeed	O
,	O
one	O
such	O
company	O
was	O
headed	O
by	O
a	O
brother	O
of	O
Bush	I-PER
—	O
rushing	O
to	O
suck	O
oil	O
from	O
Iraq	I-LOC
.	O

That	O
is	O
also	O
what	O
happened	O
with	O
Libya	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
situation	O
they	O
created	O
in	O
Iraq	I-LOC
has	O
now	O
brought	O
about	O
greater	O
instability	O
than	O
there	O
ever	O
was	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
Sunnis	I-MISC
rising	O
against	O
Shias	I-MISC
,	O
and	O
vice	O
versa	O
,	O
let	O
alone	O
the	O
disastrous	O
economic	O
consequences	O
of	O
that	O
unlawful	O
invasion	O
.	O

The	O
economy	O
is	O
unstable	O
,	O
society	O
unstable	O
,	O
and	O
people	O
are	O
fighting	O
one	O
another	O
.	O

Libya	I-LOC
has	O
been	O
made	O
equally	O
unstable	O
after	O
NATO	I-ORG
's	O
deceitful	O
intervention	O
under	O
the	O
sham	O
cover	O
of	O
Chapter	I-MISC
VII	I-MISC
of	O
the	O
Charter	I-MISC
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
and	O
the	O
phony	O
principle	O
of	O
the	O
responsibility	O
to	O
protect	O
.	O

I	O
listened	O
to	O
the	O
speech	O
made	O
by	O
the	O
Secretary-General	O
.	O

He	O
made	O
reference	O
to	O
that	O
principle	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
one	O
that	O
can	O
be	O
abused	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
has	O
been	O
abused	O
.	O

And	O
,	O
anyway	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
still	O
being	O
debated	O
.	O

Zimbabwe	I-LOC
firmly	O
believes	O
in	O
the	O
peaceful	O
settlement	O
of	O
disputes	O
between	O
and	O
among	O
States	I-LOC
in	O
a	O
manner	O
that	O
is	O
consistent	O
with	O
the	O
principles	O
and	O
purposes	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

Beyond	O
deploying	O
adequate	O
resources	O
for	O
managing	O
conflicts	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
important	O
to	O
address	O
their	O
underlying	O
causes	O
,	O
and	O
to	O
pursue	O
,	O
more	O
proactively	O
,	O
a	O
comprehensive	O
approach	O
focusing	O
on	O
conflict	O
prevention	O
,	O
peacebuilding	O
,	O
peace-maintenance	O
and	O
development	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
noticed	O
,	O
with	O
deep	O
regret	O
,	O
that	O
the	O
provisions	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Charter	I-MISC
dealing	O
with	O
the	O
peaceful	O
settlement	O
of	O
disputes	O
have	O
,	O
on	O
occasion	O
,	O
been	O
ignored	O
by	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
.	O

In	O
contrast	O
,	O
there	O
appears	O
to	O
be	O
an	O
insatiable	O
appetite	O
for	O
war	O
,	O
￼	O
￼embargoes	O
,	O
sanctions	O
and	O
other	O
punitive	O
actions	O
,	O
even	O
on	O
matters	O
that	O
are	O
better	O
resolved	O
through	O
multilateral	O
cooperation	O
and	O
dialogue	O
.	O

Instead	O
of	O
resorting	O
to	O
the	O
peaceful	O
resolution	O
of	O
disputes	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
daily	O
witnessing	O
a	O
situation	O
where	O
might	O
is	O
now	O
right	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
said	O
,	O
"	O
Well	O
,	O
yes	O
,	O
those	O
who	O
are	O
powerful	O
might	O
hang	O
on	O
the	O
principle	O
that	O
might	O
is	O
right	O
"	O
,	O
but	O
certainly	O
right	O
is	O
also	O
might	O
.	O

We	O
need	O
to	O
take	O
stock	O
of	O
the	O
inspiring	O
Preamble	I-MISC
to	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Charter	I-MISC
,	O
where	O
the	O
plenipotentiaries	O
who	O
met	O
in	O
San	I-LOC
Francisco	I-LOC
in	O
1945	O
undertook	O
to	O
"	O
save	O
succeeding	O
generations	O
from	O
the	O
scourge	O
of	O
war	O
"	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
especially	O
pertinent	O
at	O
present	O
,	O
when	O
global	O
events	O
represent	O
a	O
radical	O
departure	O
from	O
that	O
solemn	O
and	O
noble	O
San	I-LOC
Francisco	I-LOC
declaration	O
.	O

What	O
do	O
the	O
NATO	I-ORG
alliance	O
members	O
have	O
to	O
say	O
about	O
that	O
,	O
one	O
may	O
ask	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
therefore	O
important	O
that	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
should	O
respect	O
and	O
support	O
the	O
decisions	O
,	O
processes	O
and	O
priorities	O
of	O
regional	O
organizations	O
.	O

In	O
contrast	O
,	O
recent	O
events	O
—	O
as	O
has	O
already	O
been	O
stated	O
—	O
particularly	O
with	O
reference	O
to	O
Africa	I-LOC
,	O
have	O
demonstrated	O
the	O
scant	O
regard	O
that	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
and	O
certain	O
powerful	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
give	O
to	O
the	O
pivotal	O
role	O
of	O
regional	O
organizations	O
.	O

Effective	O
cooperation	O
between	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
and	O
regional	O
organizations	O
will	O
become	O
viable	O
and	O
sustainable	O
only	O
when	O
developed	O
on	O
the	O
basis	O
of	O
mutual	O
respect	O
and	O
support	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
on	O
shared	O
responsibility	O
and	O
commitment	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
regrettable	O
to	O
note	O
that	O
certain	O
unacceptable	O
concepts	O
are	O
currently	O
being	O
foisted	O
on	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
membership	O
in	O
the	O
absence	O
of	O
intergovernmental	O
mandates	O
.	O

For	O
instance	O
,	O
there	O
is	O
no	O
agreement	O
yet	O
on	O
the	O
concept	O
of	O
the	O
responsibility	O
to	O
protect	O
,	O
especially	O
with	O
respect	O
to	O
the	O
circumstances	O
under	O
which	O
it	O
might	O
be	O
invoked	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
concerned	O
by	O
the	O
clear	O
and	O
growing	O
evidence	O
that	O
the	O
concept	O
of	O
responsibility	O
to	O
protect	O
has	O
begun	O
to	O
be	O
applied	O
and	O
seriously	O
abused	O
,	O
thus	O
inevitably	O
compromising	O
and	O
undermining	O
the	O
cardinal	O
principle	O
of	O
the	O
sovereignty	O
of	O
States	O
and	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Charter	O
principles	O
of	O
territorial	O
integrity	O
and	O
non-interference	O
in	O
the	O
domestic	O
affairs	O
of	O
countries	O
.	O

For	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
to	O
successfully	O
deal	O
with	O
global	O
economic	O
,	O
social	O
,	O
security	O
and	O
environmental	O
challenges	O
,	O
the	O
existence	O
of	O
international	O
institutions	O
to	O
handle	O
them	O
and	O
a	O
culture	O
of	O
genuine	O
multilateralism	O
are	O
critical	O
.	O

The	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O
its	O
specialized	O
agencies	O
and	O
international	O
financial	O
institutions	O
are	O
the	O
only	O
instruments	O
available	O
for	O
responding	O
effectively	O
to	O
the	O
global	O
challenges	O
we	O
face	O
in	O
the	O
global	O
village	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
therefore	O
critical	O
that	O
those	O
structures	O
be	O
reformed	O
and	O
realigned	O
in	O
response	O
to	O
both	O
global	O
challenges	O
and	O
our	O
contemporary	O
realities	O
,	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
enable	O
them	O
to	O
better	O
serve	O
our	O
collective	O
interests	O
.	O

This	O
Assembly	I-ORG
is	O
the	O
most	O
representative	O
organ	O
within	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
family	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
therefore	O
dedicate	O
ourselves	O
to	O
finding	O
consensus	O
on	O
measures	O
to	O
revitalize	O
it	O
so	O
that	O
it	O
fulfils	O
its	O
mandate	O
in	O
accordance	O
with	O
the	O
provisions	O
of	O
the	O
Charter	I-MISC
.	O

We	O
wish	O
to	O
reiterate	O
our	O
deep	O
concern	O
that	O
the	O
mandate	O
,	O
powers	O
and	O
jurisdiction	O
of	O
the	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
are	O
shrinking	O
as	O
a	O
consequence	O
of	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
's	O
gradual	O
encroachment	O
on	O
the	O
Assembly	I-ORG
's	O
areas	O
of	O
competence	O
.	O

That	O
,	O
in	O
our	O
view	O
,	O
upsets	O
the	O
delicate	O
balance	O
envisaged	O
under	O
the	O
Charter	I-MISC
and	O
undermines	O
the	O
overall	O
effectiveness	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
system	O
.	O

The	O
General	I-ORG
Assembly	I-ORG
must	O
remain	O
the	O
main	O
deliberative	O
,	O
policy-making	O
organ	O
of	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
.	O

We	O
have	O
been	O
seized	O
with	O
the	O
debate	O
on	O
the	O
reform	O
of	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
for	O
far	O
too	O
long	O
.	O

My	O
delegation	O
fully	O
supports	O
the	O
current	O
intergovernmental	O
negotiations	O
on	O
the	O
reform	O
and	O
expansion	O
of	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
.	O

However	O
,	O
we	O
wish	O
to	O
caution	O
against	O
an	O
open-ended	O
approach	O
that	O
short-changes	O
those	O
of	O
us	O
from	O
regions	O
that	O
are	O
not	O
represented	O
at	O
all	O
among	O
the	O
permanent	O
membership	O
of	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
.	O

Zimbabwe	I-LOC
stands	O
by	O
Africa	I-LOC
's	O
demand	O
for	O
two	O
permanent	O
seats	O
,	O
complete	O
with	O
a	O
veto	O
if	O
the	O
veto	O
is	O
to	O
be	O
retained	O
,	O
plus	O
two	O
additional	O
non-permanent	O
seats	O
,	O
as	O
clearly	O
articulated	O
in	O
the	O
Ezulwini	I-MISC
Consensus	I-MISC
and	O
the	O
Sirte	I-LOC
Declaration	I-MISC
.	O

For	O
how	O
long	O
will	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
continue	O
to	O
ignore	O
the	O
aspirations	O
of	O
a	O
whole	O
continent	O
of	O
54	O
countries	O
?	O

We	O
shall	O
not	O
be	O
bought	O
off	O
with	O
empty	O
promises	O
,	O
nor	O
shall	O
we	O
accept	O
some	O
cosmetic	O
tinkering	O
with	O
the	O
Security	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
disguised	O
as	O
reform	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
indeed	O
a	O
travesty	O
of	O
justice	O
that	O
the	O
African	I-MISC
continent	O
,	O
which	O
accounts	O
for	O
almost	O
a	O
third	O
of	O
the	O
membership	O
represented	O
in	O
this	O
Assembly	I-ORG
,	O
has	O
no	O
permanent	O
representation	O
in	O
the	O
Council	I-ORG
.	O

Is	O
that	O
good	O
governance	O
?	O

Is	O
that	O
democracy	O
?	O

And	O
is	O
that	O
justice	O
?	O

My	O
delegation	O
condemns	O
unreservedly	O
the	O
economic	O
sanctions	O
imposed	O
against	O
my	O
country	O
and	O
people	O
in	O
an	O
unjustified	O
effort	O
to	O
deny	O
them	O
the	O
chance	O
to	O
fully	O
benefit	O
from	O
their	O
natural	O
resource	O
endowment	O
.	O

We	O
wish	O
to	O
remind	O
those	O
who	O
have	O
maintained	O
sanctions	O
against	O
us	O
that	O
there	O
is	O
international	O
consensus	O
—	O
fully	O
supported	O
by	O
the	O
Southern	I-ORG
African	I-ORG
Development	I-ORG
Community	I-ORG
,	O
the	O
African	I-ORG
Union	I-ORG
,	O
the	O
Non-Aligned	I-ORG
Movement	I-ORG
and	O
the	O
rest	O
of	O
the	O
progressive	O
world	O
—	O
that	O
these	O
sanctions	O
must	O
go	O
.	O

We	O
hope	O
they	O
will	O
go	O
.	O

Allow	O
me	O
to	O
conclude	O
by	O
reaffirming	O
Zimbabwe	I-LOC
's	O
commitment	O
to	O
the	O
principles	O
that	O
have	O
brought	O
us	O
together	O
in	O
the	O
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
for	O
the	O
last	O
67	O
years	O
.	O

My	O
country	O
is	O
confident	O
that	O
in	O
this	O
inextricably	O
interdependent	O
world	O
,	O
our	O
commitment	O
to	O
the	O
common	O
good	O
,	O
which	O
the	O
Organization	O
embodies	O
,	O
will	O
be	O
resolute	O
and	O
enduring	O
.	O

Zimbabwe	I-LOC
will	O
continue	O
to	O
stand	O
firm	O
and	O
to	O
condemn	O
unilateralism	O
,	O
the	O
imposition	O
of	O
unwarranted	O
and	O
illegal	O
sanctions	O
on	O
nations	O
and	O
the	O
unwarranted	O
extraterritorial	O
application	O
of	O
national	O
laws	O
.	O
