It	PRON	O
gives	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
pleasure	NOUN	O
,	.	O
at	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
forum	NOUN	O
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
greet	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
brothers	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
friends	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
Heads	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
State	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Government	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
delegations	NOUN	O
represented	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
Hall	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
hope	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
meetings	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
sixty-sixth	NOUN	O
session	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
General	NOUN	I-ORG
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
fruitful	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
result	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
concrete	NOUN	O
outcome	NOUN	O
commensurate	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
aspirations	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
global	ADJ	O
environment	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
stability	NOUN	O
,	.	O
security	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
lasting	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
good	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
well-being	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
humanity	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
large	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
pleased	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
see	NOUN	O
yet	NOUN	O
another	NOUN	O
diplomat	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Gulf	NOUN	I-ORG
Cooperation	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
presiding	NOUN	O
over	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
General	NOUN	I-ORG
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
take	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
opportunity	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
offer	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
sincere	NOUN	O
wishes	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
every	DET	O
success	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
Ambassador	NOUN	O
Nassir	NOUN	I-PER
Abdulaziz	NOUN	I-PER
Al-	NOUN	I-PER
Nasser	NOUN	I-PER
in	ADP	O
his	PRON	O
international	NOUN	O
mission	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
of	ADP	O
further	NOUN	O
progress	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
advancement	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
levels	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
his	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
brotherly	NOUN	O
State	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Qatar	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
also	ADV	O
thank	NOUN	O
his	PRON	O
predecessor	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Mr.	NOUN	O
Joseph	NOUN	I-PER
Deiss	NOUN	I-PER
,	.	O
for	NOUN	O
his	PRON	O
able	NOUN	O
conduct	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
and	CONJ	O
contributions	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
work	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
General	NOUN	I-ORG
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
at	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
sixty-fifth	NOUN	O
session	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
also	ADV	O
seize	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
opportunity	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
congratulate	VERB	O
him	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
his	PRON	O
reappointment	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
second	NOUN	O
term	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
office	NOUN	O
.	.	O

There	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
no	DET	O
doubt	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
entered	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
era	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
important	NOUN	O
changes	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
which	DET	O
the	DET	O
growth	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
modern	NOUN	O
means	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
communication	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
led	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
rapid	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
unprecedented	NOUN	O
transformations	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
,	.	O
such	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
now	ADV	O
experiencing	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
Arab	NOUN	I-MISC
region	NOUN	O
.	.	O

More	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
decade	NOUN	O
ago	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Kingdom	NOUN	I-LOC
of	ADP	I-LOC
Bahrain	NOUN	I-LOC
recognized	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
need	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
proceed	NOUN	O
towards	NOUN	O
greater	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
,	.	O
improvement	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
advancement	NOUN	O
,	.	O
bearing	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
mind	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
supreme	NOUN	O
interest	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
,	.	O
in	ADP	O
order	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
satisfy	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
demands	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
freedom	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
political	NOUN	O
participation	NOUN	O
—	.	O
a	DET	O
home-grown	NOUN	O
participation	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
commensurate	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
heritage	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
history	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
each	NOUN	O
country	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
its	NOUN	O
level	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
development	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Reform	NOUN	O
was	VERB	O
also	ADV	O
aimed	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
providing	NOUN	O
decent	NOUN	O
living	NOUN	O
conditions	NOUN	O
,	.	O
security	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
tranquillity	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
society	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
enjoys	NOUN	O
peaceful	NOUN	O
coexistence	NOUN	O
,	.	O
equality	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
equal	NOUN	O
opportunities	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
empowerment	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
justice	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
sustainable	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
modernization	NOUN	O
endeavours	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
throughout	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
long	NOUN	O
history	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
Kingdom	NOUN	I-LOC
of	ADP	I-LOC
Bahrain	NOUN	I-LOC
has	NOUN	O
persistently	NOUN	O
followed	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
approach	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
dialogue	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Building	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
consensus	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
people	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Bahrain	NOUN	I-LOC
around	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
provisions	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
National	NOUN	I-ORG
Action	NOUN	I-ORG
Charter	NOUN	I-ORG
of	ADP	O
2001	NUM	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
initiated	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
national	NOUN	O
dialogue	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
involving	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
sectors	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
components	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
population	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
aim	NOUN	O
was	VERB	O
to	NOUN	O
absorb	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
requirements	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
modern	NOUN	O
progress	NOUN	O
,	.	O
guarantee	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
continuation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
reform	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
fulfil	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
national	NOUN	O
aspiration	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
move	NOUN	O
forward	NOUN	O
towards	NOUN	O
comprehensive	NOUN	O
modernization	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
enhancement	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
popular	NOUN	O
participation	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
decision-making	NOUN	O
within	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
all-inclusive	NOUN	O
national	NOUN	O
partnership	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
hereby	NOUN	O
reaffirm	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
outcome	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
that	NOUN	O
dialogue	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
achievements	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Kingdom	NOUN	I-LOC
of	ADP	I-LOC
Bahrain	NOUN	I-LOC
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
national	NOUN	O
level	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
therefore	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
extension	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
long	NOUN	O
history	NOUN	O
dating	NOUN	O
back	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
beginning	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
last	NOUN	O
century	NOUN	O
,	.	O
in	ADP	O
which	DET	O
we	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
worked	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
society	NOUN	O
based	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
justice	NOUN	O
,	.	O
equality	NOUN	O
,	.	O
progress	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
openness	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
authenticity	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
,	.	O
culture	NOUN	O
,	.	O
free	NOUN	O
economy	NOUN	O
,	.	O
political	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
firm	NOUN	O
commitment	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
universal	NOUN	O
principles	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
,	.	O
peaceful	NOUN	O
coexistence	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
respect	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
views	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
others	NOUN	O
constitute	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
real	NOUN	O
wealth	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
country	NOUN	O
,	.	O
which	DET	O
we	PRON	O
seek	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
preserve	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
sustain	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
future	NOUN	O
generations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Today	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
ever	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
propitious	NOUN	O
opportunity	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
do	NOUN	O
justice	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
brotherly	NOUN	O
Palestinian	NOUN	I-MISC
people	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
help	NOUN	O
them	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
legitimate	NOUN	O
aspirations	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
recognizing	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
independent	NOUN	O
Palestinian	NOUN	I-MISC
State	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
their	PRON	O
own	NOUN	O
national	NOUN	O
soil	NOUN	O
,	.	O
with	ADP	O
East	NOUN	I-LOC
Jerusalem	NOUN	I-LOC
as	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
capital	NOUN	O
.	.	O

That	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
put	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
end	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
era	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
bitter	NOUN	O
Arab-Israeli	NOUN	I-MISC
conflict	NOUN	O
,	.	O
contingent	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
a	DET	O
complete	NOUN	O
Israeli	NOUN	I-MISC
withdrawal	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
occupied	NOUN	O
Arab	NOUN	O
territories	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
lines	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
4	NUM	O
June	NOUN	O
1967	NUM	O
in	ADP	O
Palestine	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
the	DET	O
occupied	NOUN	O
Syrian	NOUN	I-LOC
Arab	NOUN	I-LOC
Golan	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
occupied	NOUN	O
territories	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
southern	NOUN	O
Lebanon	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
in	ADP	O
accordance	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
relevant	NOUN	O
resolutions	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
international	NOUN	O
legitimacy	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
Arab	NOUN	I-MISC
Peace	NOUN	I-MISC
Initiative	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

Committed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
security	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Arabian	NOUN	I-MISC
Gulf	NOUN	I-MISC
region	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
emphasize	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
need	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
resolve	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
issue	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
three	NOUN	O
occupied	NOUN	O
United	NOUN	I-LOC
Arab	NOUN	I-LOC
Emirates	NOUN	I-LOC
islands	NOUN	O
,	.	O
either	NOUN	O
through	NOUN	O
direct	NOUN	O
negotiations	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
by	ADP	O
referral	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
International	NOUN	I-ORG
Court	NOUN	I-ORG
of	ADP	I-ORG
Justice	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

With	ADP	O
regard	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
developments	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
brotherly	NOUN	O
State	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Yemen	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
the	DET	O
Kingdom	NOUN	I-LOC
of	ADP	I-LOC
Bahrain	NOUN	I-LOC
supports	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Gulf	NOUN	I-ORG
Cooperation	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
initiative	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
maintaining	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
security	NOUN	O
,	.	O
stability	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
unity	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
that	NOUN	O
country	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
achieving	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
aspirations	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Consistent	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
commitment	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
concerted	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
action	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
its	NOUN	O
role	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
responsibilities	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
region	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
Kingdom	NOUN	I-LOC
of	ADP	I-LOC
Bahrain	NOUN	I-LOC
has	NOUN	O
never	NOUN	O
hesitated	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
contribute	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
participate	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Contact	NOUN	I-ORG
Group	NOUN	I-ORG
on	ADP	O
Libya	NOUN	I-LOC
in	ADP	O
order	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
help	NOUN	O
realize	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
aspirations	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Libyan	NOUN	I-MISC
people	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
ensure	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
country	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
unity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
territorial	NOUN	O
integrity	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bahrain	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
also	ADV	O
participating	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
peacekeeping	NOUN	O
forces	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Afghanistan	NOUN	I-LOC
in	ADP	O
order	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
country	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
stability	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
security	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
every	DET	O
sphere	NOUN	O
—political	NOUN	O
,	.	O
economic	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
security	NOUN	O
—	.	O
as	NOUN	O
well	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
fight	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
piracy	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
high	NOUN	O
seas	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Their	PRON	O
resilience	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
determination	NOUN	O
,	.	O
however	NOUN	O
,	.	O
have	NOUN	O
helped	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
safer	NOUN	O
place	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
believe	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
humankind	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
general	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
much	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
gain	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
global	ADJ	O
level	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
contributions	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Arab-	NOUN	I-MISC
Islamic	NOUN	I-MISC
civilization	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
other	NOUN	O
civilizations	NOUN	O
throughout	NOUN	O
history	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Arab	NOUN	I-MISC
Muslims	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
Christians	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
Jews	NOUN	I-MISC
and	CONJ	O
other	NOUN	O
followers	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
other	NOUN	O
religions	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
beliefs	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
coexist	NOUN	O
only	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
state	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
civility	NOUN	O
based	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
tolerance	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
speak	NOUN	O
here	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
light	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
experience	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
country	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Bahrain	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
which	DET	O
,	.	O
with	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
characteristic	NOUN	O
openness	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
civilization	NOUN	O
deeply	NOUN	O
rooted	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
history	NOUN	O
,	.	O
has	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
time	NOUN	O
immemorial	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
symbol	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
coexistence	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
interaction	NOUN	O
between	NOUN	O
these	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
contributions	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Hence	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
position	NOUN	O
since	NOUN	O
early	ADV	O
times	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
cultural	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
spiritual	NOUN	O
centre	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
natural	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
human	NOUN	O
environment	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Arabian	NOUN	I-MISC
Gulf	NOUN	I-MISC
—	.	O
a	DET	O
position	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
which	DET	O
it	PRON	O
has	NOUN	O
built	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
civil	NOUN	O
society	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
fomented	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
modern	NOUN	O
renaissance	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
areas	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
administrative	NOUN	O
organization	NOUN	O
,	.	O
economic	NOUN	O
activity	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
an	DET	O
educational	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
cultural	NOUN	O
enlightenment	NOUN	O
.	.	O

While	CONJ	O
Bahrain	NOUN	I-LOC
appreciates	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
support	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
its	NOUN	O
specialized	NOUN	O
agencies	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
achievements	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
evidenced	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
numerous	NOUN	O
awards	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
has	NOUN	O
won	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
various	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
social	NOUN	O
fields	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
stress	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
great	NOUN	O
importance	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
global	ADJ	O
issues	NOUN	O
discussed	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
annual	NOUN	O
report	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
work	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Organization	NOUN	O
(A/66/1)	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
convinced	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
imperative	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
Member	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
cooperate	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
issues	NOUN	O
such	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
climate	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
,	.	O
international	NOUN	O
health	NOUN	O
,	.	O
drought	NOUN	O
,	.	O
poverty	NOUN	O
alleviation	NOUN	O
,	.	O
disarmament	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
non-proliferation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
nuclear	NOUN	O
weapons	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
fight	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
.	.	O

This	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
more	NOUN	O
urgent	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
ever	NOUN	O
before	NOUN	O
,	.	O
given	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
scale	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
challenges	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
problems	NOUN	O
facing	NOUN	O
humankind	NOUN	O
,	.	O
so	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
can	NOUN	O
create	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
world	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
security	NOUN	O
,	.	O
peace	NOUN	O
,	.	O
tranquillity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
prosperity	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
conclusion	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
reaffirm	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
commitment	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
principles	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
purposes	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
its	NOUN	O
constructive	NOUN	O
role	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
consolidating	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
,	.	O
love	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
prosperity	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
.	.	O
