In	ADP	O
1981	NUM	O
,	.	O
today	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
date	NOUN	O
,	.	O
21	NUM	O
September	NOUN	O
,	.	O
was	VERB	O
proclaimed	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
International	NOUN	I-MISC
Day	NOUN	I-MISC
of	ADP	I-MISC
Peace	NOUN	I-MISC
to	NOUN	O
promote	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
negotiated	NOUN	O
solution	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
armed	NOUN	O
conflicts	NOUN	O
throughout	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Since	NOUN	O
1982	NUM	O
,	.	O
one	NOUN	O
year	NOUN	O
later	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
has	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
a	DET	O
long	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
difficult	NOUN	O
road	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
leave	NOUN	O
violence	NOUN	O
behind	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
attain	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
.	.	O

My	PRON	O
predecessors	NOUN	O
pursued	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
Colombians	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
each	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
his	PRON	O
own	NOUN	O
way	NOUN	O
.	.	O

This	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
task	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
I	NOUN	O
undertook	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
first	NOUN	O
day	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
my	PRON	O
Government	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
August	NOUN	O
2010	NUM	O
.	.	O
I	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
come	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
speak	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
members	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
on	ADP	O
seven	NOUN	O
occasions	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
progress	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
expectations	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
peace	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
between	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Government	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
Fuerzas	NOUN	I-ORG
Armadas	NOUN	I-ORG
Revolucionarias	NOUN	I-ORG
de	NOUN	I-ORG
Colombia	NOUN	I-ORG
(FARC)	NOUN	I-ORG
guerrilla	NOUN	O
group	NOUN	O
—	.	O
the	DET	O
largest	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
oldest	NOUN	O
such	NOUN	O
group	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
American	NOUN	I-MISC
continent	NOUN	O
.	.	O

A	DET	O
year	NOUN	O
ago	NOUN	O
,	.	O
standing	NOUN	O
here	NOUN	O
before	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
(see	NOUN	O
A/70/PV	NOUN	O
.	.	O
16)	NOUN	O
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
said	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
I	NOUN	O
expected	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
return	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
2016	NUM	O
as	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
President	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
in	ADP	O
peace	NOUN	O
—	.	O
a	DET	O
reconciled	NOUN	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O
After	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
half	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
century	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
internal	NOUN	O
armed	NOUN	O
conflict	NOUN	O
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
return	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
today	NOUN	O
,	.	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
International	NOUN	I-MISC
Day	NOUN	I-MISC
of	ADP	I-MISC
Peace	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
announce	NOUN	O
,	.	O
with	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
strength	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
my	PRON	O
voice	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
heart	NOUN	O
,	.	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
war	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
has	NOUN	O
ended	NOUN	O
.	.	O

On	ADP	O
24	NUM	O
August	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Havana	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
the	DET	O
negotiators	NOUN	O
declared	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
provisions	NOUN	O
were	NOUN	O
complete	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
adopted	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
final	NOUN	O
text	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
General	NOUN	I-MISC
Agreement	NOUN	I-MISC
for	NOUN	I-MISC
the	DET	I-MISC
Termination	NOUN	I-MISC
of	ADP	I-MISC
the	DET	I-MISC
Conflict	NOUN	I-MISC
and	CONJ	I-MISC
the	DET	I-MISC
Construction	NOUN	I-MISC
of	ADP	I-MISC
a	DET	I-MISC
Stable	NOUN	I-MISC
and	CONJ	I-MISC
Lasting	NOUN	I-MISC
Peace	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

Five	NOUN	O
days	NOUN	O
later	NOUN	O
,	.	O
a	DET	O
bilateral	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
definitive	NOUN	O
ceasefire	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
cessation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
hostilities	NOUN	O
took	NOUN	O
place	NOUN	O
.	.	O

As	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
result	NOUN	O
,	.	O
since	NOUN	O
then	NOUN	O
there	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
single	NOUN	O
death	NOUN	O
,	.	O
a	DET	O
single	NOUN	O
wound	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
a	DET	O
single	NOUN	O
bullet	NOUN	O
fired	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
conflict	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
FARC	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O
The	DET	O
Agreement	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
officially	NOUN	O
signed	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Cartagena	NOUN	I-LOC
de	NOUN	I-LOC
Indias	NOUN	I-LOC
on	ADP	O
26	NUM	O
September	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
people	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
approve	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
through	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
plebiscite	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
2	NUM	O
October	NOUN	O
.	.	O

From	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
moment	NOUN	O
forward	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
former	NOUN	O
members	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
guerrilla	NOUN	O
group	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
go	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
different	NOUN	O
cantonment	NOUN	O
areas	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
begin	NOUN	O
surrendering	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
arms	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
within	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
six-month	NOUN	O
period	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
begin	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
reintegration	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
society	NOUN	O
.	.	O
Their	PRON	O
weapons	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
melted	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
made	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
three	NOUN	O
monuments	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
—	.	O
one	NOUN	O
here	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
New	ADJ	I-LOC
York	NOUN	I-LOC
;	.	O
one	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Cuba	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
where	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
peace	NOUN	O
negotiations	NOUN	O
took	NOUN	O
place	NOUN	O
;	.	O
and	CONJ	O
another	NOUN	O
one	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

These	NOUN	O
monuments	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
remind	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
bullets	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
behind	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
and	CONJ	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
construction	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
and	CONJ	O
better	NOUN	O
country	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
begun	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Joyfully	NOUN	O
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
reiterate	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
last	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
oldest	NOUN	O
armed	NOUN	O
conflict	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
western	NOUN	O
hemisphere	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
come	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
end	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Americas	NOUN	I-LOC
—	.	O
the	DET	O
two	NOUN	O
vast	NOUN	O
American	NOUN	I-MISC
continents	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
their	PRON	O
islands	NOUN	O
,	.	O
from	NOUN	O
Patagonia	NOUN	I-LOC
to	NOUN	O
Alaska	NOUN	I-LOC
—	.	O
are	VERB	O
now	ADV	O
a	DET	O
region	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
peace	NOUN	O
.	.	O
The	DET	O
Agreement	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
was	VERB	O
reached	NOUN	O
after	NOUN	O
almost	NOUN	O
six	NOUN	O
years	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
public	NOUN	O
conversations	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
best	NOUN	O
news	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Latin	NOUN	I-LOC
America	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
.	.	O

What	NOUN	O
does	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Agreement	NOUN	O
mean	NOUN	O
?	.	O

Above	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
means	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
FARC	NOUN	I-ORG
will	VERB	O
cease	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
exist	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
armed	NOUN	O
group	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
reintegrate	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
society	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
can	NOUN	O
become	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
political	NOUN	O
movement	NOUN	O
within	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
democracy	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
agreed	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
measures	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
guarantee	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
political	NOUN	O
participation	NOUN	O
,	.	O
offer	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
assurances	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
opposition	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
strengthen	NOUN	O
democracy	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
electoral	NOUN	O
system	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O
We	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
outlined	NOUN	O
programmes	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
improve	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
quality	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
life	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
rural	NOUN	O
inhabitants	NOUN	O
,	.	O
who	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
most	DET	O
affected	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
conflict	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
land	NOUN	O
available	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
who	NOUN	O
do	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
or	CONJ	O
who	NOUN	O
lost	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
because	CONJ	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
war	NOUN	O
.	.	O

A	DET	O
central	NOUN	O
aspect	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
that	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
has	NOUN	O
focused	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
protection	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
guarantee	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
rights	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
victims:	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
rights	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
truth	NOUN	O
,	.	O
justice	NOUN	O
,	.	O
reparations	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
non-repetition	NOUN	O
.	.	O

To	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
end	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
agreed	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
such	NOUN	O
mechanisms	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
truth	NOUN	O
commission	NOUN	O
,	.	O
reparation	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
restoration	NOUN	O
measures	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
a	DET	O
comprehensive	NOUN	O
transitional	NOUN	O
justice	NOUN	O
system	NOUN	O
.	.	O
This	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
first	NOUN	O
time	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
history	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
resolution	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
armed	NOUN	O
conflicts	NOUN	O
anywhere	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
Government	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
an	DET	O
illegal	NOUN	O
armed	NOUN	O
group	NOUN	O
—	.	O
through	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
agreement	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
not	NOUN	O
through	NOUN	O
external	NOUN	O
imposition	NOUN	O
—	.	O
have	NOUN	O
agreed	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
transitional	NOUN	O
justice	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
perpetrators	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
international	NOUN	O
crimes	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
other	NOUN	O
serious	NOUN	O
crimes	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
investigated	NOUN	O
,	.	O
judged	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
punished	NOUN	O
.	.	O

This	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
positively	NOUN	O
highlighted	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Prosecutor	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
International	NOUN	I-ORG
Criminal	NOUN	I-ORG
Court	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
the	DET	O
Inter-American	NOUN	I-ORG
Commission	NOUN	I-ORG
on	ADP	I-ORG
Human	NOUN	I-ORG
Rights	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
many	NOUN	O
other	NOUN	O
organizations	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
experts	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
sure	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
model	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
justice	NOUN	O
,	.	O
which	DET	O
is	VERB	O
framed	NOUN	O
within	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
comprehensive	NOUN	O
system	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
guarantee	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
rights	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
victims	NOUN	O
—	.	O
as	NOUN	O
established	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Rome	NOUN	I-LOC
Statute	NOUN	I-MISC
—	.	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
useful	NOUN	O
precedent	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
future	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
processes	NOUN	O
.	.	O
I	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
highlight	NOUN	O
another	NOUN	O
aspect	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Agreement	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
know	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
drug	NOUN	O
trafficking	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
fueled	NOUN	O
war	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
around	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Thanks	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Agreement	NOUN	O
,	.	O
FARC	NOUN	I-ORG
is	VERB	O
committed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
severing	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
ties	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
activity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
cooperating	NOUN	O
,	.	O
through	NOUN	O
concrete	NOUN	O
actions	NOUN	O
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
combat	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
phenomenon	NOUN	O
.	.	O

This	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
highly	NOUN	O
symbolic	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
who	NOUN	O
once	NOUN	O
protected	NOUN	O
illicit	NOUN	O
coca	NOUN	O
crops	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
now	ADV	O
work	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
State	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
eradicating	NOUN	O
them	NOUN	O
.	.	O
A	DET	O
similar	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
place	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
regard	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
anti-personnel	NOUN	O
mines	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
killed	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
mutilated	NOUN	O
so	NOUN	O
many	NOUN	O
soldiers	NOUN	O
,	.	O
police	NOUN	O
officers	NOUN	O
,	.	O
farmers	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
children	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
State	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
FARC	NOUN	I-ORG
will	VERB	O
work	NOUN	O
jointly	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
demine	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
national	NOUN	O
territory	NOUN	O
.	.	O

That	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
also	ADV	O
have	NOUN	O
significant	NOUN	O
environmental	NOUN	O
benefits	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
only	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
country	NOUN	O
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
also	ADV	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
planet	NOUN	O
.	.	O

To	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
extent	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
illegal	NOUN	O
crops	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
replaced	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
legal	NOUN	O
ones	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
deforestation	NOUN	O
caused	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
coca	NOUN	O
cultivation	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
stop	NOUN	O
.	.	O

No	DET	O
longer	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
millions	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
barrels	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
oil	NOUN	O
spill	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
rivers	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
oceans	NOUN	O
because	CONJ	O
of	ADP	O
attacks	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
oil	NOUN	O
infrastructure	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
able	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
better	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
care	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
and	CONJ	O
preserve	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
natural	NOUN	O
lung	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
Amazon	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O
A	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
greets	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
today	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
full	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
hope	NOUN	O
,	.	O
a	DET	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
that	NOUN	O
,	.	O
without	NOUN	O
war	NOUN	O
,	.	O
is	VERB	O
ready	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
reach	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
highest	NOUN	O
potential	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
positive	NOUN	O
factor	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
global	ADJ	O
context	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
where	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
resources	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
used	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
finance	NOUN	O
war	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
now	ADV	O
be	NOUN	O
better	NOUN	O
used	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
education	NOUN	O
,	.	O
health	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
security	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
citizens	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
that	NOUN	O
opens	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
arms	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
welcomes	NOUN	O
investment	NOUN	O
,	.	O
trade	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
tourism	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Sustainable	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
Goals	NOUN	I-MISC
have	NOUN	O
already	ADV	O
been	NOUN	O
adopted	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
law	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
country	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
were	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
first	NOUN	O
country	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
do	NOUN	O
so	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Paris	NOUN	I-LOC
Agreement	NOUN	I-MISC
on	ADP	I-MISC
Climate	NOUN	I-MISC
Change	NOUN	I-MISC
is	VERB	O
now	ADV	O
before	NOUN	O
Congress	NOUN	I-ORG
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
enacted	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
law	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Peace	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
undoubtedly	NOUN	O
allow	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
these	NOUN	O
transformative	NOUN	O
commitments	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
greater	NOUN	O
ease	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
effectiveness	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Today	NOUN	O
,	.	O
on	ADP	O
behalf	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
almost	NOUN	O
50	NUM	O
million	NOUN	O
Colombians	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
express	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
deepest	NOUN	O
gratitude	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
ongoing	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
tireless	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
thank	NOUN	O
Cuba	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
the	DET	O
host	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
dialogues	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
Norway	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
which	DET	O
were	NOUN	O
guarantors	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
peace	NOUN	O
negotiations	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
well	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
Chile	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
Venezuela	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
which	DET	O
accompanied	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
entire	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
thank	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-LOC
States	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Germany	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
European	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
which	DET	O
appointed	NOUN	O
special	ADJ	O
envoys	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
accompany	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
dialogues	NOUN	O
.	.	O
We	PRON	O
especially	NOUN	O
thank	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
Ban	NOUN	I-PER
Ki-moon	NOUN	I-PER
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
which	DET	O
established	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
political	NOUN	O
mission	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
lead	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
monitoring	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
verification	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
ceasefire	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
disarmament	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
guerrillas	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
had	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
opportunity	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
thank	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
personally	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
few	NOUN	O
moments	NOUN	O
ago	NOUN	O
(see	NOUN	O
S/PV	NOUN	O
.	.	O
7773)	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
thank	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
countries	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Latin	NOUN	I-LOC
America	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
Caribbean	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
all	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
which	DET	O
supported	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
profoundly	NOUN	O
grateful	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
so	NOUN	O
many	NOUN	O
Governments	NOUN	O
,	.	O
countries	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
organizations	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
continuously	NOUN	O
expressed	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
solidarity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
willingness	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
challenging	NOUN	O
post-conflict	NOUN	O
phase	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
lies	NOUN	O
ahead	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
us	PRON	O
.	.	O
I	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
say	NOUN	O
today	NOUN	O
,	.	O
in	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
historic	NOUN	O
Hall	NOUN	O
,	.	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
succeeded	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
Colombians	NOUN	I-MISC
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
turning	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
page	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
war	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
start	NOUN	O
writing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
chapter	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
peace	NOUN	O
.	.	O

That	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
what	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
wish	VERB	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
rest	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
planet	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Therefore	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
offer	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
full	NOUN	O
solidarity	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
nations	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
suffered	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
suffer	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
scourge	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
global	ADJ	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
example	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
should	NOUN	O
give	NOUN	O
hope	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
possible	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
dream	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
peace	NOUN	O
when	NOUN	O
there	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
will	VERB	O
and	CONJ	O
commitment	NOUN	O
.	.	O
To	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
end	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
first	NOUN	O
disarm	NOUN	O
spirits	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
language	NOUN	O
,	.	O
because	CONJ	O
words	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
harmful	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
bombs	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
and	CONJ	O
protect	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
victims	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
most	DET	O
vulnerable	NOUN	O
,	.	O
including	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
thousands	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
human	NOUN	O
beings	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
flee	NOUN	O
war	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
seek	NOUN	O
opportunities	NOUN	O
beyond	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
borders	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
more	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
ready	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
continue	NOUN	O
supporting	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
raison	NOUN	O
d'être	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
—	.	O
the	DET	O
search	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
.	.	O
As	NOUN	O
President	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Colombians	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
am	VERB	O
happy	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
humbly	NOUN	O
excited	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
announce	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
the	DET	O
peace	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

A	DET	O
conflict	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
over	NOUN	O
half	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
century	NOUN	O
—	.	O
a	DET	O
conflict	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
left	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
220	NUM	O
,000	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
dead	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
claimed	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
8	NUM	O
million	NOUN	O
victims	NOUN	O
—	.	O
has	NOUN	O
come	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
end	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
bells	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
peace	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
ringing	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
their	PRON	O
echo	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
heard	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
nations	NOUN	O
represented	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
Hall	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
do	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
want	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
war	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
do	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
want	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
wars	NOUN	O
,	.	O
not	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
not	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
rest	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Today	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
reason	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
hope	NOUN	O
.	.	O

There	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
one	NOUN	O
less	NOUN	O
war	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
planet	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
that	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
war	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Colombia	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O
