Sir	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
with	ADP	O
great	NOUN	O
pleasure	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
I	NOUN	O
congratulate	VERB	O
you	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
your	NOUN	O
election	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
President	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
fifty-ninth	NOUN	O
session	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
General	NOUN	I-ORG
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
living	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
trying	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
turbulent	NOUN	O
times	NOUN	O
.	.	O

As	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
meet	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
continues	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
haunted	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
spectre	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
most	DET	O
recently	NOUN	O
evidenced	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Russia	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

The	DET	O
victims	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
always	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
innocent	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
objective	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
global	ADJ	O
instability	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
insecurity	NOUN	O
,	.	O
leading	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
increased	NOUN	O
intolerance	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
social	NOUN	O
regression	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
hideousness	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
means	NOUN	O
employed	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
terrorists	NOUN	O
exposes	NOUN	O
them	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
what	NOUN	O
they	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
.	.	O

No	DET	O
just	NOUN	O
political	NOUN	O
cause	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
served	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
such	NOUN	O
acts	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
war	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
struggle	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
barbarism	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
perpetrators	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
terror	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
rooted	NOUN	O
out	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
their	PRON	O
bases	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
networks	NOUN	O
destroyed	NOUN	O
.	.	O

This	NOUN	O
war	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
inherently	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
campaign	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
support	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
values	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
—	.	O
the	DET	O
values	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
all	NOUN	O
seek	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
foster	NOUN	O
—	.	O
and	CONJ	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
in	ADP	O
response	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
threat	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
serious	NOUN	O
implications	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Member	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
Organization	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

Our	NOUN	O
challenge	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
actively	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
defend	NOUN	O
freedom	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
forces	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
tyranny	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
affect	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
conditions	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
help	NOUN	O
create	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
spectre	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
.	.	O

If	CONJ	O
anyone	NOUN	O
thought	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
threats	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
global	ADJ	O
security	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
provided	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
impetus	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
looking	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
serious	NOUN	O
reforms	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
system	NOUN	O
had	NOUN	O
receded	NOUN	O
,	.	O
then	NOUN	O
surely	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
recent	NOUN	O
terrorist	NOUN	O
outrage	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
southern	NOUN	O
Russia	NOUN	I-LOC
gives	NOUN	O
pause	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
reflection	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
great	NOUN	O
challenges	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Afghanistan	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
well	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
parts	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
considerable	NOUN	O
work	NOUN	O
still	ADV	O
remaining	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Millennium	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
Goals	NOUN	I-MISC
testify	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
fact	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
need	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
passed	NOUN	O
.	.	O

On	ADP	O
the	DET	O
contrary	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
High-level	NOUN	I-MISC
Panel	NOUN	I-MISC
will	VERB	O
soon	NOUN	O
submit	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
report	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
next	NOUN	O
year	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
summit	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
planned	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
sixtieth	NOUN	O
anniversary	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
fifth	NOUN	O
year	NOUN	O
after	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Millennium	NOUN	I-MISC
Summit	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

Iceland	NOUN	I-LOC
believes	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
now	ADV	O
have	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
historic	NOUN	O
opportunity	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
undertake	NOUN	O
meaningful	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
long-awaited	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
.	.	O

This	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
in	ADP	O
no	DET	O
small	NOUN	O
way	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
reinforcement	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
idea	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
multilateralism	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
,	.	O
if	CONJ	O
genuine	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
far-sighted	NOUN	O
,	.	O
will	VERB	O
equip	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
to	NOUN	O
deal	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
effectively	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
threats	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
global	ADJ	O
security	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
weighty	NOUN	O
responsibility	NOUN	O
here	NOUN	O
next	NOUN	O
year	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
hammer	NOUN	O
out	NOUN	O
decisions	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
reform	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
have	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
opportunity	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
changes	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
equip	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
multilateral	NOUN	O
system	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
effective	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
preventing	NOUN	O
conflict	NOUN	O
,	.	O
in	ADP	O
resolving	NOUN	O
conflict	NOUN	O
where	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
occurs	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
in	ADP	O
post-conflict	NOUN	O
peace-building	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
can	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
course	NOUN	O
choose	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
do	NOUN	O
nothing	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
can	NOUN	O
linger	NOUN	O
complacently	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
inertia	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
status	NOUN	O
quo	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
consequence	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
,	.	O
however	NOUN	O
,	.	O
be	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
would	VERB	O
become	NOUN	O
less	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
less	NOUN	O
capable	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
facing	NOUN	O
these	NOUN	O
common	NOUN	O
challenges	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
security	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
particular	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
grasp	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
chance	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
itself	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
representative	NOUN	O
,	.	O
while	CONJ	O
increasing	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
efficiency	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
effectiveness	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
discussions	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
many	NOUN	O
years	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
increasing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
number	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
non-permanent	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
permanent	NOUN	O
seats	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
reach	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
conclusion	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
time	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
certain	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
long	NOUN	O
made	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
considerable	NOUN	O
contribution	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
work	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
be	NOUN	O
given	NOUN	O
permanent	NOUN	O
seats	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
am	VERB	O
referring	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
particular	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
Germany	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
India	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Japan	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
Brazil	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

But	CONJ	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
no	DET	O
less	NOUN	O
important	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
ensure	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
also	ADV	O
be	NOUN	O
given	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
permanent	NOUN	O
seat	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

Smaller	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	I-LOC
make	NOUN	O
up	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
vast	NOUN	O
majority	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Members	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Ensuring	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
smaller	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
adequately	NOUN	O
represented	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
various	NOUN	O
organs	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
is	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
only	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
matter	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
paying	NOUN	O
due	NOUN	O
regard	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
principles	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
sovereignty	NOUN	O
;	.	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
also	ADV	O
a	DET	O
practical	NOUN	O
matter	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
ensuring	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
particular	NOUN	O
challenges	NOUN	O
faced	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
smaller	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
—	.	O
both	NOUN	O
island	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
others	NOUN	O
—	.	O
are	VERB	O
taken	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
account	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
multilateral	NOUN	O
system	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Iceland	NOUN	I-LOC
knows	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
problems	NOUN	O
related	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
being	NOUN	O
far	NOUN	O
away	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
potential	NOUN	O
markets	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
know	NOUN	O
well	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
struggle	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
small	NOUN	O
economies	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
diversify	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
we	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
direct	NOUN	O
experience	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
vulnerability	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
small	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
external	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
shocks	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
natural	NOUN	O
disasters	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
opportunity	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
extend	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
sympathy	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
Caribbean	NOUN	I-LOC
States	NOUN	I-LOC
that	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
suffered	NOUN	O
so	NOUN	O
much	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
recent	NOUN	O
hurricanes	NOUN	O
.	.	O

My	PRON	O
Government	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
considering	NOUN	O
ways	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
which	DET	O
it	PRON	O
could	VERB	O
contribute	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
disaster	NOUN	O
relief	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
reconstruction	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Just	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
fundamental	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
legitimacy	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
that	NOUN	O
there	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
fair	NOUN	O
representation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
various	NOUN	O
regions	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
also	ADV	O
important	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
many	NOUN	O
smaller	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
feel	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
issues	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
understood	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
taken	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
account	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
that	NOUN	O
context	NOUN	O
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
refer	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
previously	NOUN	O
announced	NOUN	O
candidacy	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
my	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Iceland	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
for	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
non-	NOUN	O
permanent	NOUN	O
seat	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
period	NOUN	O
2009-2010	NOUN	O
,	.	O
which	DET	O
was	VERB	O
already	ADV	O
endorsed	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
1998	NUM	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Nordic	NOUN	I-MISC
States	NOUN	O
—	.	O
Denmark	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Finland	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
Norway	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
Sweden	NOUN	I-LOC
—	.	O
within	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Group	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Western	NOUN	I-MISC
European	NOUN	I-MISC
and	CONJ	O
other	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Smaller	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
valuable	NOUN	O
contribution	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
running	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
multilateral	NOUN	O
system	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Smaller	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
provide	NOUN	O
some	DET	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
most	DET	O
innovative	NOUN	O
thinking	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
approaches	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
challenges	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
face	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
—	.	O
in	ADP	O
per	NOUN	O
capita	NOUN	O
terms	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
often	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
absolute	NOUN	O
terms	NOUN	O
—	.	O
are	VERB	O
some	DET	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
most	DET	O
generous	NOUN	O
contributors	NOUN	O
.	.	O

An	DET	O
issue	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
key	NOUN	O
concern	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
small	NOUN	O
island	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
also	ADV	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
large	NOUN	O
,	.	O
is	VERB	O
sustainable	NOUN	O
use	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
resources	NOUN	O
.	.	O

As	NOUN	O
Iceland	NOUN	I-LOC
completed	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
term	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
member	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Commission	NOUN	I-MISC
on	ADP	I-MISC
Sustainable	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
(CSD)	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
my	PRON	O
Government	NOUN	O
was	VERB	O
very	ADV	O
pleased	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
see	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
organizational	NOUN	O
changes	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
working	NOUN	O
methods	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
CSD	NOUN	I-MISC
implemented	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
twelfth	NOUN	O
session	NOUN	O
,	.	O
in	ADP	O
April	NOUN	O
.	.	O

My	PRON	O
Government	NOUN	O
looks	NOUN	O
forward	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
continuing	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
active	NOUN	O
participation	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
future	NOUN	O
work	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
CSD	NOUN	I-MISC
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
promote	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
sustainable	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
resources	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Iceland	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
also	ADV	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
work	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
alternative	NOUN	O
energy	NOUN	O
resources	NOUN	O
,	.	O
particularly	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
possibilities	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
hydrogen	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
clean-	NOUN	O
energy	NOUN	O
provider	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Iceland	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
committed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
attaining	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Millennium	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
Goals	NOUN	I-MISC
as	NOUN	O
they	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
set	NOUN	O
out	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Millennium	NOUN	I-MISC
Declaration	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

My	PRON	O
Government	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
participate	NOUN	O
actively	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
preparations	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
major	NOUN	O
summit	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
2005	NUM	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
clear	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
speed	NOUN	O
up	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
order	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
,	.	O
before	NOUN	O
2015	NUM	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
goals	NOUN	O
set	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Millennium	NOUN	I-MISC
Summit	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
regard	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
2005	NUM	O
summit	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
one	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
important	NOUN	O
milestones	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
way	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
attaining	NOUN	O
them	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
now	ADV	O
turn	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
questions	NOUN	O
concerning	NOUN	O
particular	NOUN	O
regions	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Iceland	NOUN	I-LOC
warmly	NOUN	O
welcomes	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
New	ADJ	I-MISC
Partnership	NOUN	I-MISC
for	NOUN	I-MISC
Africa	NOUN	I-MISC
's	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
(NEPAD)	NOUN	I-MISC
initiative	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
its	NOUN	O
aim	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
ensuring	NOUN	O
democracy	NOUN	O
,	.	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
,	.	O
good	NOUN	O
governance	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
sound	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
management	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
efforts	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
African	NOUN	I-MISC
countries	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
management	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
resolution	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
conflicts	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
their	PRON	O
own	NOUN	O
region	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
establishment	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
Peace	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	I-ORG
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
within	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
African	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
are	VERB	O
ground-breaking	NOUN	O
developments	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
the	DET	O
African	NOUN	I-MISC
mediation	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
number	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
conflicts	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
efforts	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
African	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
African	NOUN	I-MISC
regional	NOUN	O
organizations	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
develop	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
capabilities	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
peace-supporting	NOUN	O
operations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Sub-Saharan	NOUN	I-MISC
Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
continues	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
focus	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Icelandic	NOUN	I-MISC
bilateral	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
we	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
increase	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
contribution	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
involvement	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
multilateral	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Iceland	NOUN	I-LOC
welcomes	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
recent	NOUN	O
understanding	NOUN	O
among	NOUN	O
members	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
World	NOUN	I-ORG
Trade	NOUN	I-ORG
Organization	NOUN	I-ORG
on	ADP	O
a	DET	O
framework	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
continuation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Doha	NOUN	I-LOC
development	NOUN	O
round	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
negotiations	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
trade	NOUN	O
liberalization	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
multilateral	NOUN	O
trading	NOUN	O
system	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
proven	NOUN	O
vehicle	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
promoting	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
growth	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
central	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
future	NOUN	O
prosperity	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
nations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
noteworthy	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
particular	NOUN	O
attention	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
paid	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
needs	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
least	NOUN	O
developed	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
important	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
they	NOUN	O
fully	NOUN	O
reap	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
benefits	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
multilateral	NOUN	O
trading	NOUN	O
system	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
offer	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Iceland	NOUN	I-LOC
believes	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
framework	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
give	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
negotiators	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Geneva	NOUN	I-LOC
a	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
platform	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
prompt	NOUN	O
conclusion	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Doha	NOUN	I-LOC
round	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
want	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
do	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
part	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
making	NOUN	O
sure	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
globalization	NOUN	O
benefits	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
,	.	O
not	NOUN	O
least	NOUN	O
through	NOUN	O
targeted	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
an	DET	O
effort	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
assist	NOUN	O
African	NOUN	I-MISC
countries	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
making	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
most	DET	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Doha	NOUN	I-LOC
round	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Iceland	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
participating	NOUN	O
,	.	O
together	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
other	NOUN	O
Nordic	NOUN	I-MISC
countries	NOUN	O
,	.	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Nordic	NOUN	I-MISC
Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
initiative	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
resolution	NOUN	O
1546	NUM	O
(2004)	NOUN	O
,	.	O
unanimously	NOUN	O
adopted	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
6	NUM	O
June	NOUN	O
,	.	O
provided	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
restoration	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
sovereignty	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
also	ADV	O
demonstrated	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
will	VERB	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
—	.	O
and	CONJ	O
indeed	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
rest	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
—	.	O
to	NOUN	O
resolve	NOUN	O
past	NOUN	O
differences	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
give	NOUN	O
first	NOUN	O
priority	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
political	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
economic	NOUN	O
reconstruction	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

My	PRON	O
Government	NOUN	O
remains	NOUN	O
prepared	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
lend	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
difficult	NOUN	O
work	NOUN	O
ahead	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
elsewhere	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Iceland	NOUN	I-LOC
would	VERB	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
emphasize	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
importance	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
ensuring	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
safety	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
missions	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Afghanistan	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
occupy	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
attention	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
coming	NOUN	O
months	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
has	NOUN	O
done	NOUN	O
valuable	NOUN	O
work	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
registering	NOUN	O
some	DET	O
10	NUM	O
million	NOUN	O
voters	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
presidential	NOUN	O
elections	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
9	NUM	O
October	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Afghanistan	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
important	NOUN	O
milestone	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
process	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
rebuilding	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
country	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
maintain	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
ongoing	NOUN	O
commitment	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
Afghanistan	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
where	NOUN	O
serious	NOUN	O
challenges	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
rebuilding	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
country	NOUN	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
faced	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Iceland	NOUN	I-LOC
has	NOUN	O
demonstrated	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
has	NOUN	O
assumed	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
leading	NOUN	O
role	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
running	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Kabul	NOUN	I-LOC
international	NOUN	O
airport	NOUN	O
,	.	O
under	ADP	O
the	DET	O
auspices	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
NATO-led	NOUN	I-MISC
International	NOUN	I-ORG
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Assistance	NOUN	I-ORG
Force	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

An	DET	O
area	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
continuing	NOUN	O
concern	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
,	.	O
of	ADP	O
course	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
Middle	NOUN	I-LOC
East	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Icelandic	NOUN	I-MISC
Government	NOUN	O
continues	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
call	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
Israel	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
Palestinian	NOUN	I-MISC
Authority	NOUN	I-MISC
to	NOUN	O
resume	NOUN	O
negotiations	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
a	DET	O
political	NOUN	O
settlement	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
road	NOUN	O
map	NOUN	O
sets	NOUN	O
out	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
realistic	NOUN	O
way	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
two-State	NOUN	O
solution	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Iceland	NOUN	I-LOC
fully	NOUN	O
supports	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
efforts	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Quartet	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
urge	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Quartet	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
all	NOUN	O
other	NOUN	O
well-	NOUN	O
intentioned	NOUN	O
parties	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
focus	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
issue	NOUN	O
.	.	O

At	ADP	O
the	DET	O
beginning	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
my	PRON	O
remarks	NOUN	O
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
concentrated	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Terrorism	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
an	DET	O
assault	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
express	NOUN	O
strong	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
initiative	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
urging	NOUN	O
Member	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
ratify	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
conventions	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
concern	NOUN	O
protection	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
rights	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
ordinary	NOUN	O
citizen	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
conducting	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
war	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
protect	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
terrorists	NOUN	O
themselves	NOUN	O
flout	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
sure	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
humanitarian	NOUN	O
law	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
sacrificed	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Here	NOUN	O
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
like	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
refer	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
key	NOUN	O
role	NOUN	O
played	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
International	NOUN	I-ORG
Committee	NOUN	I-ORG
of	ADP	I-ORG
the	DET	I-ORG
Red	NOUN	I-ORG
Cross	NOUN	I-ORG
—	.	O
and	CONJ	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
entire	NOUN	O
Red	NOUN	I-ORG
Cross	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
Red	NOUN	I-ORG
Crescent	NOUN	I-ORG
movement	NOUN	O
—	.	O
in	ADP	O
monitoring	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
implementation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Geneva	NOUN	I-LOC
Conventions	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
same	NOUN	O
time	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
express	NOUN	O
my	PRON	O
appreciation	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
work	NOUN	O
.	.	O

During	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
session	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
General	NOUN	I-ORG
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
Iceland	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
work	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
advance	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
issue	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Iceland	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
also	ADV	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
work	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
others	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
uproot	NOUN	O
racism	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
religious	NOUN	O
intolerance	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
major	NOUN	O
way	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
prevent	NOUN	O
conflict	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
create	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
secure	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
environment	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Iceland	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
totally	NOUN	O
committed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
multilateral	NOUN	O
system	NOUN	O
,	.	O
of	ADP	O
which	DET	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
fulcrum	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Without	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
effective	NOUN	O
multilateral	NOUN	O
system	NOUN	O
,	.	O
conflict	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
its	NOUN	O
causes	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
much	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
difficult	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
address	NOUN	O
.	.	O

But	CONJ	O
,	.	O
in	ADP	O
order	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
effective	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
system	NOUN	O
needs	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Government	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Iceland	NOUN	I-LOC
sincerely	NOUN	O
hopes	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
can	NOUN	O
bring	NOUN	O
about	NOUN	O
necessary	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
during	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
next	NOUN	O
year	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
we	PRON	O
look	NOUN	O
forward	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
working	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
Member	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
end	NOUN	O
.	.	O
