As	NOUN	O
one	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Vice-Presidents	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
session	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
assure	NOUN	O
him	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
full	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
take	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
opportunity	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
convey	NOUN	O
profound	NOUN	O
gratitude	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
appreciation	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
my	PRON	O
brother	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Ali	NOUN	I-PER
Treki	NOUN	I-PER
,	.	O
the	DET	O
outgoing	NOUN	O
President	NOUN	O
,	.	O
for	NOUN	O
his	PRON	O
able	NOUN	O
leadership	NOUN	O
during	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
sixty-fourth	NOUN	O
session	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
owes	NOUN	O
him	NOUN	O
gratitude	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
his	PRON	O
timely	NOUN	O
initiative	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
convene	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
plenary	NOUN	O
meeting	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
humanitarian	NOUN	O
emergency	NOUN	O
arising	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
floods	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
(see	NOUN	O
A/64/PV.110	NOUN	0
)	.	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
come	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
at	ADP	O
a	DET	O
difficult	NOUN	O
time	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
history	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
recent	NOUN	O
flash	NOUN	O
floods	NOUN	O
—	.	O
the	DET	O
worst	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
living	NOUN	O
memory	NOUN	O
—	.	O
have	NOUN	O
left	NOUN	O
behind	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
trail	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
death	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
destruction	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Precious	NOUN	O
lives	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
lost	NOUN	O
,	.	O
millions	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
acres	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
crops	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
washed	NOUN	O
away	NOUN	O
,	.	O
homes	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
destroyed	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
livelihoods	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
lost	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
grateful	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
our	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
partners	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
other	NOUN	O
friends	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
standing	NOUN	O
up	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
us	PRON	O
in	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
difficult	NOUN	O
hour	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
for	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
important	NOUN	O
contribution	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
supporting	NOUN	O
rescue	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
relief	NOUN	O
operations	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Government	NOUN	O
remains	NOUN	O
focused	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
resolve	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
address	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
challenges	NOUN	O
posed	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
that	NOUN	O
humanitarian	NOUN	O
crisis	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
determined	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
rebuild	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
better	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
vibrant	NOUN	O
Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
do	NOUN	O
so	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
transparent	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
accountable	NOUN	O
manner	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
resilience	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
enable	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
live	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
an	DET	O
ever	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
interconnected	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
interdependent	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
,	.	O
a	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
where	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
fate	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
destinies	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
interwoven	NOUN	O
like	NOUN	O
never	NOUN	O
before	NOUN	O
,	.	O
a	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
where	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
increasingly	NOUN	O
difficult	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
maintain	NOUN	O
islands	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
prosperity	NOUN	O
while	CONJ	O
conflicts	NOUN	O
,	.	O
oppression	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
adversity	NOUN	O
fester	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
live	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
where	NOUN	O
dividends	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
peace	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
shared	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
easily	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
fallout	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
adversity	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
instability	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Today	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
face	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
integrated	NOUN	O
onslaught	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
series	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
new	ADJ	O
and	CONJ	O
emerging	NOUN	O
challenges	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
seriously	NOUN	O
threaten	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
growth	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
development	NOUN	O
,	.	O
social	NOUN	O
cohesion	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
environmental	NOUN	O
protection	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
clearly	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
reached	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
decisive	NOUN	O
moment	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
have	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
wise	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
well-considered	NOUN	O
choices	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
bring	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
prosperity	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
present	NOUN	O
while	CONJ	O
protecting	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
preserving	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
for	NOUN	O
future	NOUN	O
generations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
response	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
simple:	NOUN	O
global	ADJ	O
problems	NOUN	O
require	NOUN	O
global	ADJ	O
solutions	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
needs	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
multilateral	NOUN	O
approach	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
truly	NOUN	O
subscribes	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
values	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
principles	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
peoples	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
signed	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
to	NOUN	O
65	NUM	O
years	NOUN	O
ago	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Charter	NOUN	I-MISC
envisages	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
where	NOUN	O
equity	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
valued	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
much	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
entitlement	NOUN	O
,	.	O
where	NOUN	O
inclusiveness	NOUN	O
replaces	NOUN	O
exclusiveness	NOUN	O
,	.	O
where	NOUN	O
dialogue	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
collaboration	NOUN	O
define	NOUN	O
engagement	NOUN	O
,	.	O
where	NOUN	O
transparency	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
openness	NOUN	O
guide	NOUN	O
business	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
decision-making	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
global	ADJ	O
institutions	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Full	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
unconditional	NOUN	O
adherence	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
values	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
principles	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
what	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
put	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
road	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
durable	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
security	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
sustained	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
growth	NOUN	O
.	.	O

As	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
primus	NOUN	O
inter	NOUN	O
pares	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
only	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
truly	NOUN	O
universal	NOUN	O
multilateral	NOUN	O
Organization	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
enjoys	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
credibility	NOUN	O
,	.	O
legitimacy	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
universal	NOUN	O
acceptability	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
realize	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
—	.	O
which	DET	O
is	VERB	O
also	ADV	O
its	NOUN	O
raison	NOUN	O
d'être	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
supports	NOUN	O
comprehensive	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
more	NOUN	O
representative	NOUN	O
,	.	O
equitable	NOUN	O
,	.	O
transparent	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
accountable	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Council	NOUN	I-ORG
reform	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
guided	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
principles	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
equality	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
democracy	NOUN	O
,	.	O
which	DET	O
could	VERB	O
conform	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
dynamic	NOUN	O
future	NOUN	O
,	.	O
one	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
entrenched	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
historical	NOUN	O
mistakes	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
individual	NOUN	O
privileges	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
past	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
should	NOUN	O
look	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
outcome	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
unites	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
does	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
divide	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
membership	NOUN	O
,	.	O
one	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
strengthens	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
does	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
weaken	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Organization	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Our	NOUN	O
collective	NOUN	O
search	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
culminate	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
consensus	NOUN	O
solution	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
corresponds	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
interest	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
entire	NOUN	O
membership	NOUN	O
,	.	O
particularly	NOUN	O
small	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
medium	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
,	.	O
developing	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

Our	NOUN	O
peacekeepers	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
laid	NOUN	O
down	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
lives	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
missions	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
were	NOUN	O
operationally	NOUN	O
demanding	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
geographically	NOUN	O
difficult	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
unique	NOUN	O
status	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
brings	NOUN	O
acceptance	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
peacekeeping	NOUN	O
activities	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
success	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
peacekeeping	NOUN	O
operations	NOUN	O
,	.	O
in	ADP	O
turn	NOUN	O
,	.	O
brings	NOUN	O
credibility	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
body	NOUN	O
.	.	O

For	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
suffering	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
conflict	NOUN	O
zone	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
sight	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
blue	NOUN	O
helmet	NOUN	O
provides	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
beacon	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
hope	NOUN	O
,	.	O
which	DET	O
has	NOUN	O
illuminated	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
lives	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
millions	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
bringing	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
alleviating	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
pains	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
sorrows	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Our	NOUN	O
commitment	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
promotion	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
peace	NOUN	O
,	.	O
security	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
stability	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
development	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
friendly	NOUN	O
relations	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
other	NOUN	O
nations	NOUN	O
,	.	O
respect	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
sovereignty	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
territorial	NOUN	O
integrity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
promotion	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
economic	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
social	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
unwavering	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
that	NOUN	O
firm	NOUN	O
conviction	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
enabled	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
democratic	NOUN	O
Government	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
remain	NOUN	O
steadfast	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
resolve	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
fight	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
extremism	NOUN	O
,	.	O
even	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
deal	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
massive	NOUN	O
destruction	NOUN	O
caused	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
catastrophic	NOUN	O
floods	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Our	NOUN	O
national	NOUN	O
consensus	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
resolve	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
fight	NOUN	O
extremism	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
remains	NOUN	O
unshaken	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
recognizes	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
applauds	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
important	NOUN	O
successes	NOUN	O
achieved	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
security	NOUN	O
forces	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
terrorists	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Those	NOUN	O
successes	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
come	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
a	DET	O
heavy	NOUN	O
cost	NOUN	O
.	.	O

More	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
20,000	NOUN	O
innocent	NOUN	O
civilians	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
fallen	NOUN	O
victim	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
more	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
2,500	NOUN	O
personnel	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
security	NOUN	O
forces	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
offered	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
ultimate	NOUN	O
sacrifice	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Our	NOUN	O
material	NOUN	O
losses	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
nearly	NOUN	O
$50	NOUN	O
billion	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Pakistani	NOUN	I-MISC
nation	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
persist	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
eliminate	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
issue	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
both	NOUN	O
regional	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
global	ADJ	O
dimensions	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
imperative	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
do	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
combat	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
menace	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
also	ADV	O
essential	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
address	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
root	NOUN	O
causes	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
,	.	O
which	DET	O
are	VERB	O
often	NOUN	O
found	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
poverty	NOUN	O
,	.	O
deprivation	NOUN	O
,	.	O
injustices	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
oppression	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
therefore	NOUN	O
absurd	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
malign	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
whole	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
a	DET	O
region	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
any	NOUN	O
religion	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
that	NOUN	O
account	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
cannot	NOUN	O
accept	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
stereotyping	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Muslims	NOUN	I-MISC
as	NOUN	O
terrorists	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Islam	NOUN	I-MISC
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
religion	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
peace	NOUN	O
,	.	O
compassion	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
brotherhood	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Terrorism	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
complete	NOUN	O
antithesis	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
Islam	NOUN	I-MISC
's	NOUN	O
humanistic	NOUN	O
outlook	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
noble	NOUN	O
values	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
supports	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
just	NOUN	O
cause	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Palestinian	NOUN	I-MISC
people	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
restitution	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
their	PRON	O
inalienable	NOUN	O
national	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
,	.	O
including	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
independent	NOUN	O
Palestinian	NOUN	I-MISC
State	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
Al	NOUN	I-LOC
Quds	NOUN	I-LOC
Al	NOUN	I-LOC
Sharif	NOUN	I-LOC
as	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
capital	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
brazen	NOUN	O
use	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
force	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
humanitarian	NOUN	O
freedom	NOUN	O
flotilla	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
31	NUM	O
May	NOUN	O
2010	NUM	O
,	.	O
which	DET	O
resulted	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
killing	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
humanitarian	NOUN	O
workers	NOUN	O
,	.	O
was	VERB	O
a	DET	O
flagrant	NOUN	O
violation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
international	NOUN	O
law	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
norms	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
look	NOUN	O
forward	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
prompt	NOUN	O
,	.	O
impartial	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
transparent	NOUN	O
inquiry	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
incident	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
Panel	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Inquiry	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
dispute	NOUN	O
over	NOUN	O
Jammu	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
Kashmir	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
one	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
oldest	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
agenda	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
about	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
exercise	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
right	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
self-	NOUN	O
determination	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Kashmiri	NOUN	I-MISC
people	NOUN	O
through	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
free	NOUN	O
,	.	O
fair	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
impartial	NOUN	O
plebiscite	NOUN	O
under	ADP	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
auspices	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
views	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
prevailing	NOUN	O
situation	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Indian-occupied	NOUN	O
Kashmir	NOUN	I-LOC
with	ADP	O
grave	NOUN	O
concern	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Over	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
past	NOUN	O
two	NOUN	O
months	NOUN	O
,	.	O
more	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
100	NUM	O
Kashmiris	NOUN	I-MISC
have	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
killed	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
Indian	NOUN	I-MISC
security	NOUN	O
forces	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Kashmir	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
strongly	NOUN	O
condemn	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
brutality	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Kashmiri	NOUN	I-MISC
people	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
respected	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
their	PRON	O
voices	NOUN	O
heard	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
create	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
enabling	NOUN	O
environment	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
peaceful	NOUN	O
solution	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
long-standing	NOUN	O
Jammu	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
Kashmir	NOUN	I-LOC
dispute	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
reaffirms	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
complete	NOUN	O
solidarity	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Kashmiri	NOUN	I-MISC
people	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
urges	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
persuade	NOUN	O
India	NOUN	I-LOC
to	NOUN	O
end	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
repression	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Kashmir	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
willing	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
engage	NOUN	O
India	NOUN	I-LOC
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
comprehensive	NOUN	O
dialogue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
normalize	NOUN	O
relations	NOUN	O
between	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
two	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
finding	NOUN	O
amicable	NOUN	O
solutions	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
outstanding	NOUN	O
issues	NOUN	O
,	.	O
including	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
core	NOUN	O
dispute	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Jammu	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
Kashmir	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

A	DET	O
peaceful	NOUN	O
resolution	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Kashmir	NOUN	O
dispute	NOUN	O
,	.	O
in	ADP	O
accordance	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
resolutions	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
taking	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
account	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
aspirations	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Kashmiri	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
,	.	O
would	VERB	O
create	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
atmosphere	NOUN	O
conducive	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
durable	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
stability	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
South	NOUN	I-MISC
Asian	NOUN	I-MISC
region	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
the	DET	O
spirit	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
global	ADJ	O
solidarity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
good-neighbourly	NOUN	O
relations	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
has	NOUN	O
hosted	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
largest	NOUN	O
concentration	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
refugees	NOUN	O
anywhere	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
past	NOUN	O
30	NUM	O
years	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
host	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
Afghan	NOUN	I-MISC
brothers	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
moral	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
humanitarian	NOUN	O
duty	NOUN	O
.	.	O

No	DET	O
country	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
suffered	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
from	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
direct	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
indirect	NOUN	O
consequences	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
decades	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
conflict	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Afghanistan	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
thus	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
abiding	NOUN	O
stake	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
stability	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Afghanistan	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

Our	NOUN	O
commitment	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
objective	NOUN	O
remains	NOUN	O
firm	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
time	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
come	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
transform	NOUN	O
Afghanistan	NOUN	I-LOC
from	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
centre	NOUN	O
stage	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
proxy	NOUN	O
wars	NOUN	O
,	.	O
interference	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
confrontation	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
a	DET	O
hub	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
development	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
believes	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
restoration	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
societal	NOUN	O
equilibrium	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Afghanistan	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
an	DET	O
Afghan	NOUN	O
responsibility	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
cannot	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
imposed	NOUN	O
externally	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
support	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
national	NOUN	O
reconciliation	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
Afghan-owned	NOUN	I-MISC
and	CONJ	O
Afghan-led	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
congratulate	VERB	O
the	DET	O
Government	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Afghanistan	NOUN	I-LOC
on	ADP	O
holding	NOUN	O
successful	NOUN	O
parliamentary	NOUN	O
elections	NOUN	O
.	.	O

They	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
strengthen	NOUN	O
President	NOUN	O
Karzai	NOUN	I-PER
's	NOUN	O
initiation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
national	NOUN	O
reconciliation	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
reintegration	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Disarmament	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
non-proliferation	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
important	NOUN	O
pillars	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
security	NOUN	O
architecture	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
remain	NOUN	O
committed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
both	NOUN	O
objectives	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
believe	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
they	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
pursued	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
an	DET	O
equitable	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
non	NOUN	O
discriminatory	NOUN	O
manner	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
asymmetric	NOUN	O
build-up	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
conventional	NOUN	O
weapons	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
espousal	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
aggressive	NOUN	O
doctrines	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
negative	NOUN	O
impact	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
regional	NOUN	O
security	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
pursuit	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
discriminatory	NOUN	O
policies	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
disregard	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
security	NOUN	O
interests	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
States	NOUN	O
seriously	NOUN	O
erode	NOUN	O
globally	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
moral	NOUN	O
authority	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
underlie	NOUN	O
equitable	NOUN	O
approaches	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
promoting	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
goals	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
nuclear	NOUN	O
disarmament	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
non	NOUN	O
proliferation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
consistently	NOUN	O
pursued	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
policy	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
conventional	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
nuclear	NOUN	O
restraint	NOUN	O
,	.	O
along	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
conflict	NOUN	O
resolution	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
South	NOUN	I-LOC
Asia	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
reaffirm	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
proposal	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
strategic	NOUN	O
restraint	NOUN	O
regime	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
important	NOUN	O
way	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
promote	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
cause	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
peace	NOUN	O
,	.	O
stability	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
security	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
region	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
fifth	NOUN	O
largest	NOUN	O
population	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
only	NOUN	O
0.4	NOUN	O
per	NOUN	O
cent	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
total	NOUN	O
greenhouse-gas	NOUN	O
emissions	NOUN	O
,	.	O
is	VERB	O
one	NOUN	O
hundred	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
thirty-fifth	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
global	ADJ	O
list	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
greenhouse-gas	NOUN	O
emitters	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Despite	NOUN	O
such	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
low	NOUN	O
contribution	NOUN	O
,	.	O
climate	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
causing	NOUN	O
irrevocable	NOUN	O
damage	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
with	ADP	O
tremendous	NOUN	O
social	NOUN	O
,	.	O
environmental	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
economic	NOUN	O
impacts	NOUN	O
.	.	O

While	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
continues	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
discuss	NOUN	O
climate	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
its	NOUN	O
scientific	NOUN	O
basis	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
seek	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
fair	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
equitable	NOUN	O
outcome	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
ongoing	NOUN	O
negotiations	NOUN	O
under	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Framework	NOUN	I-MISC
Convention	NOUN	I-MISC
on	ADP	I-MISC
Climate	NOUN	I-MISC
Change	NOUN	I-MISC
(	.	0
UNFCCC	NOUN	I-MISC
)	.	O
,	.	O
climate	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
already	ADV	O
become	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
reality	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
170	NUM	O
million	NOUN	O
Pakistanis	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

The	DET	O
present	NOUN	O
situation	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
reconfirms	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
extreme	NOUN	O
vulnerability	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
adverse	NOUN	O
impacts	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
climate	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
also	ADV	O
complicates	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
post-flood	NOUN	O
reconstruction	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
rehabilitation	NOUN	O
scenario	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
in	ADP	O
Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
interests	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
work	NOUN	O
vigorously	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
creatively	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
early	ADV	O
and	CONJ	O
successful	NOUN	O
conclusion	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
ongoing	NOUN	O
climate-change	NOUN	O
negotiations	NOUN	O
under	ADP	O
UNFCCC	NOUN	O
auspices	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Any	NOUN	O
lasting	NOUN	O
solution	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
have	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
respect	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
principle	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
common	NOUN	O
but	CONJ	O
differentiated	NOUN	O
responsibilities	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
respective	NOUN	O
capabilities	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
countries	NOUN	O
.	.	O

With	ADP	O
an	DET	O
active	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
empowered	NOUN	O
Parliament	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
a	DET	O
vigilant	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
well-informed	NOUN	O
civil	NOUN	O
society	NOUN	O
,	.	O
free	NOUN	O
media	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
an	DET	O
independent	NOUN	O
judiciary	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
democratic	NOUN	O
Government	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
putting	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
place	NOUN	O
mechanisms	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
ensure	NOUN	O
good	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
accountable	NOUN	O
governance	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
levels	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
country	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
democratic	NOUN	O
Government	NOUN	O
,	.	O
inspired	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
vision	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Shaheed	NOUN	I-PER
Benazir	NOUN	I-PER
Bhutto	NOUN	I-PER
,	.	O
attaches	NOUN	O
special	ADJ	O
attention	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
promotion	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
protection	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
segments	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
society	NOUN	O
,	.	O
particularly	NOUN	O
women	NOUN	O
,	.	O
children	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
minorities	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
now	ADV	O
a	DET	O
State	NOUN	O
party	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
27	NUM	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
conventions	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
welcome	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
creation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
composite	NOUN	O
gender	NOUN	O
entity	NOUN	O
,	.	O
UN	NOUN	I-ORG
Women	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
hope	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
lead	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
efforts	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
promote	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
,	.	O
empowerment	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
equality	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
women	NOUN	O
throughout	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Pursuing	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
forging	NOUN	O
close	NOUN	O
regional	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
partnerships	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
an	DET	O
important	NOUN	O
pillar	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
strategy	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
pursue	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
growth	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
development	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Pakistan	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
working	NOUN	O
through	NOUN	O
both	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Economic	NOUN	I-ORG
Cooperation	NOUN	I-ORG
Organization	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
South	NOUN	I-ORG
Asian	NOUN	I-ORG
Association	NOUN	I-ORG
for	NOUN	I-ORG
Regional	NOUN	I-ORG
Cooperation	NOUN	I-ORG
to	NOUN	O
further	NOUN	O
deepen	NOUN	O
regional	NOUN	O
collaboration	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
expand	NOUN	O
people-to-people	NOUN	O
contacts	NOUN	O
,	.	O
including	NOUN	O
through	NOUN	O
inter-parliamentary	NOUN	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Our	NOUN	O
strategy	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
actions	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
national	NOUN	O
level	NOUN	O
stem	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
firm	NOUN	O
belief	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
primary	NOUN	O
responsibility	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
central	NOUN	O
action	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
pursuit	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
growth	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
development	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
vested	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
nation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Despite	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
challenging	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
security	NOUN	O
environment	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
pursuing	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
aggressive	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
programme	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
conscious	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
requires	NOUN	O
enhanced	NOUN	O
fiscal	NOUN	O
space	NOUN	O
,	.	O
for	NOUN	O
which	DET	O
we	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
introduced	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
tax	NOUN	O
reforms	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
close	NOUN	O
collaboration	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
international	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
partners	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
work	NOUN	O
together	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
safe	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
secure	NOUN	O
place	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
children	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
strenuous	NOUN	O
endeavours	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
ideals	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Charter	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
prosperous	NOUN	O
place	NOUN	O
free	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
hunger	NOUN	O
,	.	O
want	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
poverty	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
owe	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
future	NOUN	O
generations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
cannot	NOUN	O
afford	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
fail	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
endeavour	NOUN	O
.	.	O
