I	NOUN	O
condemn	NOUN	O
them	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
strongest	NOUN	O
possible	NOUN	O
terms	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
perpetrators	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
such	NOUN	O
crimes	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
brought	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
justice	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
renew	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
bolster	NOUN	O
respect	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
humanitarian	NOUN	O
principles	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
unacceptable	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
personnel	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
unable	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
conduct	NOUN	O
humanitarian	NOUN	O
relief	NOUN	O
operations	NOUN	O
without	NOUN	O
risking	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
lives	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
unacceptable	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
personnel	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
denied	NOUN	O
access	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
distress	NOUN	O
.	.	O

On	ADP	O
behalf	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
people	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Norway	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
wish	VERB	O
to	NOUN	O
express	NOUN	O
my	PRON	O
respect	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
admiration	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
workers	NOUN	O
who	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
doing	NOUN	O
what	NOUN	O
they	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
help	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
other	NOUN	O
zones	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
conflict	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
danger	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Unless	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
security	NOUN	O
needs	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
are	VERB	O
met	NOUN	O
,	.	O
valuable	NOUN	O
time	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
road	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
political	NOUN	O
stability	NOUN	O
,	.	O
democracy	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
economic	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
social	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
lost	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Without	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
safe	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
secure	NOUN	O
environment	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
is	VERB	O
unable	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
help	NOUN	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
along	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
road	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
deplore	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
political	NOUN	O
assassinations	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
religious	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
political	NOUN	O
leaders	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

Now	ADV	O
we	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
focus	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
attention	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
what	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
needed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
rebuild	NOUN	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

Norway	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
participating	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
international	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
stabilize	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
rebuild	NOUN	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
benefit	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Iraqi	NOUN	I-MISC
people	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Our	NOUN	O
aim	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
to	NOUN	O
help	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
people	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
regain	NOUN	O
control	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
their	PRON	O
own	NOUN	O
destiny	NOUN	O
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
help	NOUN	O
them	NOUN	O
build	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
future	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
freedom	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
justice	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
a	DET	O
life	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
peace	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
their	PRON	O
neighbours	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
should	NOUN	O
play	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
key	NOUN	O
role	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
setting	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
benchmarks	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
guiding	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
political	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
towards	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
early	ADV	O
restoration	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
sovereignty	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
transfer	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
power	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
Iraqi	NOUN	I-MISC
government	NOUN	O
.	.	O

A	DET	O
carefully	NOUN	O
considered	NOUN	O
timeframe	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
drawn	NOUN	O
up	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
make	NOUN	O
sure	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
tasks	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
decide	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
in	ADP	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
are	VERB	O
realistic	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
achievable	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Terrorism	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
dark	NOUN	O
force	NOUN	O
,	.	O
which	DET	O
targets	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
very	ADV	O
values	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
norms	NOUN	O
upon	NOUN	O
which	DET	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Charter	NOUN	I-MISC
is	VERB	O
based	NOUN	O
.	.	O

An	DET	O
overwhelming	NOUN	O
majority	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Member	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
joined	NOUN	O
forces	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
fight	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
we	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
taken	NOUN	O
some	DET	O
important	NOUN	O
steps	NOUN	O
together	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
need	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
strengthen	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
role	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
in	ADP	O
multilateral	NOUN	O
disarmament	NOUN	O
,	.	O
arms	NOUN	O
control	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
non-proliferation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
need	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
agree	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
strong	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
effective	NOUN	O
regimes	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
provide	NOUN	O
reliable	NOUN	O
protection	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
weapons	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
mass	NOUN	O
destruction	NOUN	O
.	.	O

A	DET	O
week	NOUN	O
ago	NOUN	O
,	.	O
world	NOUN	O
leaders	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
sat	NOUN	O
down	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
New	ADJ	I-LOC
York	NOUN	I-LOC
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
invitation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Norway	NOUN	I-LOC
to	NOUN	O
discuss	NOUN	O
ways	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
fight	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
roots	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
evil	NOUN	O
.	.	O

They	NOUN	O
voiced	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
dedication	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
fight	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
their	PRON	O
determination	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
place	NOUN	O
humanity	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
centre	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
that	NOUN	O
fight	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
want	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
that	NOUN	O
reaches	NOUN	O
out	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
responds	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
concerns	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
Member	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
reach	NOUN	O
out	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
respond	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
concerns	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
individuals	NOUN	O
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
needs	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
men	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
women	NOUN	O
alike	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
need	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
equal	NOUN	O
opportunities	NOUN	O
,	.	O
where	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
resources	NOUN	O
—	.	O
and	CONJ	O
not	NOUN	O
only	NOUN	O
half	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
them	NOUN	O
—	.	O
are	VERB	O
fully	NOUN	O
put	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
use	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
vision	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
humane	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
where	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
live	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
security	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
dignity	NOUN	O
,	.	O
free	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
poverty	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
despair	NOUN	O
.	.	O

To	NOUN	O
live	NOUN	O
up	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
ideals	NOUN	O
enshrined	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Charter	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
must	NOUN	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
give	NOUN	O
priority	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
fundamental	NOUN	O
aspects	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
governance	NOUN	O
.	.	O

A	DET	O
culture	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
impunity	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
mass	NOUN	O
atrocities	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
incompatible	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
human	NOUN	O
dignity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
undermines	NOUN	O
long-term	NOUN	O
security	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Fighting	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
,	.	O
strengthening	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
security	NOUN	O
,	.	O
working	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
preventing	NOUN	O
conflict	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
challenges	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
closely	NOUN	O
related	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Millennium	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
Goals	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
pledged	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
halve	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
proportion	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
people	NOUN	O
living	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
extreme	NOUN	O
poverty	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
reduce	NOUN	O
child	NOUN	O
mortality	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
two-thirds	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
pledged	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
halve	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
proportion	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
people	NOUN	O
without	NOUN	O
access	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
safe	NOUN	O
drinking	NOUN	O
water	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
basic	NOUN	O
sanitation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Norway	NOUN	I-LOC
currently	NOUN	O
holds	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
chairmanship	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Commission	NOUN	I-MISC
on	ADP	I-MISC
Sustainable	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
we	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
committed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
achieving	NOUN	O
real	NOUN	O
progress	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
crucial	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
developing	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
developed	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
private	NOUN	O
sector	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
contribute	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Development	NOUN	I-MISC
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
built	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
a	DET	O
global	ADJ	O
partnership	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
on	ADP	O
shared	NOUN	O
responsibilities	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Norway	NOUN	I-LOC
remains	NOUN	O
committed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Doha	NOUN	I-LOC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
Agenda	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
confident	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
strengthening	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
making	NOUN	O
full	NOUN	O
use	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
multilateral	NOUN	O
framework	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
way	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
go	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
work	NOUN	O
hard	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
get	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
negotiations	NOUN	O
back	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
track	NOUN	O
.	.	O

More	NOUN	O
often	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
only	NOUN	O
becomes	NOUN	O
engaged	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
earnest	NOUN	O
after	NOUN	O
armed	NOUN	O
conflict	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
broken	NOUN	O
out	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
reasons	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
many	NOUN	O
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
they	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
no	DET	O
excuse	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
loss	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
lives	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
human	NOUN	O
misery	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
setbacks	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
development	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
too	NOUN	O
often	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
high	NOUN	O
price	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
collective	NOUN	O
inaction	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Too	NOUN	O
often	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
main	NOUN	O
legacy	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
civil	NOUN	O
war	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
another	NOUN	O
civil	NOUN	O
war	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Yet	NOUN	O
there	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
many	NOUN	O
things	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
can	NOUN	O
do	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
prevent	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
happening	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
can	NOUN	O
act	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
prevent	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
conflict	NOUN	O
drivers	NOUN	O
such	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
diamonds	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
other	NOUN	O
natural	NOUN	O
resources	NOUN	O
,	.	O
from	NOUN	O
fuelling	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
prolonging	NOUN	O
conflicts	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
we	PRON	O
can	NOUN	O
act	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
curb	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
illegal	NOUN	O
trade	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
small	NOUN	O
arms	NOUN	O
.	.	O

By	ADP	O
fighting	NOUN	O
poverty	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
promoting	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
development	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
making	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
soundest	NOUN	O
investment	NOUN	O
possible	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

The	DET	O
peace	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
between	NOUN	O
Ethiopia	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
Eritrea	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
entering	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
crucial	NOUN	O
phase	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
urge	NOUN	O
both	NOUN	O
parties	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
stand	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
their	PRON	O
commitments	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
not	NOUN	O
hesitate	NOUN	O
now	ADV	O
that	NOUN	O
they	NOUN	O
stand	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
threshold	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
lasting	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Sudan	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
important	NOUN	O
progress	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
just	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
made	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
urge	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
parties	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
step	NOUN	O
up	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
efforts	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
reach	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
final	NOUN	O
settlement	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Over	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
last	NOUN	O
few	NOUN	O
years	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
has	NOUN	O
made	NOUN	O
considerable	NOUN	O
progress	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
peacekeeping	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
foundations	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
approach	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
laid	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Assistance	NOUN	I-MISC
Mission	NOUN	I-MISC
in	ADP	O
Afghanistan	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
facing	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
particularly	NOUN	O
challenging	NOUN	O
task	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Two	NOUN	O
years	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
,	.	O
much	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
achieved	NOUN	O
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
situation	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
still	ADV	O
volatile	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Many	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
suffering	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
food	NOUN	O
shortages	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
are	VERB	O
in	ADP	O
need	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
assistance	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Elections	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
due	NOUN	O
next	NOUN	O
year	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Women	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
yet	NOUN	O
properly	NOUN	O
empowered	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Unless	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
can	NOUN	O
assure	NOUN	O
nation-wide	NOUN	O
security	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
nation-building	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Afghanistan	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
risk	NOUN	O
.	.	O

A	DET	O
sustained	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
presence	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
necessary	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
foreseeable	NOUN	O
future	NOUN	O
.	.	O

With	ADP	O
NATO	NOUN	I-ORG
in	ADP	O
command	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
International	NOUN	I-ORG
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Assistance	NOUN	I-ORG
Force	NOUN	O
(	.	O
ISAF	NOUN	I-ORG
)	.	O
,	.	O
Norway	NOUN	I-LOC
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
NATO	NOUN	I-ORG
member	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
additional	NOUN	O
stake	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
building	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
peaceful	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
prosperous	NOUN	O
future	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
people	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Afghanistan	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
decided	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
Afghanistan	NOUN	I-LOC
one	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
partner	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
development	NOUN	O
cooperation	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
Sri	NOUN	I-LOC
Lanka	NOUN	I-LOC
the	DET	O
peace	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
reached	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
decisive	NOUN	O
juncture	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
hopeful	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
parties	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
soon	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
able	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
embark	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
negotiations	NOUN	O
towards	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
interim	NOUN	O
administration	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
North-East	NOUN	I-LOC
Province	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
vital	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
parties	NOUN	O
reach	NOUN	O
agreement	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
resume	NOUN	O
direct	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
negotiations	NOUN	O
within	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
timeframe	NOUN	O
envisaged	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Development	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
economic	NOUN	O
infrastructure	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
equally	NOUN	O
important	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Sri	NOUN	I-LOC
Lanka	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
parallel	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
dealing	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
political	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
parties	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
care	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
proceed	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
important	NOUN	O
task	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
reconstruction	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
development	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Norway	NOUN	I-LOC
remains	NOUN	O
firmly	NOUN	O
committed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
role	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
facilitator	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
peace	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
between	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Government	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Sri	NOUN	I-LOC
Lanka	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
LTTE	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
call	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
engage	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
efforts	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
reconstruction	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
rehabilitation	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Sri	NOUN	I-LOC
Lanka	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
Myanmar	NOUN	I-LOC
the	DET	O
Government	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
recently	NOUN	O
stated	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
intention	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
invite	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
democratic	NOUN	O
opposition	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
ethnic	NOUN	O
minorities	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
part	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
building	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
national	NOUN	O
consensus	NOUN	O
.	.	O

A	DET	O
good	NOUN	O
way	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
start	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
release	NOUN	O
Aung	NOUN	I-PER
San	NOUN	I-PER
Suu	NOUN	I-PER
Kyi	NOUN	I-PER
immediately	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
without	NOUN	O
conditions	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
thereby	NOUN	O
demonstrate	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Government	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
sincere	NOUN	O
intentions	NOUN	O
.	.	O

This	NOUN	O
might	NOUN	O
mean	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
beginning	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
political	NOUN	O
era	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Myanmar	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

Norway	NOUN	I-LOC
stands	NOUN	O
ready	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
democratization	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
irreversible	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
strongly	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
role	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
believe	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
active	NOUN	O
involvement	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
countries	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
region	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
vital	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
reaching	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
solution	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
year	NOUN	O
2003	NUM	O
has	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
tragic	NOUN	O
one	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
Israelis	NOUN	I-MISC
and	CONJ	O
Palestinians	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

Their	PRON	O
acceptance	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
road	NOUN	O
map	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
boded	NOUN	O
well	NOUN	O
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
again	NOUN	O
violence	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
not	NOUN	O
politics	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
determining	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
course	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
development	NOUN	O
.	.	O

A	DET	O
political	NOUN	O
solution	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
needed	NOUN	O
,	.	O
building	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
a	DET	O
parallel	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
where	NOUN	O
Israel	NOUN	I-LOC
takes	NOUN	O
significant	NOUN	O
steps	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
end	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
occupation	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
where	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Palestinian	NOUN	I-ORG
Authority	NOUN	I-ORG
takes	NOUN	O
determined	NOUN	O
steps	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
fight	NOUN	O
terror	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Norway	NOUN	I-LOC
urges	NOUN	O
Israel	NOUN	I-LOC
to	NOUN	O
do	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
utmost	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
ease	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
living	NOUN	O
conditions	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Palestinians	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
capacity	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
chairman	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Ad	NOUN	O
Hoc	NOUN	O
Liaison	NOUN	O
Committee	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
assistance	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Palestinian	NOUN	I-MISC
people	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Norway	NOUN	I-LOC
remains	NOUN	O
committed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
rebuilding	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Palestinian	NOUN	I-MISC
areas	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
past	NOUN	O
year	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
trying	NOUN	O
one	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

Multilateralism	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
come	NOUN	O
under	ADP	O
pressure	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
who	NOUN	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
question	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
primacy	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
therefore	NOUN	O
look	NOUN	O
elsewhere	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
solutions	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
answer	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
challenge	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
more	NOUN	O
effective	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
thus	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
relevant	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
dealing	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
issues	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
top	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
agenda	NOUN	O
.	.	O

By	ADP	O
increasing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
relevance	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
we	PRON	O
can	NOUN	O
increase	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
authority	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
legitimacy	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Norway	NOUN	I-LOC
shares	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-	NOUN	O
General	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
view	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
Member	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
need	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
hard	NOUN	O
look	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
today	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
institutions	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
ask	NOUN	O
whether	NOUN	O
they	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
adequate	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
tasks	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
before	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
time	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
come	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
advance	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
issue	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
reform	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

Norway	NOUN	I-LOC
puts	NOUN	O
emphasis	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
reforming	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
work	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
First	NOUN	O
Committee	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
therefore	NOUN	O
welcome	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
decision	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
appoint	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
high-	NOUN	O
level	NOUN	O
panel	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
recommend	NOUN	O
concrete	NOUN	O
ways	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
which	DET	O
to	NOUN	O
strengthen	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
functioning	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
major	NOUN	O
bodies	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
relationships	NOUN	O
between	NOUN	O
them	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Norway	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
together	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Nordic	NOUN	I-MISC
countries	NOUN	O
,	.	O
has	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
long-	NOUN	O
standing	NOUN	O
commitment	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
stand	NOUN	O
ready	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
assist	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
bringing	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
initiatives	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
fruition	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
aims	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
ideals	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
are	VERB	O
as	NOUN	O
relevant	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
ever	NOUN	O
—	.	O
to	NOUN	O
maintain	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
security	NOUN	O
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
reaffirm	NOUN	O
faith	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
fundamental	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
establish	NOUN	O
conditions	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
justice	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
rule	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
law	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
promote	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
social	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
changed	NOUN	O
since	NOUN	O
1945	NUM	O
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
has	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
changed	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
it	PRON	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
urge	NOUN	O
Member	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
come	NOUN	O
together	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
a	DET	O
renewed	NOUN	O
sense	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
unity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
purpose	NOUN	O
,	.	O
so	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
can	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
Organization	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
collective	NOUN	O
spirit	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
lies	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
core	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Charter	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O
