A	DET	O
few	NOUN	O
weeks	NOUN	O
ago	NOUN	O
,	.	O
200	NUM	O
innocent	NOUN	O
children	NOUN	O
were	NOUN	O
killed	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
terrorists	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Beslan	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

Today	NOUN	O
alone	NOUN	O
,	.	O
1,700	NOUN	O
children	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
born	NOUN	O
marked	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
death	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
HIV/AIDS	NOUN	I-MISC
from	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
first	NOUN	O
breath	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Also	ADV	O
today	NOUN	O
,	.	O
hundreds	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
children	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
die	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
starvation	NOUN	O
,	.	O
bullets	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
mines	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
numerous	NOUN	O
parts	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Has	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
become	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
better	NOUN	O
place	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
was	VERB	O
a	DET	O
generation	NOUN	O
ago	NOUN	O
?	.	O

Yes	NOUN	O
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
still	ADV	O
believe	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
has	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Democracy	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
more	NOUN	O
widespread	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
ever	NOUN	O
before	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
cold	NOUN	O
war	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
come	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
end	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Fewer	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
suffering	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
famine	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Better	NOUN	O
—	.	O
but	CONJ	O
still	ADV	O
,	.	O
this	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
good	NOUN	O
place	NOUN	O
.	.	O

As	NOUN	O
long	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
children	NOUN	O
die	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
famine	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
long	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
war	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
violence	NOUN	O
end	NOUN	O
lives	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
barely	NOUN	O
started	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
good	NOUN	O
.	.	O

As	NOUN	O
long	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
children	NOUN	O
die	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
curable	NOUN	O
diseases	NOUN	O
such	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
malaria	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
tuberculosis	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
—	.	O
the	DET	O
political	NOUN	O
leaders	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
—	.	O
have	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
done	NOUN	O
enough	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
need	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
stronger	NOUN	O
commitment	NOUN	O
,	.	O
a	DET	O
stronger	NOUN	O
link	NOUN	O
between	NOUN	O
words	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
deeds	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
pull	NOUN	O
together	NOUN	O
,	.	O
more	NOUN	O
determined	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
ever	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Each	NOUN	O
individual	NOUN	O
carries	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
responsibility	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
action	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
sake	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
collective	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
need	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
stronger	NOUN	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
want	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
see	NOUN	O
progress	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Sweden	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
staunch	NOUN	O
supporter	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
reform	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
.	.	O

While	CONJ	O
advocating	NOUN	O
reforms	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
believe	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
core	NOUN	O
principles	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Charter	NOUN	I-MISC
remain	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
valid	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
ever	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
use	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
force	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
permitted	NOUN	O
only	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
last	NOUN	O
resort	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
when	NOUN	O
authorized	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
unless	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
an	DET	O
act	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
self-defence	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
need	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
more	NOUN	O
relevant	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
need	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
that	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
act	NOUN	O
early	ADV	O
and	CONJ	O
quickly	NOUN	O
,	.	O
in	ADP	O
an	DET	O
integrated	NOUN	O
,	.	O
sustainable	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
legitimate	NOUN	O
manner	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Last	NOUN	O
year	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
called	NOUN	O
upon	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
all	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
take	NOUN	O
decisive	NOUN	O
action	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
order	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
safeguard	NOUN	O
multilateralism	NOUN	O
.	.	O

He	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
need	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
strong	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
follow	NOUN	O
up	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
report	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
High-Level	NOUN	I-MISC
Panel	NOUN	I-MISC
on	ADP	I-MISC
Threats	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	I-MISC
Challenges	NOUN	I-MISC
and	CONJ	I-MISC
Change	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

For	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
to	NOUN	O
remain	NOUN	O
legitimate	NOUN	O
,	.	O
representative	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
relevant	NOUN	O
,	.	O
its	NOUN	O
composition	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
better	NOUN	O
reflect	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
today	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Since	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
adoption	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Charter	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
a	DET	O
small	NOUN	O
number	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
countries	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
emerged	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
key	NOUN	O
political	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
economic	NOUN	O
Powers	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Those	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
given	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
role	NOUN	O
which	DET	O
is	VERB	O
commensurate	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
their	PRON	O
importance	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
also	ADV	O
need	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
that	NOUN	O
ensures	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
legitimate	NOUN	O
interests	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
small	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
medium-	NOUN	O
sized	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
.	.	O

An	DET	O
expansion	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
should	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
undermine	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
efficiency	NOUN	O
.	.	O

A	DET	O
way	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
safeguard	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
limit	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
use	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
veto	NOUN	O
power	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
hope	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
High-Level	NOUN	I-MISC
Panel	NOUN	I-MISC
will	VERB	O
present	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
bold	NOUN	O
proposal	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
end	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
present	NOUN	O
stalemate	NOUN	O
.	.	O

A	DET	O
joint	NOUN	O
seat	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
European	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
should	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
ruled	NOUN	O
out	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
option	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
future	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Managing	NOUN	O
transition	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
conflict	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
become	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
primary	NOUN	O
responsibility	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

A	DET	O
standing	NOUN	O
committee	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
to	NOUN	O
advise	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
on	ADP	O
post-conflict	NOUN	O
transition	NOUN	O
issues	NOUN	O
would	VERB	O
facilitate	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
task	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Economic	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	I-ORG
Social	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
effective	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
bridging	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
gap	NOUN	O
between	NOUN	O
peacekeeping	NOUN	O
,	.	O
peace-building	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
development	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
threat	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
connection	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
the	DET	O
proliferation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
such	NOUN	O
weapons	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
real	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
need	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
strong	NOUN	O
policies	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
disarmament	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
non-proliferation	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
acute	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
nuclear-weapon	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
show	NOUN	O
real	NOUN	O
progress	NOUN	O
towards	NOUN	O
disarmament	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Efforts	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
combat	NOUN	O
proliferation	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
strengthened	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Compliance	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
existing	NOUN	O
treaties	NOUN	O
leaves	NOUN	O
much	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
desired	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
must	NOUN	O
improve	NOUN	O
.	.	O

A	DET	O
wave	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
terrorist	NOUN	O
acts	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
shaken	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
past	NOUN	O
few	NOUN	O
years	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
months	NOUN	O
when	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
had	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
mourn	NOUN	O
victims	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
easily	NOUN	O
counted	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
are	VERB	O
all	NOUN	O
repelled	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
barbaric	NOUN	O
acts	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
around	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
,	.	O
from	NOUN	O
Beslan	NOUN	I-LOC
to	NOUN	O
Jakarta	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

Nothing	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
crueller	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
violent	NOUN	O
,	.	O
senseless	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
tragic	NOUN	O
loss	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
innocent	NOUN	O
lives	NOUN	O
.	.	O

All	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
work	NOUN	O
together	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
preserve	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
democratic	NOUN	O
,	.	O
secure	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
open	NOUN	O
society	NOUN	O
.	.	O

That	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
how	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
defeat	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
.	.	O

But	CONJ	O
we	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
admit	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
never	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
successful	NOUN	O
if	CONJ	O
we	PRON	O
fail	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
defeat	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
causes	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
.	.	O

For	NOUN	O
me	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
clear	NOUN	O
:	.	O
fanaticism	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
fundamentalism	NOUN	O
exploit	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
sense	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
injustice	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
lack	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
hope	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Poverty	NOUN	O
,	.	O
oppression	NOUN	O
,	.	O
insecurity	NOUN	O
,	.	O
intolerance	NOUN	O
,	.	O
absence	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
democratic	NOUN	O
structures	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
lack	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
political	NOUN	O
freedom	NOUN	O
—	.	O
they	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
all	NOUN	O
part	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
breeding	NOUN	O
ground	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
fight	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
carried	NOUN	O
out	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
determination	NOUN	O
.	.	O

There	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
no	DET	O
short	NOUN	O
cuts:	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
respected	NOUN	O
;	.	O
international	NOUN	O
law	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
followed	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Our	NOUN	O
global	ADJ	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
instruments	NOUN	O
aim	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
protecting	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
individual	NOUN	O
.	.	O

But	CONJ	O
just	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
beings	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
equal	NOUN	O
,	.	O
so	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
States	NOUN	O
,	.	O
big	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
small	NOUN	O
.	.	O

International	NOUN	O
law	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
ultimate	NOUN	O
guarantee	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
,	.	O
no	DET	O
matter	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
size	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
power	NOUN	O
,	.	O
are	VERB	O
treated	NOUN	O
equally	NOUN	O
.	.	O

For	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
sake	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
nations	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
need	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
strong	NOUN	O
multilateral	NOUN	O
system	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Commitment	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
parties	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
peaceful	NOUN	O
solution	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
an	DET	O
end	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
occupation	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
crucial	NOUN	O
.	.	O

On	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Israeli	NOUN	I-MISC
side	NOUN	O
,	.	O
excessive	NOUN	O
violence	NOUN	O
,	.	O
extrajudicial	NOUN	O
killings	NOUN	O
,	.	O
settlement	NOUN	O
activity	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
destruction	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
property	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
end	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Israel	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
right	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
obligation	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
protect	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
exercised	NOUN	O
within	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
context	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
international	NOUN	O
law	NOUN	O
.	.	O

On	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Palestinian	NOUN	O
side	NOUN	O
,	.	O
areas	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
particular	NOUN	O
concern	NOUN	O
remain	NOUN	O
corruption	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
security	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
political	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
indiscriminate	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
horrendous	NOUN	O
terrorist	NOUN	O
attacks	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
stop	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
Palestinian	NOUN	I-ORG
Authority	NOUN	I-ORG
must	NOUN	O
do	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
.	.	O

To	NOUN	O
realize	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
vision	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
two	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
—	.	O
a	DET	O
viable	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
democratic	NOUN	O
Palestine	NOUN	I-LOC
living	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
security	NOUN	O
side	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
side	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
an	DET	O
Israel	NOUN	I-LOC
within	NOUN	O
secure	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
recognized	NOUN	O
borders	NOUN	O
,	.	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
basis	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
resolutions	NOUN	O
242	NUM	O
(	.	O
1967	NUM	O
)	.	O
and	CONJ	O
338	NUM	O
(	.	O
1973	NUM	O
)	.	O
—	.	O
the	DET	O
parties	NOUN	O
need	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
meet	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
obligations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
road	NOUN	O
map	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Quartet	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
tool	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
both	NOUN	O
sides	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
demonstrate	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
will	VERB	O
to	NOUN	O
use	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
a	DET	O
united	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
give	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Iraqi	NOUN	I-MISC
people	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
necessary	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
building	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
an	DET	O
independent	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
democratic	NOUN	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

To	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
end	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
role	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
is	VERB	O
vital	NOUN	O
.	.	O

What	NOUN	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
whole	NOUN	O
region	NOUN	O
need	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
war	NOUN	O
,	.	O
but	CONJ	O
a	DET	O
new	ADJ	O
peace	NOUN	O
.	.	O

In	ADP	O
Afghanistan	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
the	DET	O
security	NOUN	O
situation	NOUN	O
remains	NOUN	O
worrying	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
attacks	NOUN	O
against	NOUN	O
national	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
international	NOUN	O
assistance	NOUN	O
workers	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
unacceptable	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
stand	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
Afghanistan	NOUN	I-LOC
in	ADP	O
building	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
stable	NOUN	O
,	.	O
secure	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
democratic	NOUN	O
society	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
size	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
scope	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
peacekeeping	NOUN	O
operations	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
expanded	NOUN	O
dramatically	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
welcome	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
trend	NOUN	O
towards	NOUN	O
peacekeeping	NOUN	O
operations	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
broad	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
comprehensive	NOUN	O
tasks	NOUN	O
,	.	O
including	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
protection	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
vulnerable	NOUN	O
civilian	NOUN	O
populations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Children	NOUN	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
victims	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
war	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
conflict	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Nothing	NOUN	O
can	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
important	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
life	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
health	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
children	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
late	NOUN	O
Swedish	NOUN	O
Prime	NOUN	O
Minister	NOUN	O
Olof	NOUN	I-PER
Palme	NOUN	I-PER
used	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
say	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
meaningful	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
talk	NOUN	O
about	NOUN	O
"	.	O
my	PRON	O
children	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
your	NOUN	O
children	NOUN	O
"	.	O
;	.	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
all	NOUN	O
about	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
children	NOUN	O
—	.	O
the	DET	O
only	NOUN	O
tangible	NOUN	O
connection	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
future	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Their	PRON	O
protection	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
paramount	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
us	PRON	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
was	VERB	O
a	DET	O
groundbreaking	NOUN	O
achievement	NOUN	O
.	.	O

But	CONJ	O
now	ADV	O
we	PRON	O
need	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
do	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
translate	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
common	NOUN	O
objectives	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
concrete	NOUN	O
improvements	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
women	NOUN	O
around	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
.	.	O

An	DET	O
increasing	NOUN	O
number	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
other	NOUN	O
peacekeeping	NOUN	O
missions	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
set	NOUN	O
up	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

While	CONJ	O
hardship	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
plight	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
countless	NOUN	O
men	NOUN	O
,	.	O
women	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
children	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
continent	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
today	NOUN	O
brings	NOUN	O
hope	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
more	NOUN	O
vigorous	NOUN	O
leadership	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
confront	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
challenges	NOUN	O
.	.	O

President	NOUN	O
Thabo	NOUN	I-PER
Mbeki	NOUN	I-PER
showed	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
way	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
his	PRON	O
bold	NOUN	O
New	ADJ	I-ORG
Partnership	NOUN	I-ORG
for	NOUN	I-ORG
Africa	NOUN	I-ORG
's	NOUN	I-ORG
Development	NOUN	I-ORG
(	.	O
NEPAD	NOUN	I-ORG
)	.	O
initiative	NOUN	O
.	.	O

From	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
followed	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
creation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
African	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
which	DET	O
is	VERB	O
now	ADV	O
establishing	NOUN	O
itself	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
decisive	NOUN	O
body	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
addressing	NOUN	O
violent	NOUN	O
conflicts	NOUN	O
.	.	O

International	NOUN	O
law	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
guide	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
in	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
collective	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
attain	NOUN	O
freedom	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
weapons	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
mass	NOUN	O
destruction	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
terrorism	NOUN	O
,	.	O
sustainable	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
respect	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
call	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
to	NOUN	O
consider	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
possibility	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
referring	NOUN	O
matters	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Court	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

Sovereignty	NOUN	O
entails	NOUN	O
responsibility	NOUN	O
.	.	O

At	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Stockholm	NOUN	I-ORG
International	NOUN	I-ORG
Forum	NOUN	I-ORG
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
prevention	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
genocide	NOUN	O
last	NOUN	O
January	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
pledged	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
shoulder	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
responsibility	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
protect	NOUN	O
potential	NOUN	O
victims	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
genocide	NOUN	O
,	.	O
mass	NOUN	O
murder	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
ethnic	NOUN	O
cleansing	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
pledged	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
ensure	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
perpetrators	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
genocidal	NOUN	O
acts	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
brought	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
justice	NOUN	O
.	.	O

And	CONJ	O
we	PRON	O
pledged	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
cooperate	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
on	ADP	O
these	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Discussions	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
definition	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
genocide	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
never	NOUN	O
stop	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
from	NOUN	O
taking	NOUN	O
action	NOUN	O
when	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
called	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
recent	NOUN	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
resolution	NOUN	O
,	.	O
resolution	NOUN	O
1564	NUM	O
(	.	O
2004	NUM	O
)	.	O
,	.	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
terrible	NOUN	O
tragedy	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Darfur	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
necessary	NOUN	O
step	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
direction	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
particularly	NOUN	O
welcome	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
request	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
establish	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
commission	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
inquiry	NOUN	O
.	.	O

My	PRON	O
Government	NOUN	O
stands	NOUN	O
ready	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
give	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
full	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
that	NOUN	O
task	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
welcome	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
appointment	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Professor	NOUN	O
Juan	NOUN	I-PER
Méndez	NOUN	I-PER
as	NOUN	O
his	PRON	O
Special	ADJ	O
Adviser	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Prevention	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Genocide	NOUN	O
.	.	O

That	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
serve	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
clear	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
link	NOUN	O
between	NOUN	O
massive	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
systematic	NOUN	O
violations	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
threats	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
security	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Another	NOUN	O
issue	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
serious	NOUN	O
concern	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
use	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
death	NOUN	O
penalty	NOUN	O
.	.	O

For	NOUN	O
me	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
democrat	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
humanist	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
can	NOUN	O
never	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
accepted	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
want	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
every	DET	O
effort	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
seek	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
abolishment	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
death	NOUN	O
penalty	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Millennium	NOUN	O
Declaration	NOUN	I-MISC
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
Millennium	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
Goals	NOUN	I-MISC
are	VERB	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
core	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
's	NOUN	O
efforts	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
put	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
end	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
hunger	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
poverty	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
collective	NOUN	O
political	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
to	NOUN	O
give	NOUN	O
priority	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
sustainable	NOUN	O
global	ADJ	O
development	NOUN	O
,	.	O
over	NOUN	O
short-term	NOUN	O
national	NOUN	O
interests	NOUN	O
,	.	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
decisive	NOUN	O
factor	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
turning	NOUN	O
promise	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
reality	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Rich	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
fulfil	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
commitments	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
am	VERB	O
proud	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
tell	NOUN	O
you	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
Sweden	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
reach	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
national	NOUN	O
goal	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
1	NUM	O
per	NOUN	O
cent	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
gross	NOUN	O
national	NOUN	O
income	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
official	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
assistance	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
2006	NUM	O
.	.	O

But	CONJ	O
development	NOUN	O
assistance	NOUN	O
alone	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
yield	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
needed	NOUN	O
results	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Both	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
developed	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
developing	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
move	NOUN	O
forward	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
a	DET	O
number	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
other	NOUN	O
issues	NOUN	O
.	.	O

And	CONJ	O
Sweden	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
do	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
part	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
translated	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
agenda	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
national	NOUN	O
policy	NOUN	O
,	.	O
giving	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
entire	NOUN	O
range	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
government	NOUN	O
activities	NOUN	O
one	NOUN	O
single	NOUN	O
objective:	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
contribute	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
equitable	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
sustainable	NOUN	O
global	ADJ	O
development	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
act	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
coherent	NOUN	O
way	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
that	NOUN	O
single	NOUN	O
objective	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
every	DET	O
field	NOUN	O
,	.	O
whether	NOUN	O
trade	NOUN	O
,	.	O
environment	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
agricultural	NOUN	O
policy	NOUN	O
.	.	O

But	CONJ	O
this	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
not	NOUN	O
enough	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Other	NOUN	O
decisive	NOUN	O
areas	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
good	NOUN	O
governance	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
transparency	NOUN	O
,	.	O
democracy	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
,	.	O
women	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
workers'	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Let	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
end	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
blame	NOUN	O
game	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Let	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
focus	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
getting	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
job	NOUN	O
done	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Next	NOUN	O
year	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
gather	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
Hall	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
summit	NOUN	O
meeting	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
review	NOUN	O
progress	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
implementation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Millennium	NOUN	I-MISC
Declaration	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

By	ADP	O
then	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
also	ADV	O
have	NOUN	O
reflected	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
findings	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
High-Level	NOUN	O
Panel	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
recommendations	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
decisive	NOUN	O
moment	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
chance	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
Members	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
show	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
believe	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
collective	NOUN	O
action	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
will	VERB	O
shoulder	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
responsibility	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
making	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
institutions	NOUN	O
stronger	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
more	NOUN	O
effective	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Let	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
not	NOUN	O
fail	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
at	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
most	DET	O
critical	NOUN	O
juncture	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Let	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
not	NOUN	O
shirk	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
responsibilities	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
face	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
complex	NOUN	O
new	ADJ	O
realities	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Let	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
choose	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
secure	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
prosperous	NOUN	O
future	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
.	.	O
