My	PRON	O
delegation	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
confident	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
under	ADP	O
his	PRON	O
able	NOUN	O
leadership	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
General	NOUN	I-ORG
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
will	VERB	O
successfully	NOUN	O
address	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
pressing	NOUN	O
issues	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
agenda	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
current	NOUN	O
session	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
also	ADV	O
wish	VERB	O
to	NOUN	O
pay	NOUN	O
tribute	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
his	PRON	O
predecessor	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Mr.	NOUN	O
Joseph	NOUN	I-PER
Deiss	NOUN	I-PER
,	.	O
for	NOUN	O
having	NOUN	O
successfully	NOUN	O
steered	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
proceedings	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
House	NOUN	O
during	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
sixty-fifth	NOUN	O
session	NOUN	O
.	.	O

I	NOUN	O
wish	VERB	O
also	ADV	O
to	NOUN	O
congratulate	VERB	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Mr.	NOUN	O
Ban	NOUN	I-PER
Ki-moon	NOUN	I-PER
,	.	O
on	ADP	O
his	PRON	O
reappointment	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
second	NOUN	O
term	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
remain	NOUN	O
hopeful	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Secretary-General	NOUN	O
will	VERB	O
strive	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
shepherd	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
with	ADP	O
an	DET	O
open	NOUN	O
,	.	O
transparent	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
inclusive	NOUN	O
multilateral	NOUN	O
approach	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Such	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
approach	NOUN	O
,	.	O
I	NOUN	O
believe	NOUN	O
,	.	O
would	VERB	O
renew	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
revive	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
hopes	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
expectations	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
developing	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
efficacy	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
body	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Zimbabwe	NOUN	I-LOC
places	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
hopes	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
a	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
that	NOUN	O
recognizes	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
equality	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
sovereign	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
enshrined	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
founding	NOUN	O
Charter	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

As	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
all	NOUN	O
congratulate	VERB	O
this	NOUN	O
new	ADJ	O
nation	NOUN	O
,	.	O
Zimbabwe	NOUN	I-LOC
calls	NOUN	O
upon	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
international	NOUN	O
community	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
render	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
necessary	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
Government	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
its	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
tackling	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
numerous	NOUN	O
development	NOUN	O
challenges	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
lie	NOUN	O
ahead	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
them	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Zimbabwe	NOUN	I-LOC
stands	NOUN	O
ready	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
modest	NOUN	O
contribution	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
end	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
theme	NOUN	O
"	.	O
The	DET	O
role	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
mediation	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
settlement	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
disputes	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
peaceful	NOUN	O
means	NOUN	O
"	.	O
is	VERB	O
most	DET	O
apt	NOUN	O
.	.	O

But	CONJ	O
how	NOUN	O
do	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Members	NOUN	O
,	.	O
measure	NOUN	O
up	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
relation	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
in	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
activities	NOUN	O
here	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
out	NOUN	O
there	NOUN	O
,	.	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
real	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
?	.	O

It	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
my	PRON	O
principled	NOUN	O
view	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
duty-and	NOUN	O
honour-bound	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
operationalize	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
principles	NOUN	O
upon	NOUN	O
which	DET	O
the	DET	O
Charter	NOUN	I-MISC
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
is	VERB	O
based	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
guilty	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
manipulating	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Charter	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
serve	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
particular	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
sectional	NOUN	O
designs	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
ambitions	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Charter	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
our	NOUN	O
set	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
commandments	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
strictly	NOUN	O
obeyed	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
each	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
every	DET	O
Member	NOUN	O
if	CONJ	O
international	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
regional	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
maintained	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
cannot	NOUN	O
honestly	NOUN	O
say	NOUN	O
today	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
position	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
regard	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
NATO	NOUN	I-ORG
States	NOUN	O
versus	NOUN	O
Libya	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

Whatever	NOUN	O
political	NOUN	O
disturbances	NOUN	O
might	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
first	NOUN	O
occurred	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Benghazi	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
the	DET	O
process	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
mediation	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
peaceful	NOUN	O
negotiations	NOUN	O
was	VERB	O
never	NOUN	O
given	NOUN	O
full	NOUN	O
play	NOUN	O
.	.	O

It	PRON	O
was	VERB	O
deliberately	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
blatantly	NOUN	O
excluded	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
positively	NOUN	O
influencing	NOUN	O
developments	NOUN	O
.	.	O

There	NOUN	O
was	VERB	O
quick	NOUN	O
resort	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
invoking	NOUN	O
Chapter	NOUN	O
VII	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Charter	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
with	ADP	O
a	DET	O
gross	NOUN	O
,	.	O
deliberate	NOUN	O
misinterpretation	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
scope	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
mandate	NOUN	O
originally	NOUN	O
given	NOUN	O
NATO	NOUN	I-ORG
to	NOUN	O
oversee	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
protect	NOUN	O
civilians	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Bilateral	NOUN	O
hatreds	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
quarrels	NOUN	O
or	CONJ	O
ulterior	NOUN	O
motives	NOUN	O
must	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
allowed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
creep	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
the	DET	O
consideration	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
matters	NOUN	O
pertaining	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
threats	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
security	NOUN	O
,	.	O
or	CONJ	O
even	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
principle	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
responsibility	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
protect	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
have	NOUN	O
yet	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
convinced	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
involvement	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
mighty	NOUN	O
Powers	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Libya	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
affairs	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
hindered	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
advent	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
process	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
peace	NOUN	O
,	.	O
democracy	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
prosperity	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
that	NOUN	O
sister	NOUN	O
African	NOUN	I-MISC
country	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Our	NOUN	O
African	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
would	VERB	O
never	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
presumed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
impose	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
leadership	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
fraternal	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Libya	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
NATO	NOUN	I-ORG
countries	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
illegally	NOUN	O
sought	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
do	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
,	.	O
in	ADP	O
fact	NOUN	O
,	.	O
have	NOUN	O
done	NOUN	O
.	.	O

At	ADP	O
the	DET	O
very	ADV	O
least	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
African	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
would	VERB	O
have	NOUN	O
wished	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
join	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
principled	NOUN	O
members	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
body	NOUN	O
who	NOUN	O
preferred	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
immediate	NOUN	O
ceasefire	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
peaceful	NOUN	O
dialogue	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Libya	NOUN	I-LOC
.	.	O

The	DET	O
African	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
was	VERB	O
and	CONJ	O
remains	NOUN	O
fully	NOUN	O
seized	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
crisis	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
will	VERB	O
spare	NOUN	O
no	DET	O
effort	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
working	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
fully	NOUN	O
complement	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
so	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
may	NOUN	O
return	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
Libya	NOUN	I-LOC
and	CONJ	O
its	NOUN	O
tormented	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
wish	VERB	O
that	NOUN	O
process	NOUN	O
Godspeed	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
newly	NOUN	O
minted	NOUN	O
principle	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
responsibility	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
protect	NOUN	O
should	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
twisted	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
provide	NOUN	O
cover	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
premeditated	NOUN	O
abuse	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
violating	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
sacred	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
principle	NOUN	O
enshrined	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Charter	NOUN	I-MISC
of	ADP	O
non-interference	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
domestic	NOUN	O
affairs	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
States	NOUN	O
,	.	O
because	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
do	NOUN	O
so	NOUN	O
amounts	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
an	DET	O
act	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
aggression	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
causes	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
destabilization	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
sovereign	NOUN	O
State	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Moreover	NOUN	O
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
selectively	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
arbitrarily	NOUN	O
apply	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
principle	NOUN	O
serves	NOUN	O
merely	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
undermine	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
general	NOUN	O
acceptability	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Indeed	NOUN	O
,	.	O
more	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
other	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
,	.	O
all	NOUN	O
five	NOUN	O
permanent	NOUN	O
members	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
bear	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
huge	NOUN	O
responsibility	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
regard	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
ensuring	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
historical	NOUN	O
privilege	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
used	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
protect	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Charter	NOUN	I-MISC
than	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
breach	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
happening	NOUN	O
currently	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
Libya	NOUN	I-LOC
through	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
blatantly	NOUN	O
illegal	NOUN	O
,	.	O
brutal	NOUN	O
,	.	O
callous	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
murderous	NOUN	O
NATO	NOUN	I-ORG
bombings	NOUN	O
.	.	O

There	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
see	NOUN	O
NATO	NOUN	I-ORG
bombing	NOUN	O
places	NOUN	O
,	.	O
seeking	NOUN	O
out	NOUN	O
,	.	O
hunting	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
hounding	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
children	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Al-Qadhafi	NOUN	I-PER
.	.	O

Have	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
alleged	NOUN	O
sins	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
father	NOUN	O
now	ADV	O
been	NOUN	O
visited	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
sons	NOUN	O
?	.	O

Have	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
children	NOUN	O
lost	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
right	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
life	NOUN	O
?	.	O

They	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
no	DET	O
longer	NOUN	O
human	NOUN	O
beings	NOUN	O
;	.	O
they	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
being	NOUN	O
hunted	NOUN	O
every	DET	O
day	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Or	CONJ	O
is	VERB	O
it	PRON	O
because	CONJ	O
each	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
them	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
no	DET	O
longer	NOUN	O
worth	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
price	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
barrel	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
oil	NOUN	O
?	.	O

What	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
shame	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Yesterday	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
was	VERB	O
Iraq	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
Bush	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
Blair	NOUN	O
were	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
liars	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
aggressors	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
they	NOUN	O
made	NOUN	O
unfounded	NOUN	O
allegations	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
possession	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
weapons	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
mass	NOUN	O
destruction	NOUN	O
.	.	O

This	NOUN	O
time	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
is	VERB	O
the	DET	O
NATO	NOUN	I-ORG
countries	NOUN	O
that	NOUN	O
are	VERB	O
the	DET	O
liars	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
aggressors	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
they	NOUN	O
make	NOUN	O
similarly	NOUN	O
unfounded	NOUN	O
allegations	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
destruction	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
civilian	NOUN	O
lives	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
Al-Qadhafi	NOUN	I-PER
.	.	O

When	NOUN	O
we	PRON	O
in	ADP	O
Zimbabwe	NOUN	I-LOC
sought	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
redress	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
ills	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
colonialism	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
racism	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
fully	NOUN	O
acquiring	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
natural	NOUN	O
resources	NOUN	O
,	.	O
mainly	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
land	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
minerals	NOUN	O
,	.	O
we	PRON	O
were	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
still	ADV	O
are	VERB	O
subjected	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
unparalleled	NOUN	O
vilification	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
pernicious	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
sanctions	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
reasons	NOUN	O
—	.	O
lies	NOUN	O
again	NOUN	O
—	.	O
alleged	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
violations	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
rule	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
law	NOUN	O
,	.	O
human	NOUN	O
rights	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
democracy	NOUN	O
,	.	O
which	DET	O
never	NOUN	O
,	.	O
never	NOUN	O
occurred	NOUN	O
.	.	O

My	PRON	O
people	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
condemned	NOUN	O
these	NOUN	O
illegal	NOUN	O
sanctions	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
recently	NOUN	O
more	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
two	NOUN	O
million	NOUN	O
protesters'	NOUN	O
signatures	NOUN	O
have	NOUN	O
demonstrated	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
antipathy	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
them	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
thank	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Southern	NOUN	I-ORG
Africa	NOUN	I-ORG
Development	NOUN	I-ORG
Community	NOUN	I-ORG
(	.	O
SADC	NOUN	I-ORG
)	.	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
African	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
for	NOUN	O
supporting	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
and	CONJ	O
demanding	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
immediate	NOUN	O
removal	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
illegal	NOUN	O
sanctions	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
in	ADP	O
Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
are	VERB	O
also	ADV	O
duly	NOUN	O
concerned	NOUN	O
about	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
activities	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
International	NOUN	I-ORG
Criminal	NOUN	I-ORG
Court	NOUN	I-ORG
(	.	O
ICC	NOUN	I-ORG
)	.	O
,	.	O
which	DET	O
seems	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
exist	NOUN	O
only	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
alleged	NOUN	O
offenders	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
developing	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
majority	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
them	NOUN	O
Africans	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

A	DET	O
blind	NOUN	O
eye	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
routinely	NOUN	O
turned	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
leaders	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
powerful	NOUN	O
Western	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
guilty	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
international	NOUN	O
crimes	NOUN	O
,	.	O
such	NOUN	O
as	NOUN	O
Bush	NOUN	I-PER
and	CONJ	O
Blair	NOUN	I-PER
.	.	O

Such	NOUN	O
selective	NOUN	O
justice	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
eroded	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
credibility	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
ICC	NOUN	I-ORG
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
African	NOUN	I-MISC
continent	NOUN	O
.	.	O

My	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
continues	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
work	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
others	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
revitalized	NOUN	O
General	NOUN	I-ORG
Assembly	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

However	NOUN	O
,	.	O
our	NOUN	O
ambitions	NOUN	O
extend	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
need	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
reform	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
as	NOUN	O
well	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
's	NOUN	O
call	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
at	ADP	O
least	NOUN	O
two	NOUN	O
permanent	NOUN	O
seats	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
for	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
members	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
been	NOUN	O
constant	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
decades	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
cannot	NOUN	O
remain	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
only	NOUN	O
region	NOUN	O
without	NOUN	O
permanent	NOUN	O
membership	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Security	NOUN	I-ORG
Council	NOUN	I-ORG
.	.	O

The	DET	O
current	NOUN	O
global	ADJ	O
economic	NOUN	O
crisis	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
the	DET	O
attendant	NOUN	O
financial	NOUN	O
crisis	NOUN	O
compounds	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
plight	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
most	DET	O
vulnerable	NOUN	O
,	.	O
that	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
developing	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
present	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
financial	NOUN	O
architecture	NOUN	O
has	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
reformed	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
made	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
respond	NOUN	O
timeously	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
real	NOUN	O
needs	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
peoples	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
situation	NOUN	O
challenges	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
ability	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
developing	NOUN	O
world	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
achieve	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
Millennium	NOUN	I-MISC
Development	NOUN	I-MISC
Goals	NOUN	I-MISC
.	.	O

My	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
fully	NOUN	O
supports	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
right	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
gallant	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Palestine	NOUN	I-LOC
to	NOUN	O
statehood	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
membership	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Organization	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
must	NOUN	O
become	NOUN	O
credible	NOUN	O
by	ADP	O
welcoming	NOUN	O
into	ADP	O
its	NOUN	O
bosom	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
those	NOUN	O
whose	NOUN	O
right	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
attain	NOUN	O
sovereign	NOUN	O
independence	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
freedom	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
occupation	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
colonialism	NOUN	O
is	VERB	O
legitimate	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Let	NOUN	O
us	PRON	O
all	NOUN	O
accept	NOUN	O
Palestine	NOUN	I-LOC
as	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
legitimate	NOUN	O
State	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
a	DET	O
Member	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
this	NOUN	O
body	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Similarly	NOUN	O
,	.	O
the	DET	O
tormented	NOUN	O
people	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Sahrawi	NOUN	I-LOC
Arab	NOUN	I-LOC
Democratic	NOUN	I-LOC
Republic	NOUN	I-LOC
must	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
forgotten	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
call	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
immediate	NOUN	O
progress	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
engagements	NOUN	O
for	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
solution	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
their	PRON	O
long-running	NOUN	O
saga	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
Conference	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
Parties	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
Framework	NOUN	I-MISC
Convention	NOUN	I-MISC
on	ADP	I-MISC
Climate	NOUN	I-MISC
Change	NOUN	I-MISC
,	.	O
to	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
held	NOUN	O
later	NOUN	O
this	NOUN	O
year	NOUN	O
,	.	O
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
pivotal	NOUN	O
occasion	NOUN	O
from	NOUN	O
which	DET	O
we	PRON	O
should	NOUN	O
emerge	NOUN	O
with	ADP	O
agreed	NOUN	O
measures	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
address	NOUN	O
matters	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
climate	NOUN	O
change	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
how	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
mitigate	NOUN	O
threats	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
very	ADV	O
existence	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
small	NOUN	O
island	NOUN	O
States	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
particular	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
to	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
coastal	NOUN	O
regions	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
many	NOUN	O
heavily	NOUN	O
populated	NOUN	O
nations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Zimbabwe	NOUN	I-LOC
will	VERB	O
be	NOUN	O
fully	NOUN	O
engaged	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
those	NOUN	O
negotiations	NOUN	O
.	.	O

We	PRON	O
must	NOUN	O
all	NOUN	O
resist	NOUN	O
any	NOUN	O
abuse	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
which	DET	O
it	PRON	O
may	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
exposed	NOUN	O
through	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
unwelcome	NOUN	O
behaviour	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
a	DET	O
few	NOUN	O
.	.	O

My	PRON	O
country	NOUN	O
celebrates	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
UN-Women	NOUN	I-MISC
entity	NOUN	O
,	.	O
as	NOUN	O
it	PRON	O
addresses	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
position	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
more	NOUN	O
than	NOUN	O
half	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
humankind	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
all	NOUN	O
our	NOUN	O
countries	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
African	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
must	NOUN	O
not	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
undermined	NOUN	O
;	.	O
rather	NOUN	O
,	.	O
it	PRON	O
should	NOUN	O
be	NOUN	O
allowed	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
complement	NOUN	O
the	DET	O
efforts	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
for	NOUN	O
peace	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
security	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
continent	NOUN	O
.	.	O

Zimbabwe	NOUN	I-LOC
is	VERB	O
a	DET	O
peaceful	NOUN	O
member	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
the	DET	O
African	NOUN	I-ORG
Union	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
SADC	NOUN	I-ORG
,	.	O
the	DET	O
Common	NOUN	I-ORG
Market	NOUN	I-ORG
for	NOUN	O
Eastern	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
Southern	NOUN	O
Africa	NOUN	I-LOC
,	.	O
the	DET	O
Non-Aligned	NOUN	I-ORG
Movement	NOUN	I-ORG
and	CONJ	O
many	NOUN	O
other	NOUN	O
international	NOUN	O
economic	NOUN	O
and	CONJ	O
trade	NOUN	O
organizations	NOUN	O
,	.	O
and	CONJ	O
thus	NOUN	O
desires	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
continue	NOUN	O
to	NOUN	O
play	NOUN	O
its	NOUN	O
part	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
creating	NOUN	O
a	DET	O
peaceful	NOUN	O
environment	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
the	DET	O
world	NOUN	O
.	.	O

The	DET	O
United	NOUN	I-ORG
Nations	NOUN	I-ORG
can	NOUN	O
count	NOUN	O
on	ADP	O
the	DET	O
unqualified	NOUN	O
support	NOUN	O
of	ADP	O
Zimbabwe	NOUN	I-LOC
as	NOUN	O
required	NOUN	O
,	.	O
even	NOUN	O
if	CONJ	O
only	NOUN	O
in	ADP	O
our	NOUN	O
modest	NOUN	O
way	NOUN	O
.	.	O

